<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: work - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/work/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Burning out in a business (mech) suit</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brilliantcrank (Greg Storey), &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brilliantcrank.com/the-coyote-trap/?ref=brilliantcrank-newsletter&quot;&gt;The coyote trap.&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if survival looked like ownership instead? What if the best response to getting laid off isn’t to get in the line to nowhere for the next thing, but to build your own thing? Do your own thing? The tools are there. The access is there. The demand is there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve got too many smart, experienced people standing at the edge of the workforce, assuming their only move is down or to keep trying what worked yesterday. From what I read many folks fear an AI fuled collapse, but I fear another powered by denial, retreat, and stubborn nostalgia. If enough of us take this route, we’re going to see a quiet, steady slide of educated, capable folks into poverty—and that’s not just a personal tragedy, it’s a societal one. And no amount of boycotting or avoiding AI is going to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking a lot about this, lately. And I keep thinking about &quot;my own thing&quot; that I could build. I&#39;ve had some ideas, but I&#39;m not sure any of them are big enough to convince people to shovel enough money at me to pay my mortgage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, I&#39;ve never felt a particular urge to be an entrepreneur. That doesn&#39;t sound like my kind of fun, at all. Ownership, being my own boss, making all the decisions, taking all the risk. Not enticing to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, not that I think this would be a great business, but: Since I got my 3D printer, I&#39;ve seen lots of folks running little garage print farms. Looks like fun! I&#39;d love to have a dozen or two machines whirring away. But then I realize, practically speaking, a print farm isn&#39;t about printing. It&#39;s about bookkeeping, inventory, visits to the UPS store, and self-marketing—and I don&#39;t like any of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like every idea I&#39;ve come up with boils down to that. Even if I&#39;m just thinking about being a freelancer doing what I already do for work. The thing is not the thing. You have to build &amp;amp; maintain a business mech suit around the thing to make the money happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think I would like it. I think it would burn me out after not very long. That&#39;s not denial or retreat or nostalgia—I think that&#39;s just self-honesty. I mean, if it&#39;s that or starving, I&#39;ll do the needful somehow. But, for as much as I&#39;m a socially-anxious hermit, I like being on a team or in a crew. I want to do my part, play my role. I don&#39;t want to try to pull off the whole heist by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;m definitely not avoiding AI, and I&#39;m working to stay current. But I&#39;m not sure I&#39;m hanging out my own shingle any time soon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:15:48 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/solo-burnout/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/solo-burnout/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Hey Ron, who&#39;s driving?</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chris Stokel-Walker, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leaddev.com/software-quality/why-untested-ai-generated-code-is-a-crisis-waiting-to-happen&quot;&gt;Why untested AI-generated code is a crisis waiting to happen&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fear is of a slow-burn crisis where generative AI engines spew reams of code, stitched from web-scraped snippets with dubious provenance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When that code leaps from prompt to production without being vetted, the potential attack surface balloons in size. The bill for defective code is already sizable: 40% of firms say malfunctioning or miscoded software costs them at least $1 million a year, through staff churn, increased technical debt, and escalating maintenance costs, with losses above $5 million in almost half of large US firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, don&#39;t let &quot;code leap from prompt to production without being vetted&quot; - it&#39;s not like it happens on its own. Steady hand on the tiller. Vibe coding is fine for screwing around and exploration, but assume you&#39;re going to be on pager duty for whatever hits production. And if someday you stick an LLM on pager duty, may Eris have mercy on your soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IfY49zx7RU0?si=Gx2gyj-rqsBSHoL-&amp;amp;start=46&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:28 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/review-ai-code/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/review-ai-code/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Quoting Will Larson on career advice in 2025</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt; Will Larson, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://lethain.com/career-advice-2025/&quot;&gt;Career advice in 2025&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t give advice on what you should do, but if you’re finding this job market difficult, it’s certainly not personal. My sense is that’s basically the experience that everyone is having when searching for new roles right now. If you are in a role today that’s frustrating you, my advice is to try harder than usual to find a way to make it a rewarding experience, even if it’s not perfect. I also wouldn’t personally try to sit this cycle out unless you’re comfortable with a small risk that reentry is quite difficult: I think it’s more likely that the ecosystem is meaningfully different in five years than that it’s largely unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Altogether, this hasn’t really been the advice that anyone wanted when they chatted with me, but it seems to generally have resonated with them as a realistic appraisal of the current markets. Hopefully there’s something useful for you in here as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It sure does feel personal if the paycheck stops, but I know what he means. It&#39;s not &quot;not personal&quot; so much as &lt;em&gt;impersonal&lt;/em&gt; like a funnel cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although, it does feel a bit &lt;em&gt;pointed&lt;/em&gt; insofar as some of the industry moves seem to be toward pulling back some of the privilege &amp;amp; perks folks like me have enjoyed for decades. Still, indignation doesn&#39;t pay my mortgage or feed the cats, so one must roll with the punches to stay intact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 19:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/15/quoting-will-larson-on-career-advice-in/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/15/quoting-will-larson-on-career-advice-in/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>On the other end of a self-imposed death march project</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;So, I’m a couple of weeks back from a well-deserved vacation taken after the launch of a project well over 18 months in the making. I kind of overworked myself, voluntarily, and that needs to change.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2012/09/17/on-the-other-end-of-a-self-imposed-death-march-project/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2012/09/17/on-the-other-end-of-a-self-imposed-death-march-project/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Please Do Learn To Code</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2012/05/16/please-learn-to-code/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2012/05/16/please-learn-to-code/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>