<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-20</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/commit/954919050fca61d04d6e89beec96b0ea374ba74d&quot;&gt;Added support for a &lt;code&gt;draft: true&lt;/code&gt; flag on entries here&lt;/a&gt;, which should at least help me keep half-broken things from deploying mid-rant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now I just have to make sure to use that flag right so I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; don&#39;t include half-broken things here 😅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should figure out a decent way for showing really long strings here, like the path names in that cloud saves post today 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the hell do I remember things like &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://monkeybagel.com/pumas.html&quot;&gt;Pumas on Hoverbikes&lt;/a&gt; is at monkeybagel.com&quot; but I have to remind myself to eat lunch as a separate step from making lunch?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Quoting Greg Storey on Minimum Viable Humans</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greg Storey, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brilliantcrank.com/minimum-viable-humans/&quot;&gt;Minimum Viable Humans.&lt;/a&gt;&quot; hits like &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/15/quoting-will-larson-on-career-advice-in/index.html&quot;&gt;a funnel cloud&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies aren&#39;t just cutting costs—they&#39;re conducting a fundamental reset to find their Minimum Viable Humans model. They&#39;re stripping organizations down to the ground—the irreducible human functions that (currently) can&#39;t be replaced or augmented by AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rings true to what I&#39;ve been seeing. The cruelty feels incidental to the process—not to me and everyone I know, mind you—but indignation won&#39;t pay my mortgage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to get your old job back is futile—that role, as you remember it, isn’t coming back. The opportunity now lies in positioning yourself for the roles and capabilities that will emerge as organizations rebuild from the bottom up—core human strengths like creativity and ethical judgment, the ability to collaborate with AI, your unique experience and expertise, and the kind of discernment that values judgment over process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brutal, yet maybe positive? If drudgery gets distilled out, what&#39;s left are human creativity, judgment, and experience. That sounds nice, like what classic sci-fi promised us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you can&#39;t mechanize that with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time_and_motion_study&quot;&gt;a Taylorist time-and-motion study&lt;/a&gt;. Some jobs are just paychecks, some spark enthusiasm, and some flip between both unpredictably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will companies make allowances for that, while rewarding what they&#39;re asking for? I know we&#39;re seeing a reckoning right now, a firm snatching back from privileged labor. Fine, I don&#39;t need a free lunch or a foosball table, but I do need a health plan and a few days off. What&#39;s the churn for all of us while they figure that out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manager&#39;s role isn&#39;t just being eliminated—it&#39;s being fundamentally redefined from day-to-day oversight to exception handling, strategic communication, and resource allocation across much larger teams. It will keep going into augmenting the decision-making process for leaders and individual contributors alike. The boundaries of acceptable risk at all levels are now in a constant prototype state as AI becomes more powerful and faster, giving mere mortals more access to information and insight than ever before. The trick will be what training we need in order to make the pairing work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This might suit an ADHD-head like me. I could see myself as a human relay, occasionally reallocating &lt;a href=&quot;https://starcraft.fandom.com/wiki/Pylon&quot;&gt;pylons&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://starcraft.fandom.com/wiki/Vespene_gas&quot;&gt;vespene gas&lt;/a&gt; amongst largely autonomous &lt;a href=&quot;https://starcraft.fandom.com/wiki/Protoss&quot;&gt;protoss&lt;/a&gt; units. I&#39;m already having better luck than some with AI-assisted coding. Maybe I&#39;m learning the magic invocations? Maybe I&#39;m a special kind of moron? Either way, I&#39;m ending up with working code and nodding heads. This gives me some hope that I can &quot;stay current&quot; - whatever that means in the current era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admittedly, I&#39;m more comfortable directing Starcraft units and AI agents like this. That feels like a kind of management to me. I&#39;m not so comfortable directing human co-workers with the same interface, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&#39;t just another tech cycle. It&#39;s a fundamental recalibration of the human role in organizational life. And while there&#39;s no easy path through this transition, understanding what&#39;s actually happening might help you find your footing on shifting ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I keep slipping into snark because part of me finds this exciting while another part is cynical and burnt out. I&#39;m hoping optimism holds out longer than cynicism. Maybe &lt;a href=&quot;https://monkeybagel.com/pumas.html&quot;&gt;the thumbless neurotic puma driving a maroon AMC Gremlin&lt;/a&gt; have the last laugh after all? (Anybody get that reference anymore?) I dunno, I&#39;m just trying to figure how much of this is like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livescience.com/planet-earth/earthquakes/first-of-its-kind-video-captures-the-terrifying-moment-the-ground-tore-apart-during-major-myanmar-earthquake&quot;&gt;that surface rupture in Myanmar last week&lt;/a&gt;  and whether my Crocs can carry me to the right side of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:30:07 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/minimum-viable-human-career/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/minimum-viable-human-career/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Liberating save games from Xbox Cloud Gaming</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ah, the problems of a masochistic nerd trying to game. For about a year now, my gaming PC has run &lt;a href=&quot;https://bazzite.gg/&quot;&gt;Bazzite Linux&lt;/a&gt; because I got tired of Windows. I&#39;ve also got a Game Pass subscription, prepaid for a long while from before I switched to Linux. This was not a well thought out plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While other game stores work pretty great, the only way to use my Game Pass subscription on Linux is via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-us/play&quot;&gt;Xbox Cloud Gaming&lt;/a&gt;. The Xbox app doesn&#39;t on Linux and won&#39;t install Game Pass stuff locally on Linux. Still, streaming works pretty well for games I want to try and ditch when I get bored. But, it&#39;s so ephemeral that I wouldn&#39;t really want to commit to buying a game through that outright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I started playing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/clair-obscur-expedition-33/9PPT8K6GQHRZ/0010&quot;&gt;Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&lt;/a&gt; via Cloud Gaming. After about 13 hours in, I realized I wanted to buy the game. As it turns out, Steam likes Linux and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protondb.com/app/1903340&quot;&gt;the game runs well there&lt;/a&gt;. It was on sale in a bundle, so I went ahead and bought it &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1903340/Clair_Obscur_Expedition_33/&quot;&gt;from Steam&lt;/a&gt;  instead of from Xbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, my 13-hour-old save game was trapped in the cloud. I guessed I&#39;d just have to abandon it and start over. That is, until I pieced a few things together:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/xbox-play-anywhere&quot;&gt;Xbox Play Anywhere&lt;/a&gt;, the saves in Cloud Gaming sync down to PC game installations. I had one old Windows laptop left in the house that would install Game Pass games - it just played them horribly. Once I installed the game locally from Game Pass and booted it up once, my cloud save descended onto my laptop hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I installed the game again from Steam - i.e. the copy I purchased. From there, I could follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/app/1903340/discussions/0/592895445665061488/&quot;&gt;this guide to transplant my save file from Game Pass to Steam&lt;/a&gt;. Once properly transplanted, the save game found its way onto Steam&#39;s cloud sync servers and then back onto my real gaming PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
For posterity, in case that thread goes away, I copied from the newest modified directory here: ```C:\Users\me\AppData\Local\Packages\KeplerInteractive.Expedition33_ymj30pw7xe604\SystemAppData\wgs\00090000044E48CB_000000000000000000000000697F9EC3```

And I copied to here: ```C:\Users\me\AppData\Local\Sandfall\Saved\SaveGames\76561198015267336```

Oh, and it needed renaming to `EXPEDITION_0.sav` - easy peasy. 
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize this sounds like the plot to a dork heist. But, it worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:40:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/liberating-xbox-cloud-saves/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/liberating-xbox-cloud-saves/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-19</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.portlandmercury.com/photo/2025/05/19/47791648/log-lady-look-alike-contest-photos-shes-got-the-look-and-the-log&quot;&gt;Log Lady Look-Alike Contest Photos&lt;/a&gt;: She’s Got the Look (and the Log)&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love this city.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting bugs here in my Rube Goldberg blogging machine involving Syncthing and Obsidian, where sync conflicts become clashing ghost entries 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I should tweak support for a &lt;code&gt;draft&lt;/code&gt; flag here, so that posts that I&#39;m still editing don&#39;t get published automatically. This flow is almost &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; frictionless, at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using Obsidian for about 5 years now for my daily notes. I&#39;ve been tempted to take another swing at writing my own notebook, because I barely use any of Obsidian&#39;s fancier features. I mainly like that&#39;s it&#39;s a good cross-platform Markdown editor with a few plugins that I&#39;ve settled on for regular use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a vague notion to make a USB or wifi interface for an old Atari Video Touch Pad. Could use it as a Stream Deck (if I ever stream again) and / or hook it up to Home Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/miscellanea/attachments/2025-05-19-video-touch-pad.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need to find a better way to insert images like this 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>I like (reading about) making video games</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Noel Berry, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://noelberry.ca/posts/making_games_in_2025/&quot;&gt;Making Video Games in 2025 (without an engine)&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely believe making games without a big &quot;do everything&quot; engine can be easier, more fun, and often less overhead. I am not making a &quot;do everything&quot; game and I do not need 90% of the features these engines provide. I am very particular about how my games feel and look, and how I interact with my tools. I often find the default feature implementations in large engines like Unity so lacking I end up writing my own anyway. Eventually, my projects end up being mostly my own tools and systems, and the engine becomes just a vehicle for a nice UI and some rendering...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read blog posts and tutorials like this all the time. Every few months, I go on a spree of installing and firing up game development tools. I keep kind of wanting to actually end up finishing a game, kind of like how my dad used to make a few fly fishing lures but only ever managed to go fishing every few years. But, do I like reading about this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this post snags me, in particular, because one of the reasons I even started poking around with game dev stuff was to learn. And what better way to really just plummet down the rabbit hole than to learn how to make a game engine almost from scratch?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, but in terms of actually finishing things: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2016/09/11/poke-the-mongo/&quot;&gt;I can say&lt;/a&gt; I made &lt;a href=&quot;https://lmorchard.itch.io/poke-the-mongo&quot;&gt;Poke the Mongo&lt;/a&gt; for Pico-8! That&#39;s at least one finished video game. It&#39;s got &lt;a href=&quot;https://lmorchard.itch.io/poke-the-mongo&quot;&gt;an itch.io page&lt;/a&gt; and an end-game screen and everything. I won&#39;t spoil the end screen, though I&#39;m pretty sure I only know one other person who&#39;s ever seen it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:08:09 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/gamedev-reading/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/gamedev-reading/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Beyond Text-only AI</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fatih Kadir Akın, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fka.dev/blog/2025-05-16-beyond-text-only-ai-on-demand-ui-generation-for-better-conversational-experiences/&quot;&gt;Beyond Text-Only AI: On-Demand UI Generation for Better Conversational Experience&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if AI systems could generate precisely the right interface components when needed, without requiring developers to build every possible UI variation in advance? This post explores my work on a new prototype that enables LLMs to create dynamic, interactive UI components on demand, transforming how users interact with AI systems and MCP servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where LLMs are very interesting to me, where applications with them are most able to escape hype into practical building. A thing they&#39;re good at is taking some of the vague stuff we hand-wave at like &quot;you know, that thing with the days in squares on it&quot; and jumping to &quot;you mean a calendar?&quot; But then, skip straight from that to presenting a calendar for input as part of the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m finding LLMs most handy when they work in smaller universes. Give it a relatively small inventory of UI components, properly described with context, and they can be great at picking which one to use and when. Hard to hallucinate when there&#39;s not a wide range for wandering, easy to mitigate what hallucinations might occur when you can automatically kick it back into bounds. Meanwhile, the workflow can feel more smooth and demand less fiddly navigation from a user. That seems like a really promising glimmer to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 22:28:39 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/beyond-text-only-ai/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/beyond-text-only-ai/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Foggy Blogging</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Baldur Bjarnason, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.baldurbjarnason.com/notes/2025/foggy-feeds/&quot;&gt;Foggy feeds: the decline in my feed reader subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...I follow a lot of feeds in my feed reader, most of them only updating at most once a month, maybe weekly, and only a tiny handful update daily. About seven hundred (700) of the feeds I follow are active and I’ve been following some of them since the early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a decent sample size both across fields – tech, media, and academia – and time – I’ve been following most of these since before COVID – and the decline in people’s thinking across many of these feeds has been noticeable because it’s incredibly fucking annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My feeds suck, right now. My main excuse is I&#39;m way out of the habit of blogging like I did 20 years ago. And I think part of that habit is thinking out loud, getting things out into words in front of me to clarify the thinking. Tweets and toots aren&#39;t really long enough to let a fully formed notion flop out of my head and thrash around on the desk for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do know a lot of folks who got COVID, though. Gratefully, I seem to have avoided it so far. Is this like the notion that &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/07/did-lead-poisoning-cause-downfall-of-roman-empire-the-jury-is-still-out/&quot;&gt;the Roman Empire collapsed due to lead poisoning&lt;/a&gt;? I do feel like there&#39;s a lot of stupidity out there right now, like more than I&#39;d expect. I don&#39;t know if that&#39;s a conspiracy theory or just cynicism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 19:58:20 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/foggy-blogging/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/foggy-blogging/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>AI winter, again</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;carl svensson, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datagubbe.se/winter/&quot;&gt;Is Winter Coming?&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even when it comes to something like LLM-assisted programming, where a highly skilled developer can maybe, sometimes, somewhat gain a performance boost, the most pertinent question isn&#39;t if it can be done at all - but rather if what can be done good enough can also be done profitably. The number of GPUs and the amount of increasingly expensive energy required remains as unclear as the time frame needed to accomplish it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t disagree that this is where things are right now. Personally, I&#39;m getting utility from these tools - mainly for things that I could do myself, but the LLM lets me carve off a few rounds of googling and Stack Overflow browsing. That&#39;s valuable. Probably not as valuable as investors are hoping, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see some glimmers of potential in letting the agents rip in full-auto. But, I do also find that ofttimes they&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;https://prototypr.io/note/vibe-coding-cursor-windsurf-slot-machine&quot;&gt;developer slot machines&lt;/a&gt; that need careful tending to keep them from going off into the weeds, going into loops, and going off on quests for which I never asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m seeing the most value in these tools when they&#39;re given a lot of context and kept constrained to limited tasks in a tight loop with adult supervision. I&#39;ve got a hunch this will improve over time, but who knows? We could hit a wall and see winter soon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;d really like it if this stuff would settle down and be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastly.com/blog/can-we-be-normal-about-ai-now-that-deepseek-happened&quot;&gt;normal&lt;/a&gt;. But, there&#39;s probably going to be a crash before that happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 18:07:43 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/llm-winter/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/llm-winter/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-18</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I made lentil stew and roasted coffee. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also cooked some dried pinto beans in the Instant Pot for dinners this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a little Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 and DOOM: The Dark Ages.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lampmaster is a jerk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beating a boss demon at tennis is fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wanted to work on some tinkering projects but couldn’t quite find the motivation. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/18/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/18/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-17</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today was Eurovision day, and not much else got done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/17/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/17/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-16</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I listen to podcasts at between 1.8x - 2.5x, depending on the day&#39;s mental weather. That means, when I&#39;ve met a podcaster I listen to, they sound drugged or drunk to me.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve had folks tell me this sounds stressful. But, I get distracted in the gaps and my mind wanders. Easier for me to follow rapid word dumps. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is not a flex, this is a coping strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new Peter Murphy album, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://petermurphy.bandcamp.com/album/silver-shade&quot;&gt;Silver Shade&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, sure is Peter Murphy. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t hate this at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m really digging the collabs he did here, teaming up with folks like Boy George, Trent Reznor, and Justin Chancellor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hey, you, service provider on the web that I pay for: I am annoyed that I&#39;m constantly signed out when I come to visit. You don&#39;t remember me, and you are constantly trying to call-to-action and dark-pattern me into your growth hacks when I already have an account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Burning out in a business (mech) suit</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brilliantcrank (Greg Storey), &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://brilliantcrank.com/the-coyote-trap/?ref=brilliantcrank-newsletter&quot;&gt;The coyote trap.&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if survival looked like ownership instead? What if the best response to getting laid off isn’t to get in the line to nowhere for the next thing, but to build your own thing? Do your own thing? The tools are there. The access is there. The demand is there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve got too many smart, experienced people standing at the edge of the workforce, assuming their only move is down or to keep trying what worked yesterday. From what I read many folks fear an AI fuled collapse, but I fear another powered by denial, retreat, and stubborn nostalgia. If enough of us take this route, we’re going to see a quiet, steady slide of educated, capable folks into poverty—and that’s not just a personal tragedy, it’s a societal one. And no amount of boycotting or avoiding AI is going to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been thinking a lot about this, lately. And I keep thinking about &quot;my own thing&quot; that I could build. I&#39;ve had some ideas, but I&#39;m not sure any of them are big enough to convince people to shovel enough money at me to pay my mortgage?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, I&#39;ve never felt a particular urge to be an entrepreneur. That doesn&#39;t sound like my kind of fun, at all. Ownership, being my own boss, making all the decisions, taking all the risk. Not enticing to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, not that I think this would be a great business, but: Since I got my 3D printer, I&#39;ve seen lots of folks running little garage print farms. Looks like fun! I&#39;d love to have a dozen or two machines whirring away. But then I realize, practically speaking, a print farm isn&#39;t about printing. It&#39;s about bookkeeping, inventory, visits to the UPS store, and self-marketing—and I don&#39;t like any of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems like every idea I&#39;ve come up with boils down to that. Even if I&#39;m just thinking about being a freelancer doing what I already do for work. The thing is not the thing. You have to build &amp;amp; maintain a business mech suit around the thing to make the money happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think I would like it. I think it would burn me out after not very long. That&#39;s not denial or retreat or nostalgia—I think that&#39;s just self-honesty. I mean, if it&#39;s that or starving, I&#39;ll do the needful somehow. But, for as much as I&#39;m a socially-anxious hermit, I like being on a team or in a crew. I want to do my part, play my role. I don&#39;t want to try to pull off the whole heist by myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&#39;m definitely not avoiding AI, and I&#39;m working to stay current. But I&#39;m not sure I&#39;m hanging out my own shingle any time soon?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:15:48 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/solo-burnout/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/solo-burnout/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Hey Ron, who&#39;s driving?</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chris Stokel-Walker, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://leaddev.com/software-quality/why-untested-ai-generated-code-is-a-crisis-waiting-to-happen&quot;&gt;Why untested AI-generated code is a crisis waiting to happen&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fear is of a slow-burn crisis where generative AI engines spew reams of code, stitched from web-scraped snippets with dubious provenance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When that code leaps from prompt to production without being vetted, the potential attack surface balloons in size. The bill for defective code is already sizable: 40% of firms say malfunctioning or miscoded software costs them at least $1 million a year, through staff churn, increased technical debt, and escalating maintenance costs, with losses above $5 million in almost half of large US firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, don&#39;t let &quot;code leap from prompt to production without being vetted&quot; - it&#39;s not like it happens on its own. Steady hand on the tiller. Vibe coding is fine for screwing around and exploration, but assume you&#39;re going to be on pager duty for whatever hits production. And if someday you stick an LLM on pager duty, may Eris have mercy on your soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IfY49zx7RU0?si=Gx2gyj-rqsBSHoL-&amp;amp;start=46&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 00:00:28 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/review-ai-code/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/review-ai-code/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Ruining YouTube on purpose</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Android Authority, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.androidauthority.com/youtube-peak-points-ads-3557905/&quot;&gt;YouTube’s new ads will ruin the best part of a video on purpose&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube is always cooking up new ways to show you ads. Be it skippable ads, non-skippable ads, mid-rolls, or bumpers, the goal, as always, is to find more places to make more money. And now, thanks to AI, YouTube has found a brand-new spot to squeeze in ads — right when something exciting happens in a video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think I quite understand the point of ads on YouTube, these days. Are they there to get me to think favorably of an advertiser and buy something from them? Or are they there to annoy me into paying for YouTube Premium? Does this make anyone happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 23:52:08 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/ads-ruining-youtube/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/ads-ruining-youtube/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>