<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: reading - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/reading/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>I like (reading about) making video games</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Noel Berry, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://noelberry.ca/posts/making_games_in_2025/&quot;&gt;Making Video Games in 2025 (without an engine)&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I genuinely believe making games without a big &quot;do everything&quot; engine can be easier, more fun, and often less overhead. I am not making a &quot;do everything&quot; game and I do not need 90% of the features these engines provide. I am very particular about how my games feel and look, and how I interact with my tools. I often find the default feature implementations in large engines like Unity so lacking I end up writing my own anyway. Eventually, my projects end up being mostly my own tools and systems, and the engine becomes just a vehicle for a nice UI and some rendering...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read blog posts and tutorials like this all the time. Every few months, I go on a spree of installing and firing up game development tools. I keep kind of wanting to actually end up finishing a game, kind of like how my dad used to make a few fly fishing lures but only ever managed to go fishing every few years. But, do I like reading about this stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this post snags me, in particular, because one of the reasons I even started poking around with game dev stuff was to learn. And what better way to really just plummet down the rabbit hole than to learn how to make a game engine almost from scratch?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, but in terms of actually finishing things: &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2016/09/11/poke-the-mongo/&quot;&gt;I can say&lt;/a&gt; I made &lt;a href=&quot;https://lmorchard.itch.io/poke-the-mongo&quot;&gt;Poke the Mongo&lt;/a&gt; for Pico-8! That&#39;s at least one finished video game. It&#39;s got &lt;a href=&quot;https://lmorchard.itch.io/poke-the-mongo&quot;&gt;an itch.io page&lt;/a&gt; and an end-game screen and everything. I won&#39;t spoil the end screen, though I&#39;m pretty sure I only know one other person who&#39;s ever seen it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:08:09 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/gamedev-reading/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/gamedev-reading/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Musing about e-books, libraries, and tracking my reading</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just ripped through Martha Wells&#39; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/41742208-the-cloud-roads&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cloud Roads&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; in a couple days. Sadly, the next volume in the series is on hold at the library. But, I think I can live until it&#39;s my turn to check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve just really gotten in a good groove with e-book lending from &lt;a href=&quot;https://multcolib.overdrive.com/&quot;&gt;my local library system&lt;/a&gt;. I hate that OverDrive&#39;s artificial scarcity and DRM system exists as such, but I love that my tax dollars are shoveling books into my hands on a steady drip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also helps that I&#39;ve managed to keep a morning habit of exercise biking and reading going since last fall. Sometimes, I end up riding 10 - 20 minutes past my intended time, just because I can&#39;t put the book down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m tempted to work my Goodreads activity into things over here - do a little &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/PESOS&quot;&gt;PESOS&lt;/a&gt; action to give me some markdown to play with. Also tempted to migrate to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bookwyrm-social/bookwyrm&quot;&gt;Bookwyrm&lt;/a&gt; and own my own reading records. But, the Kindle integration with Goodreads is effortless. It&#39;s almost accidental that I&#39;m recording my reading at all. Maybe I could synchronize them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been tempted to eject from the Amazon Kindle ecosystem. I could kind of do it with my BOOX e-ink tablet, but it&#39;s rather big and better suited for PDFs. I&#39;m on my 3rd Kindle in about 10 years and they haven&#39;t entirely annoyed me away yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 21:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/15/reading/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/15/reading/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Too long? Read anyway.</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Wherein I rant at medium length about functional literacy and language competency in knowledge work and information technology.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/02/25/too-long-read-anyway/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/02/25/too-long-read-anyway/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>