<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />      
      <item>
          <title>Professional JavaScript Frameworks is a real book!</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2009 19:22:58 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/08/20/professional-javascript-frameworks-is-a-real-book/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/08/20/professional-javascript-frameworks-is-a-real-book/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>HTML5 drag and drop in Firefox 3.5</title>
          <description>Oh hey, look! It&#39;s another blog post—and this one
is cross-posted on hacks.mozilla.com.
I won&#39;t say this is the start of a renewed blogging habit, but let&#39;s see what happens.




    
        Drag and drop is one of the most fundamental interactions
        afforded by graphical user interfaces.  In one gesture, it
        allows users to pair the selection of an object with the
        execution of an action, often including a second object in the
        operation.  It&#39;s a simple yet powerful UI concept used to
        support copying, list reordering, deletion (ala the Trash / Recycle Bin),
        and even the creation of link relationships.
    
        Since it&#39;s so fundamental, offering drag and drop in web
        applications has been a no-brainer ever since browsers first
        offered mouse events in DHTML.  But, although
        mousedown, mousemove, and
        mouseup made it possible, the implementation has been
        limited to the bounds of the browser window.  Additionally,
        since these events refer only to the object being dragged,
        there&#39;s a challenge to find the subject of the drop when
        the interaction is completed.
    

    Of course, that doesn&#39;t prevent most modern JavaScript
    frameworks from abstracting away most of the problems and
    throwing in some flourishes while they&#39;re at it.  But, wouldn&#39;t
    it be nice if browsers offered first-class support for drag and
    drop, and maybe even extended it beyond the window sandbox?
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    As it turns out, this very wish is answered by the HTML 5 specification 
    &lt;a target=&quot;_new&quot; href=&quot;http://www.whatwg.org/specs/web-apps/current-work/multipage/editing.html#dnd&quot;&gt;section on new drag-and-drop events&lt;/a&gt;, and 
    &lt;a target=&quot;_new&quot; href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/En/DragDrop/Drag_and_Drop&quot;&gt;Firefox 3.5 includes an implementation&lt;/a&gt; of those events.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    If you want to jump straight to the code, I&#39;ve put together 
    &lt;a target=&quot;_new&quot; target=&quot;_new&quot; target=&quot;_new&quot; href=&quot;http://decafbad.com/2009/07/drag-and-drop/api-demos.html&quot;&gt;some simple demos&lt;/a&gt; 
    of the new events.  
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;

    I&#39;ve even scratched an itch of my own and
    built &lt;a target=&quot;_new&quot; target=&quot;_new&quot; target=&quot;_new&quot; href=&quot;http://decafbad.com/2009/07/drag-and-drop/outline.html&quot;&gt;the beginnings of an outline editor&lt;/a&gt;,
    where every draggable element is also a drop target—of which
    there could be dozens to hundreds in a complex document, something
    that gave me some minor hair-tearing moments in the past
    while trying to make do with plain old mouse events.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    And, all the above can be downloaded or cloned from 
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/lmorchard/fx35-drag-and-drop&quot;&gt;a GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;
    I&#39;ve created especially for this article—which continues after the jump.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 15:26:40 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/07/15/html5-drag-and-drop/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/07/15/html5-drag-and-drop/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Controlled Monetization</title>
          <description>I took the pills. Like everyone else, I took the pills and I sent in the hair and the piss to prove I took the pills. I’d figured something out, though: I could stop taking the pills for the first half of the month, then double up at the end. I still passed the tests; no one knocked on the door.</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/05/30/controlled-monetization/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/05/30/controlled-monetization/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>From Spaceman to Plantsman</title>
          <description>The first time the spaceman saw my garden, I thought he was going to strangle me.</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/05/30/from-spaceman-to-plantsman/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/05/30/from-spaceman-to-plantsman/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>I (used to) like rev=&quot;canonical&quot;</title>
          <description>Update 4/14: So, I liked rev=&quot;canonical&quot;, but I like the notion of pages offering sets of alternative URLs better.  There are enough cracks in the case for rev=&quot;canonical&quot; to stop caring about it and instead focus on the notion behind it.  However it&#39;s expressed—is it rel=&quot;shortlink&quot; now?—the final remaining things I&#39;d like to see are:

An more generalized scope for alternate URL choices asserted by publishers, not just URL shortening.  Other criteria beyond character length include ease of entry on mobile devices (eg. short, but also simple, maybe mostly numeric), ease of verbal mention (eg. billboards, postcards, etc).

HTTP headers are great where available—hooray for HEAD—but it still needs to be in the page for publishers who can&#39;t set custom headers.

Microformats are great, but I&#39;d rather not parse a whole page to the footer to lift out the desired URLs.

Don&#39;t panic. Have fun.


And with that, I&#39;m going to try coming up with other things to write about so this blog doesn&#39;t stay dormant.  The rest of this entry remains unedited below...</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 05:05:50 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/04/13/i-like-revcanonical/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/04/13/i-like-revcanonical/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>7 facts about me</title>
          <description>So, it finally happened—I&#39;ve been tagged by Stephen Donner.  I&#39;ve not been one to follow memes in this blog, but this one&#39;s been going around the Mozillasphere for awhile now and has been kind of interesting.  I&#39;m half-tempted to bookmark and tag all the entries I&#39;ve caught so far.  Anyway, the rules:

Link to your original tagger(s) and list these rules in your post.
Share seven facts about yourself in the post.
Tag seven people at the end of your post by leaving their names and the links to their blogs.
Let them know they’ve been tagged.

Now, for your random facts, after the jump:</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2009 16:59:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/23/7-facts-about-me/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/23/7-facts-about-me/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Tags do work (for me, at least)</title>
          <description>For the &quot;too long; didn&#39;t read&quot; crowd:

I&#39;ve been using a lot of tags on Delicious over a relatively long time, so they seem very useful to me.
Delicious encourages the use of tags through UI convention and tool usage patterns, whereas Flickr presents no particular bias toward collecting tags from users.
Since title and description attract more contribution effort from users on Flickr than on Delicious, it&#39;s natural that search over those fields will be more productive than for tags.
Search on Delicious doesn&#39;t have access to the complete text of the bookmarked resource, and often tags will contain information missing from the supplied title or description.
All told, tags on Delicious are more essential than tags on Flickr.
In conclusion, I think Do Tags Work? misses the value of tags, as I know them, by focusing on Flickr.

Of course, I don&#39;t really care what this means for folksonomy and the rest of Web 2.0—tags work for me on Delicious.  So, I suspect this means I&#39;m not entirely opposed to the sentiment in Do Tags Work?, because I don&#39;t think tags work everywhere their use is attempted.
The rest of this entry elaborates on the above.</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 06:29:34 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/18/tags-do-work-for-me-at-least/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/18/tags-do-work-for-me-at-least/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Enter the LizardFeeder</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 00:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/06/enter-the-lizardfeeder/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/06/enter-the-lizardfeeder/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Resolutions</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 19:10:22 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/05/resolutions/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/05/resolutions/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Three Years in Review</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2009 19:09:22 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/05/three-years-in-review/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/01/05/three-years-in-review/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>