<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels and self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/</link>
      <item>
          <title>Arthur&#39;s got a bulging blogroll</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;http://timeistight.com/index.php?entry=/blogs%20and%20blogging/0xDECAFBAD.txt&quot;&gt;0xDECAFBAD (I love that name) has a new design, powered by Blosxom. I like it. You&amp;apos;re going in my bulging blogroll, Les.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source:&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://timeistight.com/index.php?entry=/blogs%20and%20blogging/0xDECAFBAD.txt&quot;&gt;Time is Tight: 0xDECAFBAD v2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My referrer monitoring scripts have been out of action since shortly
after I revised my site design, so I&amp;apos;ve been missing links.  Today, I
fired things up again for the first time since the beginning of the
months and caught the above.  Wow, and I&amp;apos;m an Elite Geek, at that!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Welcome to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/0xDECAFBAD&quot;&gt;0xDECAFBAD&lt;/a&gt;!  You can do anything at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/0xDECAFBAD&quot;&gt;0xDECAFBAD&lt;/a&gt;!  The
unattainable is unknown at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/0xDECAFBAD&quot;&gt;0xDECAFBAD&lt;/a&gt;!  Yes, this is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/0xDECAFBAD&quot;&gt;0xDECAFBAD&lt;/a&gt;, and
welcome to you who have come to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/0xDECAFBAD&quot;&gt;0xDECAFBAD&lt;/a&gt;!  Welcome!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(Please tell me someone out there knows what I&amp;apos;m going on about.)
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2003 23:01:45 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/26/arthurs-blogroll/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/26/arthurs-blogroll/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>The A500 ain&#39;t 3G</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;http://www.mobitopia.com/20030326.html#191341&quot;&gt;Sheesh. Okay, come back to us when you get a real phone.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source:&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mobitopia.com/20030326.html#191341&quot;&gt;Mobitopia: Slashdot - Life in 3G&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So says Mr. Beattie.  And I say, &amp;quot;Hey, that&amp;apos;s &lt;strong&gt;my&lt;/strong&gt; phone!&amp;quot;  And then I
say, &amp;quot;Oh yeah, that&amp;apos;s right, that&amp;apos;s my phone.&amp;quot;  I like my phone, it&amp;apos;s a
nice phone.  I had a Treo Communicator, but it went kaput.  I thought the
A500 would be a decent 3G device.  It&amp;apos;s not.  But it&amp;apos;s a nice phone...
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2003 20:42:11 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/26/a500-not-3g/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/26/a500-not-3g/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>The Singularity vs Human Nature</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Apologies in advance if this post-cum-essay runs a bit long...
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;http://www.disenchanted.com/dis/humanity/brainbuilder.html?id=8Mir9Pz5&quot;&gt;We could conclude that modern human intelligence is an unfinished product, and something that nature hasn&amp;apos;t quite got around to polishing yet. The problem-solving intelligence part can be tuned and revved up to high levels, but it becomes unstable like early supersonic jet prototypes that shook themselves to pieces just after reaching the sound barrier. Nature has outstripped itself, producing a freak organism with a feature that&amp;apos;s obscenely over-developed but under-refined. We&amp;apos;ve seen examples of evolution getting ahead of itself before, like the rapid conversion to an erect, bipedal skeletal frame without properly modifying the spine to withstand the back-aching load of pregnancy. To get a better grip of human failings, and human stupidity, you have to realize that modern Homo sapiens sapiens just isn&amp;apos;t done yet.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source:&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disenchanted.com/dis/humanity/brainbuilder.html?id=8Mir9Pz5&quot;&gt;Disenchanted: * Early prototype, expect instability&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;http://www.disenchanted.com/dis/technology/mediated.html?id=AtW2JdUp&quot;&gt;When our own instincts are inadequate, or become a hazard, and the surrogate activities to control them aren&amp;apos;t sufficient anymore, then there certainly will be a push to change human nature to fit his new, self-crafted niche. And the answer to my original question?that man will invent something that knocks him out of his niche with fatal consequences?is yes. Homo sapien will die, and homo modified will inherit the earth.&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source:&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disenchanted.com/dis/technology/mediated.html?id=AtW2JdUp&quot;&gt;Disenchanted: Invent this and die&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There&amp;apos;s only an essay or two per month published over at Disenchanted,
but they&amp;apos;re gems, each and every one.  And what I read almost never
fails to resonate with something I&amp;apos;ve been thinking or musing about,
from my perspective as a geek wondering about life, the universe, and
everything and as a fan of Kurzweil, Vinge, and all of post-humanity.
But my anticipation of the Singularity is constantly swayed by things
such as the theses of the above quoted essays.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
See, as an irredeemable believer in the ways of better living through
technology, I look forward to our increasing ability to further
self-improve and bootstrap to higher levels of living, longevity,
ability, understanding, and exploration.  But, there&amp;apos;s a neopagan
mystic and naturalist in me who keeps looking for the catch.  There
must be natural limits we don&amp;apos;t yet understand.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
No matter the precocious cleverness of our species, there&amp;apos;s got to be
plenty of good reasons it takes millions of years to achieve progress
in forms and patterns of life.  There are lots of little subtle
details to be easily missed.  We&amp;apos;re smart, but not yet endowed with
the patience and wisdom that eternity grants.  I both breathlessly
await and fear the arrival of our ability to fundamentally change
human nature directly through genetic manipulation and device
implantation.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As the first essay quoted above asserts, I believe the human species
is unfinished.  But as with the second essay, I think we&amp;apos;ve outpaced
evolution in terms of changing the conditions under which the process
itself occurs.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Just look around you.  You&amp;apos;re likely indoors, in a building composed
of simple straight lines which register easily on your visual pattern
recognizers, with corridors and doorways and rooms proportioned to
your bodily dimensions.  The air is conditioned to your respiratory
and temperature tolerances.  Things are padded and accessible.  Food
and drink are likely plentiful.  The only predators you&amp;apos;re likely to
meet up with during your day are of your own species.  Nothing really
challenges your basic nature.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yet, this is just what the universe has been doing to forms of life
throughout the history of evolution.  Only now, we&amp;apos;ve jumped the
tracks, reversed the flow of control, and have reshaped our corner of
the universe to fit our status quo.  So, where does that leave the
natural process of evolution with regard to us?  Stopped or slowed to
a crawl, that&amp;apos;s where.  Maybe falling backward, since we have
prosthetics, glasses, and other forms of propping up imperfections
that would have otherwise been faced with disincentives by natural
selection.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, where are we without a natural evolution?  We&amp;apos;re left as an
unfinished species, with a peculiar mix of awesome abilities matched
with amazing disabilities.  Very clever people, but with a lot of
blind spots.  There are certain ways in which it is very difficult and
sometimes nearly impossible for us to think.  We have biases toward
grouping things by similarity, dividing them by difference - which
allows for a very elegant economy of memory and thought, but allows
for peculiarly devastating things like racism and xenophobia.
Critical thinking is counterintuitive, yet is one of our most powerful
tools.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And there are definite flaws in our perceptions of reality, as any
book of optical illusions will tell you.  One thing that struck me
like a thunderbolt came from a human biology class: Ever try following
a common housefly with your eyes?  Isn&amp;apos;t it frustrating how it just
seems to &lt;strong&gt;vanish&lt;/strong&gt; from your sight?  I can&amp;apos;t find a reference to back
me up, so this is just from memory: I was taught that flies have
developed a particularly zig-zaggy and erratic flight pattern to evade
just our kind of mammalian vision system.  But, studies of fly-eating
frogs have shown that their vision systems appear particularly tweaked
to react to a fly&amp;apos;s midair dance.  Imagine what else slips past us, or
comes to our attention garbled because our very apparatus contains
biases of which we&amp;apos;re yet to even conceive?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Here we are, then, flawed and incomplete yet with a growing ability to
self-modify.  As an amateur computer scientist, I shudder a bit at any
code that&amp;apos;s self-modifying.  It can be done, and it can be powerfully
enabling, but it&amp;apos;s just so damn easy to blow a foot off with the
technique.  So too with ourselves, then.  There&amp;apos;s a possiblity that we
can push ourselves into a richer level of thought and perception and
ability without destroying ourselves completely.  But, we&amp;apos;re going to
miss things, important things.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If we&amp;apos;re lucky, we&amp;apos;ll roll with it and survive.  But, as the second
Disenchanted essay explores, we&amp;apos;ll most certainly render the species
as we know it extinct, and push ourselves our of a natural niche and
into a wholly artificial niche in need of perpetual maintenance and
renewal.  Maybe this artifical niche will be easily sustained and
portable enough to take with us if we want to leave the planet.  On
the other hand, maybe this artificial niche will prove our undoing as
it outstrips our ability to keep it up.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, given all this, I think the inevitable predicted verticality of
the Singularity&amp;apos;s curve has an incredibly strong counter-force
stemming from human nature itself.  What does this mean?  Not sure.
What to do?  Not sure.  But it tells me that the Kurzweilan and
Vingian predictions of which I&amp;apos;m so fond face some severe reality
checks.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
More thinking to do.  Thanks to Disenchanted for making me think this
far today.  :)
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2003 17:32:49 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/26/singularity-vs-human-nature/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/26/singularity-vs-human-nature/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>I want to trade my Gameboy Advance for a GP32.</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote cite=&quot;http://www.gbax.com/gp32review.html&quot;&gt;
It comes out the box with an English manual, a PC link cable, the GP32
uses PC smartMedia as its Hard disk and has 8meg of internal ram + its
(upgradeable) OS, a USB port, a large hires screen (which is SO much
better than the GBA one), two stereo speakers (one on each side), a
joypad and 6 buttons (4 on front and 2 shoulder buttons), a 3v in
socket, a headphone socket, volume control, battery compartment (2xAA
for 10-14 hours) &amp;amp; an EXT out port which allows you to do many things
including using the gp32 on your TV or for wireless multiplayer.
...The console is open source and fully supports people making their
own programs for it, there is a GCC based devkit complete with
graphics and sound libs.
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;credit&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;small&gt;Source:&lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gbax.com/gp32review.html&quot;&gt;GBAx.com review of the GP32&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Just read a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gbax.com/gp32review.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;review of the GP32&lt;/a&gt;,
a handheld game console I&amp;apos;d never heard of before.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gbax.com/gp32pics.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Pictures of it&lt;/a&gt; look amazing,
and the specs aren&amp;apos;t too shabby either.  Powerful enough to run
emulators of a sickening array of game platforms, uses &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/SmartMedia?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;SmartMedia&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
cards, support wireless multiplayer via cell phone.  And, oh yeah, it
looks like you can actually see the screen.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The biggest flaw I see in this thing is that it would be so easy to
pirate games for it.  Supposedly there were some attempts to provide
for a mechanism to &amp;quot;lock&amp;quot; games to a particular handheld, but that
appears to already have been circumvented.  So, while the thing looks
like a dream machine to me, it probably looks like a nightmare to game
producers.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Still, though, I want one.  And I bet Russell Beattie wouldn&amp;apos;t mind
one either, if he hasn&amp;apos;t heard about it yet, given his
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.russellbeattie.com/notebook/20021201.html#184646&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;professed love for his GameBoy Advance&lt;/a&gt;.
And, speaking of Russell, I wonder just how well that wireless
multiplayer support works...
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2003 21:59:37 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/25/i-want-a-gp32/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/25/i-want-a-gp32/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>New release of BookmarkBlogger available</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Playing with a few other little widgets here and there, I thought I&amp;apos;d 
fire off a new revision to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/BookmarkBlogger&quot;&gt;BookmarkBlogger&lt;/a&gt; for Safari I&amp;apos;ve been using
off and on.  This one&amp;apos;s a big more OS-X-ish, and uses a properties file
for configuration instead of completely confusing command line options.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/ShareAndEnjoy&quot;&gt;ShareAndEnjoy&lt;/a&gt;!  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Also working on a lil DOM4J-, JTidy-, and &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/BeanShell?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;BeanShell&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;-based scraper
for producing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; from arbitrary web sites.  Yeah, it&amp;apos;s been done before,
but not by me and not quite like this.  And eventually I think I want to 
try turning both this and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/BookmarkBlogger&quot;&gt;BookmarkBlogger&lt;/a&gt; into dual-purpose standalone
and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AgentFrank&quot;&gt;AgentFrank&lt;/a&gt; plugin packages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2003 20:29:20 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/24/new-bookmark-blogger/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/24/new-bookmark-blogger/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>.NET Newbie</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So, while my time is mine, I&amp;apos;ve decided that I want to expand my
practical horizons.  And, one of the first things I can think of is to
go lateral and approach something I&amp;apos;ve looked upon with mild disdain:
Microsoft technologies.  In particular: .NET
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I already understand Unix well enough to do damn near anything -- this
is not to say that there aren&amp;apos;t still years worth of things left for
me to learn in that sphere, but I&amp;apos;m not nearly as adept with
Microsoft&amp;apos;s offerings.  And, besides the practical concerns with being
flexible enough to take on what work the world offers me, I also have
a hunch that this .NET thing will make me think as differently about
Microsoft as OS X made me change my mind about Apple.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Maybe.  But it&amp;apos;s still a good attitude with which a punk unixhead can
approach the subject, I think.  I&amp;apos;m going to assume that brighter
people than myself have applied themselves to the creation of .NET and
prepare to be surprised.  This attitude has always served me well in
the past when trying something new.  (Take Python, for instance.)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Okay.  Got a good attitude.  Have installations of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WinXP&quot;&gt;WinXP&lt;/a&gt; and Win2003
preview (which I&amp;apos;m kinda, grudgingly digging so far) running in
Virtual PC on my &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/PowerBook?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  Could even draft a PC at home into
service running an appropriate OS if need be.  Have downloaded the
.NET Framework and installed it on XP and Win2k3.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now what?  Were this Java, I&amp;apos;d pop open an emacs window and start
playing.  I&amp;apos;d grab some free app servers and check some things out.
Being on a fixed budget, I don&amp;apos;t think I can spring for any packages
like Visual Studio .NET.  And being a unixhead, I&amp;apos;m used to being able
to find dev tools for free.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Anyway, this absolute newbie is continuing to poke around.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 19:20:55 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/17/dot-net-newbie/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/17/dot-net-newbie/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>No More Searchling?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So, as I&amp;apos;m working to recover all the old tools I knew and loved on my
iBook, I see this on the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.ics.purdue.edu/~mthole/searchling/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Searchling home page&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;Work on Searchling has ceased to focus on its successor
-- iSeek.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
...and there are no downloads for searchling available, neither binary
nor source.  Harumph!  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And the screenshots of iSeek don&amp;apos;t please me much -- I see a search
field wodged into the menu bar in place of the nice, slick ghostly
search field that would materialize with a quick Cmd-Space or a click
of the magnifying glass.  Gagh.  My menu bar&amp;apos;s already crowded enough
with &lt;strong&gt;menu entries&lt;/strong&gt; on this 12&amp;quot; screen as it is.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But, if I&amp;apos;m completely wrong, and there ends up being a feature to
make iSeek work and feel just like my old friend the Searchling...
well, then I say congratulations to its author for cobbling together a
saleable lil widget, and I&amp;apos;ll be waiting impatiently for its release.
:)
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 18:40:51 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/17/no-more-searchling/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/17/no-more-searchling/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Pagination for Blosxom</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;apos;s a little something I whipped up last week:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/BlosxomPaginate&quot;&gt;BlosxomPaginate&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;apos;ve been using Blosxom and Blagg for my news aggregator lately, just
for a change, and one thing I was really missing was some way to see
entries that fell off the end of the front page.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, I made this.  It
lets me flip back and forth between pages of Blosxom entries, and I
even went so wild as to include full flavour-based template support of
the display of the navigation elements.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/ShareAndEnjoy&quot;&gt;ShareAndEnjoy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 16:12:45 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/17/blosxom-paginate/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/17/blosxom-paginate/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Happy Trails to Me, I&#39;m Job-Free: Week One</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;apos;t written much last week, between the job search and getting
myself hooked up with a new laptop.  I&amp;apos;d meant to revise my initial
post announcing my being laid of - but instead, I simply lost it
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/misc/thirsty_ibook.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;when the iBook got doused&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, to those of you who haven&amp;apos;t heard my news: I was laid off a little
over a week and a weekend ago.  No hard feelings or fireworks, just
typical bad economy reasons.  Nevertheless, it took me by surprise.
So now I&amp;apos;m shopping my resume around.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If you&amp;apos;re interested, my resume is available here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/2003/03/l-m-orchard-resume.doc&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;http://www.decafbad.com/2003/03/l-m-orchard-resume.doc&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/2003/03/l-m-orchard-resume.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;http://www.decafbad.com/2003/03/l-m-orchard-resume.pdf&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Last week was strange.  Having been let go on a Friday, I had a
weekend to pretend things were all as usual.  But, when Monday hit,
things were different.  I still got up at the usual time, did the
usual morning things, and got out of the apartment as if I were going
to work.  But instead of heading for the highway, I headed for a
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espresso-royale.com/locations_detail.cfm?state=Michigan&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;coffee shop&lt;/a&gt;
near campus with wireless internet.  Trying to keep the old
patterns as normal as possible, only now my job is finding a job and
getting myself in shape for what&amp;apos;s out there.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It wouldn&amp;apos;t be news to anyone to hear that the job market, at least
what I&amp;apos;ve seen of it so far, is nothing like the verdant plains and
valleys of even 3 years ago - which is about the last time I took a
serious look.  After a first survey of a few job boards online, I
fired off a handful of resumes and apps, and took notes on what&amp;apos;s
being asked for so as to prepare some semblance of a learning plan
while I&amp;apos;m off.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So by the end of last week, I&amp;apos;d accomplished these various and sundry
things:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 5 cups of coffee consumed per day
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1 resume updated and revised
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 6 resumes emailed and 4 online applications filled
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 5 profiles completed at online recruiting sites
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1 application for unemployment filed
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1 12&amp;quot; G4 &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/PowerBook?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; acquired and configured
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 3 Microsoft operating systems installed and configured under Virtual PC
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1 .NET Framework installed and exploration begun
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 1 novel finished, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0872863328/103-7733542-0669406?vi=glance&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Close to the Machine&lt;/a&gt; by Ellen Ullman
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 6 hours of Metroid Prime played
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
There&amp;apos;s been more, but it&amp;apos;s the amount of Metroid Prime play I&amp;apos;m most
proud of - had I not gotten out of the apartment in the morning, the
hours invested in that would have been immensely greater.  Maybe after
I&amp;apos;ve fired off a few more resumes, I&amp;apos;ll feel better about actually
taking a rest since my brane&amp;apos;s been going full speed for months now at
work.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Thought a bit about striking out on my own with freelance work, but
the Ellen Ullman book has given me a bit of a strange mood.  She makes
working for oneself sound both promising and desolate at once - though
the promising bits would seem to be the things that disappeared with
the 90&amp;apos;s.  So that leaves it sounding pretty unpalatable.  Who knows,
though - I always wanted to work from (but not at) a coffee shop.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Well, back to searching and my first baby steps with .NET - wish me
luck.  And if you happen to be in town, stop by and say haloo.
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2003 13:57:42 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/17/first-week-off/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/17/first-week-off/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>iBooks Don&#39;t Get Thirsty</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just for future reference:  No matter what your cats think, iBooks 
never get thirsty for a nice big tumbler of water.  Nor do they
ever have a need to soak in the contents of said tumbler overnight.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Although now, I have an expensive, dead laptop that makes white
noise sounds not unlike the ocean when it&amp;apos;s plugged in.  And it 
smells like the magic blue smoke when it&amp;apos;s let out of the chip.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I just hope that the hard drive is recoverable.  Updates will be
sporadic as I try to reconstruct my environment and remember passwords
and try to find serial numbers.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Oh yeah, and still on the trail of the job hunt.  Going to be
tweaking some things around here as I have time, to make things
a bit more presentable for company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2003 02:25:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/12/thirsty-ibook/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/12/thirsty-ibook/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Ping Pong to Weblogs Dot Com</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://simon.incutio.com/archive/2003/03/09/aPleaForPings&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Simon Willison writes&lt;/a&gt;
that he&amp;apos;d read my blog more if I
&lt;a href=&quot;http://newhome.weblogs.com/faq#howCanMyWeblogParticipateInWeblogscom&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;pinged weblogs.com&lt;/a&gt;
more often.  I used to, via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MovableType&quot;&gt;MovableType&lt;/a&gt;, but my new blog doesn&amp;apos;t.  Enter
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raelity.org/apps/blosxom/plugins/notification/ping_weblogs_com.individual&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;ping_weblogs_com&lt;/a&gt;,
a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raelity.org/apps/blosxom/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Blosxom&lt;/a&gt; plugin to ping weblogs.com.  I&amp;apos;ve
just installed it.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Let&amp;apos;s see if he notices.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2003 01:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/10/ping-pong/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/10/ping-pong/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Building Pipelines with Web Services</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/tech/old/oooodh.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;on this day last year&lt;/a&gt;,
I was excitely thinking about pipelining webservices together like commands in a
UNIX command line shell.  Lately, I&amp;apos;ve been doing quite a bit of work at the
command line level, more so than I ever have before.  And for all the clunkiness
and inelegances to be found there, I think the zen has stuck me.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sure, it&amp;apos;s an ass-ugly string of characters that connects commands
like find, sort, awk, sed, grep, and ssh together.  But, in constructing such
monstrosities, I find myself generating new disposable tools at a rate
of at least one every minute or so.  And, though a few have found themselves graduating
into fuller, cleaner, more general tools, I would have been stuck for
hours were it not for a quick multi-file grep across a vast plain of comma-separated
value files digested by a tag team of sed and awk.  Then, like magic, I toss in
an incredibly slow yet, at the time, convenient call to mysql on another server
behind a firewall via ssh with a SQL call constructed from the regurgitations
of said sed and awk brothers.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, I&amp;apos;m thinking again:  How hot would this be if it were web services replacing
each of my commands?  How hot would it be if there was a STDIN, STDOUT, and STDERR
for a whole class of web services?  Imagine an enhanced bash or zsh piping these
beasts together.  For awhile, I thought my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpcFilteringPipe&quot;&gt;XmlRpcFilteringPipe&lt;/a&gt; API was the way to
go, but lately I&amp;apos;ve been thinking more in the direction of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt;.  I have to admit
that the XML-RPC API is a bit clunky to use, and besides, no one&amp;apos;s really paid
it much notice besides using it in the peculiar fashion I do to make my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WeblogWithWiki&quot;&gt;WeblogWithWiki&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
How about this for a simpler API:  Post data to a URL, receive data in response.
There&amp;apos;s your STDIN and STDOUT.  What about STDERR?  Well, I suppose it&amp;apos;s an
either-or affair, but standard HTTP header error codes can fill in there.  What
about command line arguments?  Use query parameters on the URL to which you&amp;apos;re
posting.  This all seems very web-natural.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Now I just have to write a shell that treats URLs as executable commands.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2003 17:39:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/06/web-service-pipelines/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/06/web-service-pipelines/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Did I dream the urchin phone?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, I don&amp;apos;t think I made this up:  I was reading Wired Magazine a
few months ago, and I saw a phone featured in the Fetish section
that was designed like a Koosh&lt;sup&gt;TM&lt;/sup&gt; ball or a sea-urchin.
The idea is that it would be used in a teleconference, thrown back
and forth across the room from speaker to speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need this at my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has anyone else seen this thing, remember what it was called, or
where they&amp;apos;re selling it?  I can&amp;apos;t seem to find it again in any of
the Wired issues I can find in my apartment and office.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2003 17:21:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/06/throwable-phone/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/06/throwable-phone/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Bad Apple, No Battery</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So, sometime around last November, my iBook started having battery 
problems.  It went from 3 hours of life, down to an hour, and finally
down to about 15 minutes&amp;apos; worth of life.  Being lazy and busy, and 
having my iBook mostly at desks near outlets, I put off taking it into
the shop -- I&amp;apos;d just taken it there to replace the hard drive, and I
didn&amp;apos;t feel like parting with it again.  Stupid, I know.  Lazy, I know.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Well, since then, the problem hasn&amp;apos;t gotten better, and I was just about 
to get off my ass to do something about it when I see this:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macnn.com/news.php?id=18661&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;MacNN: iBook users experience 10.2.4 battery bug&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So after browsing around forums a bit, I learned &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?artnum=14449&amp;amp;SaveKCWindowURL=http%3A%2F%2Fkbase.info.apple.com%2Fcgi-bin%2FWebObjects%2Fkbase.woa%2Fwa%2FSaveKCToHomePage&amp;amp;searchMode=Expert&amp;amp;kbhost=kbase.info.apple.com&amp;amp;showButton=false&amp;amp;randomValue=100&amp;amp;showSurvey=false&amp;amp;sessionID=anonymous%7C165795247&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;how to reset my Power Management Unit&lt;/a&gt;,
did so, and discovered that the battery began to charge again.  I left 
the iBook off and watched the 4 LEDs on the battery gradually light up
over a bit of time while working on my desktop.  Looks like the problem&amp;apos;s
solved for now.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ugh.  I&amp;apos;m glad, at least, that it wasn&amp;apos;t a physically dead battery.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2003 17:56:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/05/bad-apple-no-battery/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/05/bad-apple-no-battery/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Oh, I&#39;m feeling lucky.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog-images/lucky.jpg&quot; target=&quot;_new&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/blog-images/lucky-sm.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Oh yeah, and a giggle for me today:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;.  
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Enter &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;m Feeling Lucky&amp;quot;.  
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Click &amp;quot;I&amp;apos;m Feeling Lucky&amp;quot;.  
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
What do you see?  If you&amp;apos;re seeing what I&amp;apos;m seeing, it&amp;apos;s this very site!  
Now, I&amp;apos;m not sure how long this will last, or whether it means someone at
Google H.Q. loves me, but it&amp;apos;s pretty dern nifty.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://web-graphics.com&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Nathan Steiner of web-graphics.com&lt;/a&gt; for the tip!
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2003 15:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/04/feeling-lucky/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2003/03/04/feeling-lucky/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>