<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: apple - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels and self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/</link>
      <item>
          <title>Freedom to Change Your Mind</title>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I posted a few days ago about &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.lmorchard.com/2012/09/24/freedom-of-from-choice&quot;&gt;freedom of and from choice&lt;/a&gt;, but I think there&amp;#x2019;s something &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthogonality&quot;&gt;orthogonal&lt;/a&gt; to that spectrum: The freedom to change your mind, both figuratively and literally.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2012/09/27/freedom-to-change-your-mind/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2012/09/27/freedom-to-change-your-mind/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Upgrades versus Antiques</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2008 16:07:19 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2008/10/19/upgrades-versus-antiques/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2008/10/19/upgrades-versus-antiques/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Frustrations in using iTunes and iPod to capture podcast listening behavior</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2007 20:13:04 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2007/03/09/frustrations-in-using-itunes-and-ipod-to-capture-podcast-listening-behavior/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2007/03/09/frustrations-in-using-itunes-and-ipod-to-capture-podcast-listening-behavior/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>the iphone will not be your new mobile computer</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 16:01:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2007/01/12/the-iphone-will-not-be-your-new-mobile-computer/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2007/01/12/the-iphone-will-not-be-your-new-mobile-computer/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>macbook pro volume settings are aware of headphone presence</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2006 18:19:52 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2006/11/17/macbook-pro-volume-settings-are-aware-of-headphone-presence/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2006/11/17/macbook-pro-volume-settings-are-aware-of-headphone-presence/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>iPod go thud then click, click, click.</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2005 17:28:40 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2005/10/25/ipod-go-thud-then-click-click-click/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2005/10/25/ipod-go-thud-then-click-click-click/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Could an iPod and AV cable fit in a DVD case?</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2005 18:05:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2005/10/21/could-an-ipod-and-av-cable-fit-in-a-dvd-case/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2005/10/21/could-an-ipod-and-av-cable-fit-in-a-dvd-case/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>No user serviceable fans</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2005 10:54:42 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2005/10/06/no-user-serviceable-fans/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2005/10/06/no-user-serviceable-fans/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>My iPod experience is all about tickling myself.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;apos;ve had an iPod for a little over a week now, and I&amp;apos;ve been working pretty diligently to rate every song I hear and trying to make sure all the metadata is correct.  I&amp;apos;ve even started tinkering with tagging songs using things like &lt;code&gt;:dreamy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:goofy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:energy&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;:calm&lt;/code&gt; in the comments field for use with Smart Playlists.  (Yeah, I know about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.danshockley.com/tunetags.php&quot;&gt;TuneTags&lt;/a&gt;, but the psuedo-XML in song comments bugs me, as does the somewhat buggy behavior of the last version of the program I tried.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this point, I&amp;apos;ve managed to cram about 3400 songs from our CD collection into it.  (So much for the marketing!)  With my efforts so far, a &amp;#x201C;Good Music&amp;#x201D; Smart Playlist selecting for 3-stars and above gives me around 415 songs.  This doesn&amp;apos;t count the songs I&amp;apos;ve rated with 1-star, which get deleted from the iPod periodically.  Also, I&amp;apos;ve yet to get a significant proportion tagged with special comments, so mood-based and concept-based playlists are far off until I get a better tool for letting me quickly and lazily tag songs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, this morning on the way into work I fired up my &amp;#x201C;Good Music&amp;#x201D; playlist on random for the first time, and I was amazed at how good the selection was.  Yes, I rated these songs, so I should know they&amp;apos;re good--but so far, I&amp;apos;ve had all 3400 songs on shuffle and have been alternating between listening and rating, skipping songs I wasn&amp;apos;t in the mood for, and canning songs right off the bat with a 1-star rating.  So up until now, my rotation has been an &lt;em&gt;okay&lt;/em&gt; experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, hearing that mix of consistently high rated songs was an unexpectedly good experience.  What occurred to me as I rounded the last stretch of I-75 into Detroit this morning is that this metadata and these Smart Playlists on shuffle amount to an attempt to tickle myself.  Ever try that?  For the most part, it doesn&amp;apos;t work.  Sure, you know where you&amp;apos;re ticklish--but if it&amp;apos;s your hand trying to do it, you&amp;apos;re expecting it and the tickle doesn&amp;apos;t happen.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;apos;m probably stepping too far into breathless pretentiousness with this, but it makes me want to think further about machine learning and intelligence.  Yeah, Smart Playlists are a very, very rudimentary form of intelligence, but it&amp;apos;s good enough to tickle me with a music mix--which is a very real bit of value added to my life.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much further this tickling-myself metaphor can be taken?  That is: take a machine endowed with information I produced, apply some simple or slightly complex logic with a bit of random shuffle, and feed it back to me to see if it makes me experience it with some novelty.  Someone&amp;apos;s got to already be on top of this as a research project.  That, or it&amp;apos;s an idea obvious or dumb enough only to appeal to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2004 21:18:19 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/10/27/ipodtickles/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/10/27/ipodtickles/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>I&#39;m one of the iPod generation now</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So I finally got myself an iPod, thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://missadroit.livejournal.com&quot;&gt;The Girl&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through various twists of replacement policy and iBook promotional antics, somehow she ended up with two 20GB 4G iPods, both of which she&amp;apos;s been planning to sell off on eBay to end up with some cash and an iPod Mini.  Well, it finally occurred to me this weekend that I needed to buy one of those iPods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I&amp;apos;ve been only been listening to streaming radio at work, since I don&amp;apos;t really have the hard drive space on my PowerBook for music, and loading up the work PC with MP3s is pretty unpalatable.  I miss the days when I had a 40GB library at work, but between company policy where I am now and having lost that whole library in a hard drive crash back then, I&amp;apos;m hesitant to go there again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the iPod.  I was reminded of its presence in The Girl&amp;apos;s office, still boxed up and shrink-wrapped, at a moment when I was thinking about podcasting and thinking about my lack of hard drive space.  So, I gave in and snapped it up.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus far, I&amp;apos;m pretty happy.  Sure, I&amp;apos;d been looking at the larger capacity models that came with a dock and remote, but this one was the right price at the right place and the right time.  I was also lucky that she had an iTrip she was selling that just happened to work satisfactorily for playing MP3s in my car - something that&amp;apos;s been a bit of a quest of mine for years.  While it&amp;apos;s true I do have an in-dash Blaupunkt MP3 CD player in my Ford Focus now, it&amp;apos;s also true that 20GB certainly outweighs 700MB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The few snags I&amp;apos;ve run into so far mostly have to do with the fact that it seems like my desired usage pattern of the iPod isn&amp;apos;t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; supported.  See, I don&amp;apos;t want to have a massive library on my PowerBook, to be synched in part onto my iPod.  I have a library on a file server at home, and I want to use the iPod alternately as a music store away from home for iTunes on my PowerBook and as an MP3 player while I&amp;apos;m driving.  I don&amp;apos;t want any music at all on my PowerBook.  Problem is, though, the iPod isn&amp;apos;t &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; a first-class citizen in iTunes.  Party Shuffle doesn&amp;apos;t work, and I had a few problems with making sure metadata (like ratings and last played date) made it into iTunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yeah, and I wish they&amp;apos;d turn down the wheel sensitivity &lt;strong&gt;way&lt;/strong&gt; down when setting a song&amp;apos;s rating.  At present, it&amp;apos;s just a bare millimeter of a finger&amp;apos;s twitch to leap from 1 to 5 stars.  Might just be me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, for the most part, I&amp;apos;m very happy to have my own music at work again, and the potential of tinkering with smart playlists and podcasts are exciting to me.  That, and the fourth-generation iPod is just an elegant, slick joy to hold.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2004 19:15:49 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/10/19/ipodismine/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/10/19/ipodismine/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>