<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: twitter - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/twitter/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>New blog, a lot like the old blog, but more of it</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years now, I&#39;ve wanted to turn this blog into a place to write Big Serious Entries with fancy layouts and lots of words &amp;amp; images. I thought that would get me somewhere interesting. But, it turns out, that&#39;s a pretty heavy squelch filter on getting things out of my brain and onto the web. I just don&#39;t have the energy or follow-through to come up with Big Serious Entries all that often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I do have is a lot of little things that I could let tumble out of my ADHD brain. I used to do more of that here - but since the advent of Twitter, way back in 2006, I allowed most of that to be shunted over there. And when I finally abandoned Twitter in 2022, that brain spew more fully moved to &lt;a href=&quot;https://masto.hackers.town/@lmorchard&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except, not entirely. Twitter and Mastodon are mostly good for tiny things. Not medium or long things. Or things that start small and grow with further thought throughout a day or a week. My blog could be good at that, though. So, I&#39;m reworking the layout and how I can write entries to better accomodate that and dovetail into my habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the way &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison&lt;/a&gt; run their blogs. They riff throughout the day with notions of various length and format - sometimes as short as a toot and sometimes expanding out into full essays. They&#39;ve both done this for years and years, and they&#39;ve done well at it. So, I&#39;m going to shamelessly steal some of their ideas and plonk them down here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I&#39;m also going to try a few of my own ideas. Like, Simon runs his blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/simonw/simonwillisonblog&quot;&gt;as a Django app&lt;/a&gt; and Dave &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=about&quot;&gt;writes in OPML&lt;/a&gt;. Personally, I like my &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2020/05/24/easy-blog-oven/index.html&quot;&gt;Easy-Blog Oven&lt;/a&gt; and I like writing in Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I don&#39;t like is tediously opening a new Markdown file every time I might have a wild idea, though. That&#39;s a thing that Dave&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.opml.org/&quot;&gt;OPML Editor&lt;/a&gt; had going for it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20061003021452/http://blogs.opml.org/decafbad/&quot;&gt;back when I blogged with it&lt;/a&gt;: You opened one outline for the whole day and just let ideas tumble into it over the hours. (Hmm, I want a screenshot here. I need to figure out how to paste one in.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, my stand-in for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.opml.org/&quot;&gt;OPML Editor&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. In some ways, it&#39;s more cumbersome for outlining than OPML, but it does other things I like. So, I&#39;ve come up with this goofy file format to open just one file per day and compose multiple entries in that file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s markdown, but if I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/content/posts/2025/2025-05-09.md?plain=1#L15&quot;&gt;start a line with ASCII-art scissors (i.e. &lt;code&gt;8&amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/a&gt; then my Easy-Blog Oven &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/lib/posts.js#L140-L156&quot;&gt;will chop that file up&lt;/a&gt; into separate entries. I can also include a bit of JSON in there for post metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No entry in the file is final, things may expand and contract and bud off into new entries over time. I&#39;ll probably let them alone after midnight, though. That might cause some churn in my RSS feeds, so I may eventually set them to a 24-hour delay. I don&#39;t know, I&#39;m still thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I get really ambitious, I&#39;ll rig up some machinery to automatically publish as I write in an Obsidian tab. But, that&#39;s some hackery for the days ahead. For now, I just want to get these changes pushed out into the world before I wander off after something else shiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Edit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/script/publish-posts-from-obsidian.sh&quot;&gt;I wrote a script that runs in a cronjob that pushes my edits from Obsidian to GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. That&#39;s all it really took, just one more sproingy bit atop the Rube Goldberg machine.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 19:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/new-blog-a-lot-like-the-old/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/new-blog-a-lot-like-the-old/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>There are no ushers on Mastodon</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: There are no ushers on Mastodon. There&#39;s no one paid to show you to your seat, no one whose job it is to ease you into comfort and remove friction.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/11/07/no-ushers/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/11/07/no-ushers/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Twitter, or social cowardice as a service</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: Yeah, yeah, I&#39;m navel gazing about Twitter over here.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/28/twitter/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/28/twitter/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Random thoughts for 2014 Oct 23</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: This is a bunch of stuff I just randomly collected throughout the day.
Look here for a bit of explanation. I may or may not do this again.
I&#39;m experimenting and entertaining myself.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2014/10/23/thoughts/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2014/10/23/thoughts/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Toot = Tiny Outburst of Text</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;I&#39;ve been toying with something Twitterish lately, and thought I needed a
different word to describe the central social object. So, I started using
toot, which means &quot;tiny outburst of text&quot;. Of course, I started by
making fart jokes to myself before that expansion appeared in my head. But, I
think it&#39;s fun.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2014 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2014/10/23/toot-toot/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2014/10/23/toot-toot/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Separating publishing from hosting on the web</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Social media like Twitter and Facebook combine web publishing and hosting. You can’t run different software, and you can’t move your stuff. So, if you’re unhappy, your choices are a) deal with it or b) abandon your stuff and your friends. Those are pretty rough options.
But, what if you could move your stuff? And what if you could switch apps?&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2014/10/09/separating-publishing-from-hosting-on-the-web/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2014/10/09/separating-publishing-from-hosting-on-the-web/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Microblogging like it&amp;#8217;s 2002</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Every year or so, I (re)join the ranks of hackers who decide they’d like to try building a microblogging tool. It’s sometimes after Twitter or Facebook does something cruddy to remind me that I’m the product. Sometimes, it’s when jerks have the run of the place and no one can do anything about it. Often these things are highly correlated.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2014/10/08/microblogging-like-its-2002/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2014/10/08/microblogging-like-its-2002/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Half-formed thoughts about Twitter, social silos, web APIs, and mashups</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: Turns out, the way to derive value from web APIs is to let your community run off and do free research and development. Harvest the results, and profit. We were never promised participation, but it felt like it was a 2-way street. Silly us. Where do we go from here?&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2012 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2012/07/12/half-formed-thoughts-about-twitter/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2012/07/12/half-formed-thoughts-about-twitter/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>I (used to) like rev=&quot;canonical&quot;</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Update 4/14: So, I liked rev=&quot;canonical&quot;, but I like the notion of pages offering sets of alternative URLs better.  There are enough cracks in the case for rev=&quot;canonical&quot; to stop caring about it and instead focus on the notion behind it.  However it&#39;s expressed—is it rel=&quot;shortlink&quot; now?—the final remaining things I&#39;d like to see are:

An more generalized scope for alternate URL choices asserted by publishers, not just URL shortening.  Other criteria beyond character length include ease of entry on mobile devices (eg. short, but also simple, maybe mostly numeric), ease of verbal mention (eg. billboards, postcards, etc).

HTTP headers are great where available—hooray for HEAD—but it still needs to be in the page for publishers who can&#39;t set custom headers.

Microformats are great, but I&#39;d rather not parse a whole page to the footer to lift out the desired URLs.

Don&#39;t panic. Have fun.


And with that, I&#39;m going to try coming up with other things to write about so this blog doesn&#39;t stay dormant.  The rest of this entry remains unedited below...&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2009 05:05:50 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/04/13/i-like-revcanonical/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2009/04/13/i-like-revcanonical/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>using Twitterrific with identi.ca</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2008 21:56:18 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2008/07/18/using-twitterrific-with-identica/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2008/07/18/using-twitterrific-with-identica/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Queue everything and delight everyone</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2008 19:17:18 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2008/07/04/queue-everything-and-delight-everyone/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2008/07/04/queue-everything-and-delight-everyone/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Why I&#39;m playing with Laconica</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 20:32:40 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2008/07/03/why-im-playing-with-laconica/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2008/07/03/why-im-playing-with-laconica/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Getting Laconica up and running</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Update, 30 Sep 2008: 
You don&#39;t want to follow the directions on this page—instead, leave this page and read this:  
http://laconi.ca/darcs/README
At one point, very early on in Laconica-time, this blog post offered useful information on getting Laconica up and running.  But since then, my time has taken me away from playing with Laconica and thus this guide has fallen far behind.  Hopefully soon I&#39;ll get back around to Laconica hacking, but not today.
I&#39;m leaving the original text of this post here for posterity, but this is no longer current and following this guide will do more harm than good in confusing you about Laconica installation!
Again, to learn about getting Laconica up and running, leave this page and read this:
http://laconi.ca/darcs/README
The latest mini-sensations to arrive through my firehoses are identi.ca, a Twitter-clone / microblogging site, and the Open Source software Laconica, which powers the aforementioned site.
Having started and neglected two Twitter cloning attempts of my own, Cuckoo and OpenInterocitor, seeing someone else carry the torch with any modicum of momentum is attractive to me.  So, I spent a little bit last night getting the code running on my own servers, and managed to do it twice:

decafbad.com/laconica
lmorchard.com/laconica

See, the interesting thing promised by Laconica—and something I wanted in my own clones—is the ability to federate instances of the software.  That is, users on one Laconica-based site should be able to subscribe to the updates from users on another site, by way of the OpenMicroblogging specification.  Although federation isn&#39;t a silver bullet to a web-scale Twitter clone, I do think it&#39;s one of the most important bootstrap steps—but that&#39;s another blog post entirely.
Thus, since I&#39;d like to see you run a Laconica site (or something like it) for mine to talk to, I figured I&#39;d document how I got the thing running.  My server is running Ubuntu Gutsy, so your mileage may vary.  This is a long one, so check out the how-to after the jump...&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jul 2008 19:21:35 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2008/07/03/getting-laconica-up-and-running/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2008/07/03/getting-laconica-up-and-running/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Outsourcing creativity via APIs</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2007 18:17:21 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2007/11/01/outsourcing-creativity-via-apis/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2007/11/01/outsourcing-creativity-via-apis/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Twitter&#39;s Mojo Bubble</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 02:36:55 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2007/10/17/twitters-mojo-bubble/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2007/10/17/twitters-mojo-bubble/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>