<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: miscellanea - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/miscellanea/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-20</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/commit/954919050fca61d04d6e89beec96b0ea374ba74d&quot;&gt;Added support for a &lt;code&gt;draft: true&lt;/code&gt; flag on entries here&lt;/a&gt;, which should at least help me keep half-broken things from deploying mid-rant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now I just have to make sure to use that flag right so I &lt;em&gt;still&lt;/em&gt; don&#39;t include half-broken things here 😅&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I should figure out a decent way for showing really long strings here, like the path names in that cloud saves post today 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How the hell do I remember things like &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://monkeybagel.com/pumas.html&quot;&gt;Pumas on Hoverbikes&lt;/a&gt; is at monkeybagel.com&quot; but I have to remind myself to eat lunch as a separate step from making lunch?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-19</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.portlandmercury.com/photo/2025/05/19/47791648/log-lady-look-alike-contest-photos-shes-got-the-look-and-the-log&quot;&gt;Log Lady Look-Alike Contest Photos&lt;/a&gt;: She’s Got the Look (and the Log)&quot; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I love this city.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interesting bugs here in my Rube Goldberg blogging machine involving Syncthing and Obsidian, where sync conflicts become clashing ghost entries 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I should tweak support for a &lt;code&gt;draft&lt;/code&gt; flag here, so that posts that I&#39;m still editing don&#39;t get published automatically. This flow is almost &lt;em&gt;too&lt;/em&gt; frictionless, at this point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been using Obsidian for about 5 years now for my daily notes. I&#39;ve been tempted to take another swing at writing my own notebook, because I barely use any of Obsidian&#39;s fancier features. I mainly like that&#39;s it&#39;s a good cross-platform Markdown editor with a few plugins that I&#39;ve settled on for regular use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a vague notion to make a USB or wifi interface for an old Atari Video Touch Pad. Could use it as a Stream Deck (if I ever stream again) and / or hook it up to Home Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/miscellanea/attachments/2025-05-19-video-touch-pad.png&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need to find a better way to insert images like this 😅&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-18</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I made lentil stew and roasted coffee. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also cooked some dried pinto beans in the Instant Pot for dinners this week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Played a little Clair Obscur: Expedition 33 and DOOM: The Dark Ages.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Lampmaster is a jerk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beating a boss demon at tennis is fun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wanted to work on some tinkering projects but couldn’t quite find the motivation. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/18/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/18/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-17</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Today was Eurovision day, and not much else got done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/17/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/17/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-16</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I listen to podcasts at between 1.8x - 2.5x, depending on the day&#39;s mental weather. That means, when I&#39;ve met a podcaster I listen to, they sound drugged or drunk to me.&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ve had folks tell me this sounds stressful. But, I get distracted in the gaps and my mind wanders. Easier for me to follow rapid word dumps. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is not a flex, this is a coping strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The new Peter Murphy album, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://petermurphy.bandcamp.com/album/silver-shade&quot;&gt;Silver Shade&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, sure is Peter Murphy. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t hate this at all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m really digging the collabs he did here, teaming up with folks like Boy George, Trent Reznor, and Justin Chancellor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hey, you, service provider on the web that I pay for: I am annoyed that I&#39;m constantly signed out when I come to visit. You don&#39;t remember me, and you are constantly trying to call-to-action and dark-pattern me into your growth hacks when I already have an account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-15</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s weird working at a company that was once all about open source and now... isn&#39;t so much. There are things I&#39;m doing that I don&#39;t think I should be talking about. And yet, I want to talk about them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But, also, I think we &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be talking about them. And also making it all open source. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Been checking out are.na - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.are.na/les-orchard/arena-babysteps-for-me&quot;&gt;it seems like Pinterest for horn-rimmed-glasses aesthetics&lt;/a&gt;. That&#39;s not meant as an insult, mind you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/15/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/15/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-14</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks like I ended up with an AI-heavy posting day, today. I think I broke the seal yesterday. I&#39;ll probably post about other things in the near future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve been meaning to write something up about the Rube Goldberg machine that runs this blog now. Writing this bullet point to irritate myself to do it soon, maybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I bought a &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.boox.com/collections/all/products/tabultrac&quot;&gt;BOOX Tab Ultra C&lt;/a&gt; almost 2 years ago. I use it almost daily for writing notes and journal entries. It&#39;s also been pretty great for reading comics in color. Two things I really don&#39;t like about it:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s got a camera bump on the back, so it doesn&#39;t sit flat on a table without a case on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The case that came with it is disintegrating into dust.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, I&#39;m considering trying to design my own replacement case - or at least a layer to stick on the back to even out the camera bump. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hoping to use &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/3dprinting&quot;&gt;#3dprinting&lt;/a&gt; and embed magnets that line up with the device&#39;s own internal case mounting magnets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But, like, why put a camera bump on a tablet?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why design a camera bump into anything, really? Just make the device thicker and fill the rest of the space with battery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to stop before I go on a cranky rant about my intense disgust for camera bumps and notches and other failures of design from Apple that the rest of the industry have just copied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Really, I&#39;m just caremad, because I used to be a huge fan of Apple - had the sticker on my car and everything. But, they have &lt;em&gt;betrayed&lt;/em&gt; me over the years with stuff that seems to matter only to me. 🤷‍♂️&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just noticed that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jpmonette/feed&quot;&gt;jpmonette/feed&lt;/a&gt; - a node.js module for generating RSS, Atom, and JSON feeds - got &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jpmonette/feed/releases/tag/5.0.1&quot;&gt;a new release&lt;/a&gt; a couple days ago after about 4 years of dormancy. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks like they may have possibly fixed a few of the issues I had with it, when last I tried using it. 🤔&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I need to work links &amp;amp; bookmarks into this new blog in a better way. Like these:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ign.com/articles/nintendo-revises-user-agreement-and-if-you-break-it-nintendo-reserves-the-right-to-brick-your-switch&quot;&gt;Nintendo Revises User Agreement, And If You Break It, Nintendo Reserves The Right to Brick Your Switch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, that just makes me want to jailbreak my Switch even more and then never again connect it to the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mjtsai.com/blog/2025/05/14/critical-warning-for-external-purchases-in-app-store/&quot;&gt;Critical Warning for External Purchases in App Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yeah, it&#39;s stuff like this that&#39;s got me fixed on switching back to Android with my next phone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve only bought one iPhone and I&#39;ve never felt the Courage or the Magic the whole time I&#39;ve used it. It&#39;s never felt like &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; phone, always felt like a loaner with a breathalyzer and a bill acceptor slot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That said, the thing is physically a tank and will probably survive intact to annoy me for a few more years before I can justify the replacement cost.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-13</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m in a weird place with this current AI wave in the tech industry. Drafting up some thoughts, maybe they&#39;ll turn into a post? I started just riffing here, but the riffing kept expanding, so I think I should give it some time to cook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And, indeed, I went ahead and posted a separate entry on &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/13/thinking-about-llms/&quot;&gt;what I&#39;m thinking about AI and LLMs&lt;/a&gt;! Maybe too many words that no one will read, but I wanted to get it out of my head for future noodling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None of what I wrote there about AI &amp;amp; LLMs is particularly novel - in fact, the post is probably about 2 years behind the times. It&#39;s just that I think I needed to get it written down to get my own head straight. And maybe to refer to it later?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also, this AI stuff &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-features/chatgpt-hypen-em-dash-ai-writing-1235314945/&quot;&gt;makes me self-conscious about my love of em dashes&lt;/a&gt;, which predates the popularity of LLMs for generating text? This shell command says I&#39;ve used at least 172 of them around here: &lt;code&gt;find . -type f -name &quot;*.md&quot; -print0 | xargs -0 grep -o &quot;—&quot; 2&amp;gt;/dev/null | wc -l&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can tell you exactly where I picked up my love of em dashes: Ayn Rand&#39;s &lt;em&gt;Atlas Shrugged&lt;/em&gt;, sophomore year of high school. It was a conscious decision to adopt them. My opinions on that book have changed, but my use of em dashes remains insufferable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/macieklamberski/feedsmith&quot;&gt;feedsmith&lt;/a&gt;: &quot;Robust and fast parser and generator for RSS, Atom, JSON Feed, and RDF feeds, with support for Podcast, iTunes, Dublin Core, and OPML files.&quot;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well, that&#39;s relevant to my interests. Might be worth replacing my half-baked RSS template on this blog with that, at least.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/13/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/13/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-12</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m probably going to keep &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/metablogging&quot;&gt;#metablogging&lt;/a&gt; here for awhile, as I work out the kinks with the revised system. I do have other projects &amp;amp; pursuits that I want to start rambling about here. Also kind of hoping that having an easy channel for show &amp;amp; tell will encourage me a bit to actually spend time on them and document a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/tofjadesign/pen/LEExbqr&quot;&gt;Carousel + Lightbox + Glow demo on CodePen&lt;/a&gt; is too fancy for my blog, but it&#39;s really nifty. Maybe I need to just code my own up from scratch and I&#39;m overthinking this lightGallery thing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flipboard.video/w/p7cECAUgThGrfQo9Cqvb8r&quot;&gt;Molly White argues&lt;/a&gt; it’s time to reclaim the web: move your work to spaces you control, support open tools, and help build a web that serves people, not profit.&quot; She&#39;s been banging this drum for a long while, and she&#39;s right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Considering integrating responses from Bluesky and Mastodon here and posting entries from here to there. Those aren&#39;t exactly space I control, but they&#39;re relatively open tools, and I can archive things here. Also, I think it&#39;d be meeting folks more where they are. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I thought maybe requiring a Bluesky or Mastodon account to respond here would be a pain in the butt. But, I gave my Disqus widget a fresh try over the weekend and it&#39;s not exactly pleasant these days. I guess I can see why a lot of blogs just punt and link out to Hacker News threads for their comments - but I am not at all a fan of the orange site, myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I post the occasional toot &lt;a href=&quot;https://masto.hackers.town/@lmorchard&quot;&gt;on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; and I post links to my half-baked &lt;a href=&quot;https://pebbl.ing/u/lmorchard?&quot;&gt;Pebbling Club profile&lt;/a&gt;. Tempted to do the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/PESOS&quot;&gt;PESOS&lt;/a&gt; thing and copy those into daily entries over here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushed out some RSS feed fixes:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;images should be properly linked with absolute URLs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posts with timestamps in the future should be omitted (i.e. like my daily miscellanea that&#39;s not &quot;final&quot; until just before midnight)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;links to feeds from tag pages should work now, both as visible in-page links and in the head of the page for auto-discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/12/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/12/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-11</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A thing I have realized: filling all the vents of my Crocs with &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/3dprinting&quot;&gt;#3dprinting&lt;/a&gt; nonsense makes them a bit too warm to wear. 🥵&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Man, this image gallery component I lashed together just isn&#39;t behaving right. Image sizes are all over the place. I&#39;ve seen this particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lightgalleryjs.com/&quot;&gt;lightGallery&lt;/a&gt; widget work well on other sites, so I&#39;m pretty sure it&#39;s something I&#39;m doing that&#39;s disagreeable. Not sure how to fix it, tempted to switch to something else entirely - on the hypothesis that picking it up and shaking it like an Etch-a-Sketch may result in a better outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t often get feedback &amp;amp; comments via the Disqus comments widget I&#39;ve embedded at the end of every post. That could be because a) folks aren&#39;t reading my blog or b) Disqus is too annoying to use these days. Probably both. I can work on the former by posting better stuff more often and sharing it around. As for the latter, I dunno. I don&#39;t want to open a spam honeypot, but I think I need to offer some simpler way to at least give a lil thumbs up as a response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m tempted to hook this stuff up to accounts on the Fediverse and Bluesky, try to get feedback from those channels. That could be worth hacking on for a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just like my RSS feeds, though, I don&#39;t want to generate churn on those networks as I iterate on posts over the course of a day. I&#39;m still thinking through how to balance editing flexibility with publishing stable things when word goes out to the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe these miscellanea posts get a 24-hour delay, because they&#39;re where I expect to futz around the most throughout a day. If you happen to read them, you&#39;re an early alpha reader I guess. Other posts that bud off from this daily scratchpad will likely be stable enough to send out immediately. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess that means I need to implement a defer-until feature in my Easy-Blog Oven 🤔 Maybe I can set the post date into the future and implement logic such that no post shows up in a feed or gets sent out to another service until after that time? Too clever?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hmm, I sent out &quot;Word to your mother&quot; on &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/meshtastic&quot;&gt;#meshtastic&lt;/a&gt; and someone replied. Maybe my messages &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; getting out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m starting to look into getting a doorbell camera that works with Home Assistant. I&#39;ve seen a few recommendations for PoE widgets. Like this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/REOLINK-Doorbell-Security-Diagonal-Detection/dp/B0B7S1HMPC&quot;&gt;REOLINK Video Doorbell PoE Camera&lt;/a&gt;. That seems troublesome, unless I&#39;m careful to stick it on its own VLAN / DMZ / whatever? Like I&#39;m imagining someone could walk up at 4am, unhook it, plug in a laptop, and have fun on my network?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/11/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/11/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-10</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nice day in Portland! Took the car to get serviced, walked for a sammich at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makeitsnappys.com/&quot;&gt;Snappy&#39;s&lt;/a&gt;, then walked over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://totlgames.com/&quot;&gt;TOTL Games&lt;/a&gt; to see what&#39;s what there. Bought myself an Xbox 360 HDD expansion. Someday, I&#39;ll get around to hacking that thing and loading it up with all the Rock Band ever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time for a bike ride! I&#39;ve got a 15 mile route in Portland that I take around &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Willamette_River&quot;&gt;the Willamette River&lt;/a&gt; just about any weekend when the weather&#39;s pleasant. Not all that long, but rather pleasant, and gets me out of the house.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m still playing with &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/meshtastic&quot;&gt;#meshtastic&lt;/a&gt; a little, but I think the two devices I have are really only receiving and not managing to transmit to anyone. At least, no one&#39;s ever really responded to any of my &quot;ping&quot; messages. Not sure whether I want to go further down the rabbit hole and buy any more robust antennas and the associated paraphernalia that goes along with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive CSS is hard, let’s go shopping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/10/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/10/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-09</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Been watching &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lCuoUSDBVa&quot;&gt;Resurrecting Sinistar: A Cyber-Archaeology Documentary&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, which has been great. Played Sinistar last at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.retrogamingexpo.com/&quot;&gt;Portland Retro Gaming Expo&lt;/a&gt; in October and was digging the heck out of it. They squeezed so much out of that 8-bit processor - I guess it had a multitasking system that could handle like over 100 game entities? In 1983?! The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/synamaxmusic/sinistar&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; has actually surfaced, so you can see how they did it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was starting to do &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/tag/weeknotes/&quot;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, this month. But, this week, I decided what I really wanted to do was just blog more. So, that got me started hacking on my blog software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m just going to deploy these changes to the blog. Some things might be broken, but I&#39;ll fix them as I go. I want to start actually using the thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking I&#39;ll start each day off with a miscellanea entry like this one and fill it full of little bullets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe I&#39;ll start spawning little entries for bookmarks and quotes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the main things I&#39;m thinking about with all this hackery and ASCII art is whether I&#39;ll be able to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; with all these files in 10 - 20 years&#39; time. Granted, I&#39;ll be pushing 70, so maybe I won&#39;t care by then?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But, the writing is the important part to me. I could write a whole new blog publisher from scratch and still read all the file formats. I&#39;ve done that a couple times now and I can still handle stuff I wrote back in 2002. I think that&#39;s pretty cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And here I am, attempting to blog from Obsidian on my phone? Is this the future?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next thing I need to work out is how to upload and display images via Obsidian on my phone. I think it&#39;s very doable, just a few more bits of Rube Goldberg crud to slot into place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve been asked to write up how this whole mess works - that might be a thing I&#39;ll do this weekend in greater detail. It really is an accumulation of random little parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dang, now that I have this easy channel from my brain into my blog, I&#39;m feeling like a motormouth. I&#39;ll probably settle down, soon enough. I&#39;m always giddy with a new toy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>