<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: bluesky - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/bluesky/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-12</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m probably going to keep &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/metablogging&quot;&gt;#metablogging&lt;/a&gt; here for awhile, as I work out the kinks with the revised system. I do have other projects &amp;amp; pursuits that I want to start rambling about here. Also kind of hoping that having an easy channel for show &amp;amp; tell will encourage me a bit to actually spend time on them and document a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/tofjadesign/pen/LEExbqr&quot;&gt;Carousel + Lightbox + Glow demo on CodePen&lt;/a&gt; is too fancy for my blog, but it&#39;s really nifty. Maybe I need to just code my own up from scratch and I&#39;m overthinking this lightGallery thing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flipboard.video/w/p7cECAUgThGrfQo9Cqvb8r&quot;&gt;Molly White argues&lt;/a&gt; it’s time to reclaim the web: move your work to spaces you control, support open tools, and help build a web that serves people, not profit.&quot; She&#39;s been banging this drum for a long while, and she&#39;s right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Considering integrating responses from Bluesky and Mastodon here and posting entries from here to there. Those aren&#39;t exactly space I control, but they&#39;re relatively open tools, and I can archive things here. Also, I think it&#39;d be meeting folks more where they are. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I thought maybe requiring a Bluesky or Mastodon account to respond here would be a pain in the butt. But, I gave my Disqus widget a fresh try over the weekend and it&#39;s not exactly pleasant these days. I guess I can see why a lot of blogs just punt and link out to Hacker News threads for their comments - but I am not at all a fan of the orange site, myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I post the occasional toot &lt;a href=&quot;https://masto.hackers.town/@lmorchard&quot;&gt;on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; and I post links to my half-baked &lt;a href=&quot;https://pebbl.ing/u/lmorchard?&quot;&gt;Pebbling Club profile&lt;/a&gt;. Tempted to do the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/PESOS&quot;&gt;PESOS&lt;/a&gt; thing and copy those into daily entries over here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushed out some RSS feed fixes:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;images should be properly linked with absolute URLs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posts with timestamps in the future should be omitted (i.e. like my daily miscellanea that&#39;s not &quot;final&quot; until just before midnight)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;links to feeds from tag pages should work now, both as visible in-page links and in the head of the page for auto-discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/12/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/12/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>