<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels and self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com</link>
      <item>
          <title>LiveJournal largely ignored, but why?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Caught this snippet on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tweney.com/writing.php?display=322&quot;&gt;tweeney.com&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hyperorg.com/blogger/index.html#85393106&quot;&gt;JOHO&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;quot;...LiveJournal.com (which most weblog news stories overlook for some reason) boasts more than 650,000 [users]...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why does everyone seem to ignore &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/LiveJournal&quot;&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt;?  It&amp;apos;s very, very, very rare that I see a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/LiveJournaller&quot;&gt;LiveJournaller&lt;/a&gt;&amp;apos;s posts linked into the Blogosphere at large.  Granted, I know that the median user was a 15 year old female who complains about Mom and her boyfriend, when last I checked.  But, as the adage goes: 90% of anything is crap.  There are, nevertheless, a good number of worthwhile streams of narrative in that space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, I don&amp;apos;t see many of the people behind LJ stepping out and making noise in the Outer Blogosphere either.  I think many of them are just plain busy keeping the site afloat, or having lives, and LJ is world enough for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But 650,000 users... that&amp;apos;s a lot.  More than Radio and rivalling Blogger.com.  Is there a real qualitative difference in writing between the groups?  I would still imagine there&amp;apos;s a lot of crap to be found via Blogger.com.  I&amp;apos;m not sure about Radio, though, since I get the impression that the 15 year olds have yet to flood into the userbase and its following seems more tilted toward professionals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as for the software &amp;amp; service itself...  As far as I can see, LJ is one of the easiest paths out there to starting a weblog/journal online.  And it was one of the first sites I ever encountered that had a desktop-based client app for posting to it.  And, though not prominently placed, they have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feeds for every single journal on the site.  They&amp;apos;re even working &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; aggregation features into the place by gatewaying external &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feeds in as special LJ users to be added like any other LJ &amp;quot;friend&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, to me, LJ sounds like a top competitor to every other blog/news aggregation product or service out there - yet I rarely hear about it.  Hrm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone have a theory why?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2002 17:40:33 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/30/ooobfb/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/30/ooobfb/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Interop:  Movable Type IM-based pub/sub?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Even more gas is flowing - from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jacobsen.no/anders/blog/&quot;&gt;andersja&lt;/a&gt;&amp;apos;s blog: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jacobsen.no/anders/blog/archives/2002/08/30/movable_type_notifications_to_instant_messenger.html&quot;&gt;Movable Type notifications to Instant Messenger?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really want to see this, and I want to see news aggregators exploit this - why poll a feed once an hour when you can just have the feed tell you to come &amp;apos;n get it?  Basic publish/subscribe model.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the advantage Radio has over MT in this regard is this:  Radio is a persistently running app/server/daemon thing.  MT is a collection of scripts that does nothing until asked to run.  Radio can connect to IM and stay connected.  Something like MT would need to login to an IM service each and every time it wanted to ping.  Maybe that&amp;apos;s not such a big deal, really.  I also have a hunch that there would be some difficulties with web hosting sites who don&amp;apos;t really want customers emitting IMs from their CGIs.  Maybe not a big deal either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just seems like an impedance mismatch, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I&amp;apos;d like to see is something like this:  An XML-RPC/SOAP &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; IM gateway.  And then, eventually, I&amp;apos;d like to see a decentrallized P2P network with XML-RPC/SOAP entry points that can smoothly replace centralized resources that have XML-RPC/SOAP entry points, maybe using IM networks as one possible rendevous point.  (Just remembered this project: &lt;a href=&quot;http://relativity.yi.org/jxta-bridge/&quot;&gt;JXTA Bridge&lt;/a&gt;.  Mental note - play with JXTA again and poke at SOAP some more.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2002 17:24:23 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/30/ooobfa/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/30/ooobfa/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Outlining + IM = On Fire</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Dave writes, &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/backissues/2002/08/29#When:6:18:09PM&quot;&gt;I have my instant outliner going again.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kick.  Ass.  Now we&amp;apos;re cooking with gas.  I think I need to get a fresh install of Radio going on this iBook again, especially since it seems renice works now and can tame the CPU hungry beast to managable levels.  I was kinda waiting to see if/when the people hacking with IM in Radio would close this loop.  Now I want to see what this can do to news aggregation, pub/sub, change notification, etc and more.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2002 08:30:34 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/30/ooobfo/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/30/ooobfo/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Would the real RSS please stand up?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0101679/2002/08/27.html#a766&quot;&gt;Sam Ruby responds&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/whyRss10NamedRss&quot;&gt;Dave&amp;apos;s question&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;I am not a stakeholder in this naming issue, nor can I claim based on personal experience that any of the above references are authoritative, but based on these references alone, it seems to me that one could ask the converse to both of these questions: i.e, why is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; 0.91 called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;, and why did the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; 0.91 branch use &lt;code&gt;&lt;rss&gt;&lt;/rss&gt;&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;[rdf:rdf]&lt;/code&gt;?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;This is basically what I&amp;apos;d started writing as a response the other night, but I lost it in a browser crash.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I browsed around a bit, revisited some old links I&amp;apos;d followed when first I started hacking with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; and frustratedly discovered the format fork.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://backend.userland.com/stories/rss091&quot;&gt;As Dave tells it&lt;/a&gt;, his adoption of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; started in cooperation with Netscape, and the later resulted in his continued support and development after Netscape had wandered away from it and shed the developers responsible.  So from his seat I would think that it looks like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; was abandoned in his lap and thus he felt free to continue on shaping it toward his own ends, namely those of simplicity and real dirt-under-the-nails use versus further design and planning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, later &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; 1.0 comes into the picture.  About this point in history I&amp;apos;m fuzzy.  Most accounts and articles I see do not mention how v1.0 came about and who birthed it.  Most of what I&amp;apos;ve ready just basically says, &amp;quot;And then there was v1.0&amp;quot;  But who said so and when and why?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That 1.0 has more in common with the v0.9 roots than any of Dave&amp;apos;s v0.9x series is clear, so maybe in this respect one could say that this naturally lends v1.0 a &amp;quot;natural&amp;quot; claim on the name by virtue of bloodline and original intent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, one could also say that Dave&amp;apos;s v0.9x series has a claim on the name due to virtue of having actually been in active development directly after the original v0.9.  Call this a claim by virtue of squatting rights?  By virtue of principles of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.libertyforall.net/2002/archive/do-ocracy.html&quot;&gt;Do-ocracy&lt;/a&gt;, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0101679/2002/05/07.html#a454&quot;&gt;Sam wrote about Apache&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then, on another set of hands belonging to another body altogether, why did Dave keep the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; name if he was so radically changing the nature of the format by ditching &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt;?  (But the history confuses me - I seem to remember that change started when it was still in the hands of Netscape.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where does that leave things?  Ugh.  Seems like Dave&amp;apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; should be so because he kept the torch burning in the Dark Times.  But it seems like the Other &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; should be so because it&amp;apos;s the heir to the original throne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then again, I could have the whole history mixed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I say, everybody get up!  I&amp;apos;ll start the music, you all run around, and pick new format names before I hit stop on the CD player.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2002 23:11:47 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/29/ooobei/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/29/ooobei/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>&quot;...ideas are fucking worthless.&quot;</title>
          <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;...that&amp;apos;s what&amp;apos;s got me so bothered about people musing in their weblogs about projects they&amp;apos;d like to do. Stop talking about it an just build it. Don&amp;apos;t make it too complicated. Don&amp;apos;t spend so much time planning on events that will never happen. Programmers, good programmers, are known for over-engineering to save time later down the road. The problem is that you can over-engineer yourself out of wanting to do the site...&lt;/i&gt; [Andre Torrez, &lt;a href=&quot;http://torrez.org/archives/000300.php&quot;&gt;Even You Can Do It&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/blockquote&gt;Just found this post today, via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oblomovka.com/&quot;&gt;Danny O&amp;apos;Brien&lt;/a&gt;.  This is why I threw this site together, and why I have a link to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/ReleaseEarlyReleaseOften&quot;&gt;ReleaseEarlyReleaseOften&lt;/a&gt; on the front page.  
&lt;p&gt;Before this, I would spend years working on something in silence, only to have it fall over on top of me and end with me never wanting to touch it again.  For almost 2 years, I was working on a &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/projects/iaido&quot;&gt;Zope replacement in Perl called Iaido&lt;/a&gt; before I finally created a &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/SourceForge?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; project for it and invited some people in to play.  By then, I was already disgusted with my ugly code, wanted to scrap it and restart, but wasn&amp;apos;t nearly enthusiastic enough to do that.  And by then, there was just too much code - and yet too little documentation - for anyone I invited in to really dive in and muck about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And &lt;strong&gt;this&lt;/strong&gt; project was to be the core of a community site for coders, web designers, and general all around mad scientists.  It would be named &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/NinjaCode?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;NinjaCode&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ninjacode.com&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;http://www.ninjacode.com&lt;/a&gt;.  Well, you can see, the community never got off the ground, and I don&amp;apos;t even have a hold on the domain anymore.  It coulda been a contenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you can see now, on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/Projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; page, that I&amp;apos;ve been gradually working up and spinning out little hacks and widgets.  Eventually, they combine into bigger widgets, like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MTXmlRpcFilterPlugin&quot;&gt;MTXmlRpcFilterPlugin&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;apos;m thinking that this is the way to go.  And, even if/when I do get a grandiose idea, I need to start off releasing the widgets early and show the build up process here in this weblog.  Then, there&amp;apos;s some documentation from the start and maybe even some enthusiastic co-conspirators from the start.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2002 22:11:12 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/26/ooobeh/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/26/ooobeh/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>AmphetaOutlines fix download page fixed</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;D&amp;apos;oh.  Just realized that the download link for the fixed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaOutlines&quot;&gt;AmphetaOutlines&lt;/a&gt; was at the bottom of the page, so I was puzzled that I kept getting emails about it doing the same broken things.  I seem to be missing many things lately.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the correct download is here:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/pub/Main/FilterData/AmphetaOutlines-20020822.tar.gz&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;AmphetaOutlines-20020822.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;should&lt;/strong&gt; include the corrected &amp;quot;URL=&amp;quot; redirect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2002 21:32:33 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/25/ooobeg/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/25/ooobeg/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Comments rise from the ashes</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, that sucked.  I managed to get an all but complete dump of my &lt;code&gt;comments.db&lt;/code&gt; file with &lt;code&gt;db_dump&lt;/code&gt; on my server, but then nothing would parse or load that file after that.  Banged around with it for awhile until I finally realized how to parse the dump file myself with a perl one-liner and rebuilt the comments DBM file that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately after that, I migrated everything to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MySQL&quot;&gt;MySQL&lt;/a&gt;.  Not a silver bullet, but it seems a better idea than relying on those DBM files.  They seemed neat &amp;amp; clever at first - but now that I have a bit invested here, they&amp;apos;re an annoyance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I managed to recover the last few comments I got while things went wonky, but if I happened to miss one of yours, I&amp;apos;m sorry.  I&amp;apos;m glad I recovered the comments, though, because I tend to think that comments left here are often more valuable than whatever dross I may have spewed in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2002 06:55:33 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/23/ooobef/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/23/ooobef/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Dead comments, they keep calling me</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Grr again.  As a few of you have told me in email, and as I noticed toward the end of yesterday, my comments feature here is dead.  Seems that as the disk filled up on this server, someone tried leaving a comment, and as Murphy came into play, the comments DB file got corrupted.  The odd thing, and fortunate thing for me anyway, is that I&amp;apos;m still getting the comments emailled to me.  So if/when I get this DB file recovered, or if I wipe it and start over (not happy about that option), I might try re-posting the comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got some good pointers on some hosting options and may be checking out one or another of them soon.  Also looks like there are still issues with my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaOutlines&quot;&gt;AmphetaOutlines&lt;/a&gt;, even after a re-release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2002 15:10:01 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/23/ooobee/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/23/ooobee/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>A warning about MTXmlRpcFilterPlugin use</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A few words of warning, which should be pretty obvious, with regard to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MTXmlRpcFilterPlugin&quot;&gt;MTXmlRpcFilterPlugin&lt;/a&gt; use:  Every appearance of the tag makes a separate web service call.  This could be painful if you stick it in your individual archive item template, and then rebuild your site.  (ie. at least one hit on the filter service for each item in your weblog)  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2002 22:37:02 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/22/ooobed/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/22/ooobed/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>AmphetaOutline fix.  No, really.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ack!  I just realized, even though it took two emails make the light go on, that my tarball of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaOutlines&quot;&gt;AmphetaOutlines&lt;/a&gt; for download in the wiki has still had the broken click-count page bundled for the last month or so.  For some reason I thought that I&amp;apos;d fixed that and re-uploaded the tarball, but no!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So: It&amp;apos;s there now, hopefully this is a fix for any of you who tried it and saw the insane refresh loop happen with you clicked on a news item.  Hop on over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaOutlines&quot;&gt;AmphetaOutlines&lt;/a&gt; and grab yourself a new copy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next...  I screw around with Bayesian filters as applied to incoming news items, categories of interest, and alert levels.  Maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2002 22:26:25 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/22/ooobec/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/22/ooobec/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Of hosting woes and hippy nerd commune servers</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Grr, shame on me for getting cheap hosting again.  For the most part, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phpwebhosting.com&quot;&gt;PHPWebHosting&lt;/a&gt; has been just fine - they give me SSH access to a shell, about 120MB of space, a few &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MySQL&quot;&gt;MySQL&lt;/a&gt; databases, and generally leave me alone for US$10 per month.  But at this point, the leaving me alone bit isn&amp;apos;t working out so well, since the server I&amp;apos;m on over there has had its main disk fill up regularly, thus bringing down all the sites hosted on it (including mine).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;apos;d &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000245.phtml&quot;&gt;joked a little while ago&lt;/a&gt; about getting myself an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XServe&quot;&gt;XServe&lt;/a&gt; and finding some affordable colocation.  Now, though, I&amp;apos;m not laughing so much.  I should probably just find another webhost, but it&amp;apos;s tempting to have my own server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past, I had a few friends at an ISP, so they let me stash a little linux server on their network for occasional favors.  I miss that.  Didn&amp;apos;t cost me anything, and my impact on their network was negligible.  Meanwhile, I had a stable, semi-reliable box on the net at which I could point a domain.  Services could catch fire and other things could tank, and no one got hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem now, though, is that shelling out for a server and colocation costs just to play around is a just a &lt;strong&gt;smidgen&lt;/strong&gt; outside my budget.  As I&amp;apos;ve pondered before, maybe I could actually host a money-making service on it with some of these hacks I&amp;apos;m percolating through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, a co-worker put the idea in my head that it might not be unreasonable to think that I could invite some tenants onto my server to share some of the cost.  I figure I&amp;apos;d take the burden of buying &amp;amp; owning the server, but I&amp;apos;d like to spread the service cost out.  I wouldn&amp;apos;t want to make a profit, I&amp;apos;d just like to make a kind of nerd commune.  It&amp;apos;d be nice if I could get the cost for everyone under US$10-15, though I imagine my cost would be higher given a server payment.  If I could get mine below $40-50 a month, I think I&amp;apos;d be happy, though this seems like a pipe dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The devil being in the details, however, I don&amp;apos;t really know how one would go about such a thing, considering service agreements and contracts and taxes and blah blah blah.  I&amp;apos;m a financial moron, and I&amp;apos;m also certainly not into being a 24/7 available customer service rep, or to perform tech help.  Basically, I&amp;apos;d like to run a server to host mad scientist experiments performed by a relatively small cadre of mad scientists who can mostly clean up after themselves.  I&amp;apos;d like to run an IRC server, maybe a Jabber server, maybe a few random half-baked server ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other other hand, is anyone out there doing this already and want a new tenant?  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2002 16:57:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/22/ooobeb/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/22/ooobeb/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Whew, take a breath, get some lunch.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Yikes.  I think &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000250.phtml&quot;&gt;that was&lt;/a&gt; the longest entry I&amp;apos;ve posted here - I usually reserve my rants, opinion posts, and various longer prose for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://deus-x.livejournal.com&quot;&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt;.  Maybe I&amp;apos;ll actually start showing a little more personality around these parts too.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2002 20:29:26 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/21/ooobea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/21/ooobea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>On grousing about Dave&#39;s exit from a mailing list</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Scanning news today, I see in my referrers a link from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/aggregators/&quot;&gt;new aggregators discussion group&lt;/a&gt; to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000228.phtml&quot;&gt;outliner &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaDesk&quot;&gt;AmphetaDesk&lt;/a&gt; skin.  Curious, I go &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/aggregators/message/44?threaded=1&quot;&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt; and see what looks like a bit of grumbling between &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disobey.com&quot;&gt;Morbus Iff&lt;/a&gt;.  I make my way back to &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/aggregators/message/42&quot;&gt;near the head of the thread&lt;/a&gt; to see what&amp;apos;s what, where I find a link to Morbus&amp;apos; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disobey.com/dnn/2002/06/index.shtml#001333&quot;&gt;post of opinioned and somewhat ranty disagreement&lt;/a&gt; toward &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.userland.com/whatIsANewsAggregator&quot;&gt;Dave&amp;apos;s definition of the modern News Aggregator&lt;/a&gt;.  What disturbs me is that the grumbling &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/aggregators/message/48&quot;&gt;quickly ends&lt;/a&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;Bill -- I&amp;apos;m going to unsubscribe from this list now. The neener boys are in charge. Take care. Dave&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Now first of all, I too &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000191.phtml&quot;&gt;disagree with Dave&amp;apos;s definition&lt;/a&gt;, and have posted as much.  Although I did so in a less rant-mode manner, both Morbus and I pointed to the fact that the news aggregator definition served the goals of Radio 8.0 marketing, being that the definition very specifically identified the features of his own product.  Rant or not, the point is made.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What disappoints me about Dave&amp;apos;s response on-list, though, is that instead of addressing the content of the disagreement, he goes after the ranting and hits back with a smidgen of ad-hominem of his own while calling for the &amp;quot;high road&amp;quot;.  Then, once he&amp;apos;s tagged on the ad-hominem he unsubscribes and dismisses the list altogether, never actually acknowledging the original point made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, though I don&amp;apos;t have a link, I&amp;apos;ve read several times where Dave has disparaged discussion groups and offered linked weblogs as the superior alternative.  I&amp;apos;ve read his essay on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.userland.com/whatIsStopEnergy&quot;&gt;Stop Energy&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;apos;m aware of his position toward the grousings and grumblings and flamings that go on within a discussion group.  And I&amp;apos;ve nodded my head almost every time he&amp;apos;s written about these things - freeform discussions on the net can sometimes - but not always - be a clusterfuck of morons and Stop Energy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it&amp;apos;s just because Dave is so intolerably fed up with &lt;i&gt;any&lt;/i&gt; hint of a clusterfuck that he dropped off the list.  I wouldn&amp;apos;t put up with much shit either, especially after heart surgery.  But to me it looked like pretty defensive behavior right from the get-go.  Morbus even gave somewhat of an apology (for him :) ) and moved on to politely hit the issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this bugs me a bit, along with other &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/UserLand&quot;&gt;UserLand&lt;/a&gt;-related thoughts I&amp;apos;ve had lately, for this reason:  Here&amp;apos;s a discussion group devoted to the very nature and future of one of the headline features of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RadioUserLand&quot;&gt;RadioUserLand&lt;/a&gt;.  And the people there are some of the most prevalent names I&amp;apos;ve seen appear time and time again in relation ot the subject.  I would think that this would be a dream group for him, in terms of driving and benefiting from innovation.  Instead, it takes only a small amount of rant to drive him away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, I&amp;apos;ve never met him, but I think I&amp;apos;d like Dave personally.  Yes, I know his writings often have one foot or both feet in marketing for his products.  But, I can&amp;apos;t recall his denying this, and I see it as the natural behavior of someone who really thinks he&amp;apos;s got something hot.  He gives favor to his customers in his posts, and he has his own opinions.  But I know these things, and I still like his software, and I still buy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, it&amp;apos;s clear that sometimes he doesn&amp;apos;t give equal time to points which may be contradictory or unfavorable to his side of things, and sometimes he gets things wrong.  But he&amp;apos;s not a journallist - he&amp;apos;s a blogger who writes from the hip and sees what flies.  Whether he lies outright is another story I haven&amp;apos;t the first inclination to follow up on, but the very nature of his product stands to check and balance to him there.  He can&amp;apos;t get away with too much with his own customers calling him on things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I&amp;apos;m starting to ramble.  What really bothers me about the quick dismissal of the list seems like a &amp;quot;See?! This is what I mean!&amp;quot; demonstration on-list, and I almost expect a post later again promoting weblogs over DG&amp;apos;s altogether.  But I didn&amp;apos;t even see him give the list a chance, and I think that&amp;apos;s sad given the brain power in that roster.  Granted, it&amp;apos;s his perogative to have slim thresholds for annoyance, but I&amp;apos;d think this would be value for his company and product.  As I said, I like his software, but he&amp;apos;s refusing free help and consultation on the future of his product.  I see those involved in groups like this taking their products beyond his, even those that were originally direct clones of his.  Maybe this ends up tying into his grousing on Open Source versus commercial software eventually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, maybe he just thinks he doesn&amp;apos;t need any help of this sort and has the sheer magnitude of innovational mojo to leave us all in the dust.  If so, rock on.  :)  As for me, I just joined the list.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2002 20:22:30 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/21/ooobeo/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/21/ooobeo/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>And I didn&#39;t even know 0xDECAFBAD had soul!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, imagine that!  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.furrygoat.com/&quot;&gt;Someone&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.furrygoat.com/Misc/Thanks.html&quot;&gt;doing something&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/thanks-for-feeding-me.phtml&quot;&gt;in the spirit of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com&quot;&gt;my site&lt;/a&gt;!  &lt;strong&gt;Neat!&lt;/strong&gt;  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2002 07:08:11 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/21/ooobdh/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/21/ooobdh/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Note to self</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick mental notes:  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Ditch the blogroll or make better efforts at updating it.  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Publish my news aggregator subscription list in addition to, or instead of the blogroll.  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Examine referrer records for readers of my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feed to find readers of whom I&amp;apos;m unaware.  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Visit all the sites listed under &lt;a href=&quot;http://dev.myelin.co.nz/ecosystem/blogs/http_3a_2f_2fdecafbad_2ecom_stats.html&quot;&gt;my stats at the blogging ecosystem site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Write more, both here, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://deus-x.livejournal.com&quot;&gt;over at &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/LiveJournal&quot;&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt;.  Possibly revive &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/deus_x/radio/&quot;&gt;The Spirit of Radio&lt;/a&gt; and my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RadioUserLand&quot;&gt;RadioUserLand&lt;/a&gt; hacking efforts.  (ie. Make Radio run blog entries through my Wiki filter)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Reskin this place, simplify and make accessible and less ugly.  Reduce number of toys, or at least give them all off switches.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Get back to work.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2002 20:06:05 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/20/ooobdg/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.lmorchard.com/2002/08/20/ooobdg/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>