<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels and self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/</link>
      <item>
          <title>Not dead yet.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Still alive...  I think.  Have worked about 40 or 50 hours in the past 3 days.  First release of work project happens tomorrow, after which I hope to take a 4 day vacation to celebrate my and my girlfriend&amp;apos;s birthday (Oct 24, same day).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Some revelations over the last few days:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;October is not 31 days long - it is 31 days and one hour long.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Java has a class to handle date manipulations that I forgot to use, for some reason - but now that I know about it, there&amp;apos;s some major rearchitecting in store to use it.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;apos;m tired of bar graphs, web server logs, and explaining how the tea leaves are read.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I like my new Treo Communicator - it is great for playing &lt;a href=&quot;http://roguelike-palm.sourceforge.net/kMoria/index.php&quot;&gt;kMoria&lt;/a&gt; (but not &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nethack.org&quot;&gt;NetHack&lt;/a&gt;) and quickly SSH&amp;apos;ing into a server from bed to restart a process about whose death I was paged on the same device.  (ooh, what if the pager message could contain a button to connect to the server crying wolf?)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;I&amp;apos;ve come to realize that I enjoy playing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/NetHack&quot;&gt;NetHack&lt;/a&gt; and kMoria between compile-and-test cycles at 3AM better than I ever enjoyed Everquest in quieter times.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;On the drive home, as the sun was rising, I was trying to think of just what aspects of Everquest (beyond graphics and besides multiplayer) are better than the family of Rogue-like games.  And...  could someone hack together a Rogue-like UI with which one could play Everquest?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Also on the drive home, I was thinking that I&amp;apos;d like to take a break from being a geek and a software architect altogether, and maybe raise sheep and make sweaters for awhile.  What do you think?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hernias suck, and impending surgery is stress-inducing.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Hopefully I&amp;apos;ll be recovered and returned to the world after next week.  I&amp;apos;ve been vaguely poking my head in and around the neighborhood, but with my iBook suffering from seizures and my brain feeling like an alien abduction aftermath, I&amp;apos;ll have a lot of catching up to do.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2002 07:51:35 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/24/ooocab/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/24/ooocab/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>RSS icon in CSS &amp; HTML</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Found something sick from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livejournal.com/users/jwz/&quot;&gt;JWZ&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/LiveJournal&quot;&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt; - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livejournal.com/talkread.bml?journal=lj_nifty&amp;amp;itemid=57340&amp;amp;thread=1095420#t1095420&quot;&gt;a CSS-based RSS icon&lt;/a&gt;.  Believe it or not, it&amp;apos;s smaller in bytes than the gif.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
  .xml_button {
     color:            FFFFFF;
     background-color: FF6600;
     border-color:     FF6600;
     border-style:     outset;
     text-decoration:  none !important;
     margin:           2em 0em 0em 0em;
     padding:          0em 0.5em 0em 0.5em;
     border-width:     2;
  }
  .xml_button:hover {
     background-color: FF9900;
  }
  .xml_button:active {
     border-style:     inset !important;
  }
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/newslog.xml&quot; class=&quot;xml_button&quot;&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;XML&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2002 18:32:30 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/21/ooocaa/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/21/ooocaa/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Status check, damage report</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Still fighting my way through the following: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;iBook hard drive crash (it&amp;apos;s still making that noise, though I thought I could cordon off the bad blocks)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;subsequent email loss (tried to mail me in the last month?  try again, please?)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;final sprint to the end of a work project&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;My girlfriend&amp;apos;s moving in with me!&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;apos;s my birthday and her birthday (Oct 24th), and our dating anniversary (Oct 27th) (strange alignment, that)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;But, the work project&amp;apos;s almost done.  Going on a vacation this week to celebrate the birthdays and anniversary.  And I&amp;apos;m not sure yet what to do with the iBook.  But!  I plan on torturing myself into prodigious amounts of writing again by having a go at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=U&amp;amp;start=1&amp;amp;q=http://www.nanowrimo.com/&amp;amp;e=653&quot;&gt;NaNoWriMo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2002 18:30:06 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/21/ooocao/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/21/ooocao/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Is the iBook supposed to make that noise?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ugh.  Hard drive in my little iBook is going &amp;quot;brr-tick-tick-tick-tick.  brr-tick-tick-tick-tick.&amp;quot; while various processes inexplicably freeze up and go AWOL.  These are things I&amp;apos;ve come to recognize as the death of a hard drive.  So, since I&amp;apos;ve been putting everything on my laptop lately, I&amp;apos;m feeling a bit lost today.  No email via local IMAP filtered through &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/SpamAssassin&quot;&gt;SpamAssassin&lt;/a&gt; and things.  No news aggregator.  No outlines.  Currently running a disk utility that I hope will route around the damage, but I&amp;apos;m not sure.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I know it&amp;apos;s gratuitous, but replacing my iBook with a &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/TiBook?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;TiBook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; that I don&amp;apos;t have to pay off for 18 months sounds mightly nice.  But, I promised myself and my girlfriend that the Treo was the last toy for awhile, until I have everything all paid off.  That, and I keep hearing rumors of a new &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/TiBook?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;TiBook&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; in the ether, early next year.  Yeah, yeah, wait for the next latest and greatest and I&amp;apos;ll be waiting all eternity, but waiting in this case would appear to align with other more prudent goals.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But either way, I&amp;apos;m feeling my lack of computing support today like a sleeping limb.  I&amp;apos;m such a dork :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2002 18:26:43 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/17/ooocoi/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/17/ooocoi/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>A new toy, and blaming Vinge</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So I finally broke down and bought a new gadget.  My phone was 5 years old and losing its antenna, and my Handspring Visor Deluxe (pre-ordered the day of introduction!) was showing its age.  I was thinking that, for the phone, I&amp;apos;d get something small and sleek.  Something that would likely fall through the little hole I inevitably have in every pocket of every jacket and overcoat I own.  And I was thinking that eventually, I&amp;apos;d procure a Sharp Zaurus to replace my PDA.  I would miss the Palm OS platform, it having done alright by me for about 6 years now, but I wanted excitement! and adventure! and modernity!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Well, after long deliberation, I saw that &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/CompUSA?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;CompUSA&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; was having an 18-months same-as-cash promotion, so I finally dragged myself in there and purchased...  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.sprintpcs.com/explore/PhonesAccessories/PhoneDetails.jsp?selectSkuId=treo300&amp;amp;FOLDER%3C%3Efolder_id=2421&amp;amp;CURRENT_USER%3C%3EATR_SCID=ECOMM&amp;amp;CURRENT_USER%3C%3EATR_PCode=None&amp;amp;CURRENT_USER%3C%3EATR_cartState=group&amp;amp;bmUID=1034793472298&quot;&gt;A Treo Communicator 300&lt;/a&gt;.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
What can I say?  I had a service contract with Sprint yet to expire, and had heard decent things about the device.  And it turned out that I just didn&amp;apos;t want to give up Palm OS quite yet, and all the other powerful phone-and-PDA combos were so hideously brick-like.  (I know, let&amp;apos;s take a standard Pocket PC, and Krazy-Glue a speaker and a stubby antenna on top!  &lt;a href=&quot;http://wapsight.com/info/2002/10/10/110227.html&quot;&gt;It&amp;apos;ll look brilliant!&lt;/a&gt;)  And along the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/BlogWalking&quot;&gt;BlogWalking&lt;/a&gt; theme, among other things, it does wireless internet admirably well and for a price that I&amp;apos;m not sweating too hard to pay.  The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/HipTop&quot;&gt;HipTop&lt;/a&gt; might&amp;apos;ve done me better, but like I said: contract I&amp;apos;m still stuck in, and Palm OS that I know how to hack.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Before I&amp;apos;d gotten it, I obsessively poured over reviews.  One of the biggest horror story themes I caught was with getting the thing activated on Sprint&amp;apos;s network, back in August.  Well, no sweat for me there.  I called up the activation number and was walked through the process by a very polite gentleman with a pleasant Indian accent whose phrases and reponses were so identically spoken that I thought I was speaking with a machine.  (Am I looney, or had I read somewhere that many call centers were &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.outsource2india.com/why_india/articles/call_centers_india.asp&quot;&gt;being outsourced to India&lt;/a&gt; and lands abroad via some nice WAN technologies?)  The new Treo was ringing and hitting Google within 10 minutes after I got off the call, despite his cautioning me that it might take upwards of 6 hours to get processed.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Once working, the earbud/mic supplied with the device worked very well.  Holding the thing up to my ear is nicer than one might expect when pressing a small slab to the side of one&amp;apos;s face, but I&amp;apos;ll probably use the earbud more.  Now if I only had an elegant way to stow and fetch the earbud on my person while I&amp;apos;m out and about.  Unspooling that tangle is no way to quickly answer the phone.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As for applications, I had everything from my old Visor transferred in short order, including my body of data whose history went all the way back to my first blocky Palm Pilot.  After that, I went out and snagged a large blob of net apps and synced them up.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=U&amp;amp;start=6&amp;amp;q=http://www.aol.com/aim/aim4palm.html&amp;amp;e=653&quot;&gt;AIM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pdaapps.com/TreoSmsApp/default.html&quot;&gt;SMS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=U&amp;amp;start=2&amp;amp;q=http://www.arthurian.nu/upirc/download.php3&amp;amp;e=653&quot;&gt;IRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=U&amp;amp;start=1&amp;amp;q=http://online.offshore.com.ai/~iang/TGssh/&amp;amp;e=653&quot;&gt;SSH&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=U&amp;amp;start=1&amp;amp;q=http://www.wind-junkie.de/PalmVNC/&amp;amp;e=653&quot;&gt;VNC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=U&amp;amp;start=2&amp;amp;q=http://www.icq.com/download/installpalm.html&amp;amp;e=653&quot;&gt;ICQ&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=U&amp;amp;start=5&amp;amp;q=http://www.actualsoft.com/prod_mmpro_details.htm&amp;amp;e=653&quot;&gt;email (via IMAP!)&lt;/a&gt;, and most importantly Google via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=U&amp;amp;start=1&amp;amp;q=http://www.handspring.com/software/blazer_overview.jhtml&amp;amp;e=653&quot;&gt;Blazer&lt;/a&gt; all worked great.  (Although, you have to watch AIM.  It &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.palmblvd.com/boards/Bugs/messages/923.html&quot;&gt;does nasty things&lt;/a&gt; occasionally and seems to corrupt its databases, requiring a warm reboot, deletion, and reenabling of all your hacks and extensions.)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, shortly I&amp;apos;ll be looking for a way to combine &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaDesk&quot;&gt;AmphetaDesk&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/OffNews?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;OffNews&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; with &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/Plucker?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;Plucker&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to give me a way to package up and slurp down a day&amp;apos;s reading like I used to do with &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/AvantGo?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;AvantGo&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  The funny thing, though, is I don&amp;apos;t know whether a single package-and-sync of reading is enough in a day.  It used to be - I would slurp down News.com, Wired News, Slashdot, and a smattering of other sites and be set for the day.  But now, I check my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaDesk&quot;&gt;AmphetaDesk&lt;/a&gt; at least 6-10 times a day.  Given that, and the fact that I do have a decent allowance for data per month, I may look at putting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaDesk&quot;&gt;AmphetaDesk&lt;/a&gt; out on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/JohnCompanies&quot;&gt;JohnCompanies&lt;/a&gt; server and whip up a Blazer-friendly skin for it using some ideas from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaOutlines&quot;&gt;AmphetaOutlines&lt;/a&gt; to hide redundant items and save me some bytes.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;apos;s such a difference now, using the Sprint data network with this slim and elegant little Treo, versus when I first bought a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.novatelwireless.com/palmtop/minstrel3.html&quot;&gt;Novatel Minstrel&lt;/a&gt; for my Palm III and used it to vaguely, slowly, gradually poke around on the web with that solid brick of magic stuff.  I can&amp;apos;t wait until all of this finally converges with affordable, socially inobtrusive wearables.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I also just got done reading another &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/VernorVinge&quot;&gt;VernorVinge&lt;/a&gt; story, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fictionwise.com/ebooks/ebook4380.htm&quot;&gt;&lt;i&gt;Fast Times at Fairmont High&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  I blame him for this.  I want display contact lenses, ubiquitous networking via computing clothes, consensual imagery overlayed across all I see.  I want twitch-speed access to searches so that I can pick up on the song or poem someone starts quoting, and complete the line for them.  I want to ping objects around me and have them respond with self-identification.  I want to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disenchanted.com/dis/technology/fly-by-wire.html&quot;&gt;live-by-wire&lt;/a&gt;.  But until then, I have a wireless net connection on my Treo with a keyboard that makes me look only slightly geeky when I type.  That, and a desire to get my butt back into school so that maybe I can get the credentials to climb my way into research with tech like this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2002 21:32:38 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/16/ooocoh/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/16/ooocoh/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Microsoft and Clip Art Follies</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is why I love the web &amp;amp; blogosphere these days.  It&amp;apos;s getting just a little harder to get away with bullshit every day.  :)  Threads cross at &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/backissues/2002/10/14#When:2:30:09PM&quot;&gt;on Dave&amp;apos;s site&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.metafilter.com/mefi/20798&quot;&gt;Metafilter&lt;/a&gt;, among other sites, and Microsoft&amp;apos;s counter-Switch ad is revealed.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Man.  And they even used a &lt;a href=&quot;http://creative.gettyimages.com/source/search/detail.asp?source=searchResults&amp;amp;imageIndex=10&amp;amp;hdnSync=%22One+Woman+Only%3AOnly+Women%22+and+%22Coffee%3AHot+Drink%22~0%2C12%2C449%2C3%2C15%2C1%2C0%2C0%2C0%2C12287%2C0%2C1%2C0%2C0%2C0%2C0%2C0%2C0%2C0%2Cen-us%2C1%2C%22One+Woman+Only%3AOnly+Women%22+and+%22Coffee%3AHot+Drink%22%2C389%2C257%2C1%2C&amp;amp;hdnCurrPage=4&quot;&gt;clip art image&lt;/a&gt; for the &amp;quot;real person&amp;quot;.  I&amp;apos;ve not been in the web biz, ad biz, or promotions biz for very long at all, but I&amp;apos;ve already developed a cynical chuckle for clip art people.  I&amp;apos;ve either searched through sources myself, or been at the shoulder of a creative director while she or he did the searching.  It doesn&amp;apos;t take very long until you can nail it when you see it.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But clip art in and of itself isn&amp;apos;t bad - it&amp;apos;s when an attempt is made to pass the clip art over as some kind of candid reality...  that&amp;apos;s when a company really shows how smart they think you are.  :)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(Oh, and P.S.:  Can you people &lt;strong&gt;please&lt;/strong&gt; stop using those &amp;quot;photographer standing on a stool over a model looking up&amp;quot; posed images?  It really doesn&amp;apos;t convey hip, cool, or clever.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2002 06:55:23 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/15/ooocog/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/15/ooocog/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>It&#39;s all about the conversation, not the referrer logs.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Pilgrim implements something I&amp;apos;ve been thinking about for awhile: His &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintomark.org/archives/2002/10/11.html#further_reading_upgrades&quot;&gt;Further Reading Upgrades&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; now harvest what appears to be the paragraph surrounding a link on a referring page.  Along with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feed of &amp;quot;Further Reading&amp;quot; items he&amp;apos;s made available, he&amp;apos;s got a nice game of follow-the-leader set up for the rest of us referrer log watchers.  Nice &amp;amp; elegant &amp;amp; makes me ashamed.  :)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Mark pulls back the curtain and &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintomark.org/projects/misc/linkbackparser.py.txt&quot;&gt;reveals the secret&lt;/a&gt;.  Yay!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yet another demonstration to me that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000258.phtml#000258&quot;&gt;ideas are f&amp;apos;ing worthless&lt;/a&gt; and the making is what matters.  Lots of things I&amp;apos;ve been &lt;strong&gt;thinking&lt;/strong&gt; about doing, but never get done.  (See also: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000305.phtml&quot; title=&quot;Blog entry #000305&quot;&gt;Blog:000305&lt;/a&gt;)  Just a few weeks ago, I managed to upgrade my referrer tracking to dig out the titles of referring pages.  And I&amp;apos;ve had an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/recent_referers_rss.php&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; of referrers myself for a few months now, but mine&amp;apos;s been ugly as sin and so I&amp;apos;ve kept it to myself.  So now I&amp;apos;ll need to think in earnest about how to do some extraction of the link-surrounding excerpt in referring pages.  Mark&amp;apos;s referrer handling really is elegant - it even seems to know how to collapse multiple views on the same referring entry (ie. front page, archive page, individual entry page).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
More things to play with :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2002 18:16:20 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/11/ooocof/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/11/ooocof/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>A breakthrough in outline transclusion!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Funny, I&amp;apos;ve just been toying around the last few weeks with doing just this, for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaOutlines&quot;&gt;AmphetaOutlines&lt;/a&gt;, to cut down on the wodge of HTML it feeds the browser all at once.  Marc Barrot presents &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0104487/2002/10/10.html#a423&quot;&gt;Transclusion Breakthrough: The Endless Web Page.&lt;/a&gt;  The post reads a bit like an &lt;a href=&quot;http://grandpasgeneral.com/seamonk.html&quot;&gt;advert for Amazing Live Seamonkeys!&lt;/a&gt;, but I think the enthusiasm is understandable:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is the &lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;in-browser&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt; version of what Dave Winer and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/UserLand&quot;&gt;UserLand&lt;/a&gt; created for Radio&amp;apos;s outliner.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is &lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;instant rendering&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;, happening on the fly as you browse through the current page. It is totally recursive: try clicking on the &amp;apos;endless web page&amp;apos; node that appears under my name in the demo page.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Now, I&amp;apos;d like to dissect and figure this out, and add it to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaOutlines&quot;&gt;AmphetaOutlines&lt;/a&gt; hack so that I can stop loading 5MB (!!!) of HTML every time I reload the page.  Beyond that, I can see some very cool applications involving live data navigation and outline rendering and... yeah.  This is cool stuff.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2002 23:48:34 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/10/ooocoe/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/10/ooocoe/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Testing Net::Blogger</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing Net::Blogger&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2002 06:09:46 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/09/ooocod/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/09/ooocod/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Cheers and tears, too</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone out there.  I&amp;apos;ve been busy as hell these last weeks, for reasons personal and professional, but I wanted to take a second to say something:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Thank you for writing.  You make me &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintomark.org/archives/2002/10/01.html#there_are_four_lights&quot;&gt;cheer&lt;/a&gt;, and you make me &lt;a href=&quot;http://snowdeal.org/section/ex_machina/archives/2002_10_06_index.html#85536636&quot;&gt;cry&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This makes me think about being a bit more human in this space, along with being the tech obsessive here.  My &lt;a href=&quot;http://deus-x.livejournal.com/&quot;&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/a&gt; has caught most of my personal entries and rants, but maybe I&amp;apos;ll finally merge the two.  Not that I&amp;apos;ve had much time for writing lately, unfortunately, but it&amp;apos;s heading toward colder and longer nights here, and I&amp;apos;m sure the urge will strike.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2002 19:46:11 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/08/ooococ/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/08/ooococ/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>MTCleanHTMLPlugin has a competitor</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Like the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MTCleanHTMLPlugin&quot;&gt;MTCleanHTMLPlugin&lt;/a&gt; I &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000296.phtml#000296&quot;&gt;released a little while ago&lt;/a&gt;, Brad Choate&amp;apos;s new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bradchoate.com/past/mtsanitize.php&quot;&gt;MT Sanitize Plugin&lt;/a&gt; appears to do the same job.  I haven&amp;apos;t tried it yet, but since I&amp;apos;m using a pile of Brad&amp;apos;s plugins and have based all of mine upon his examples, I&amp;apos;m assuming it&amp;apos;s good stuff.  I&amp;apos;ll likely check it out and see if I like mine or his better for my own use. :)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(Oh, and in case anyone wonders, I mean &amp;quot;competitor&amp;quot; in the &amp;quot;there&amp;apos;s no competition because his code-fu&amp;apos;s likely better than mine here&amp;quot; sense. :) )&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2002 21:58:10 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/03/ooocob/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/03/ooocob/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Dangerous BlogWalking</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Seen at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hiptop.com&quot;&gt;HipTop.com&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hiplogs Online Journals?It&amp;apos;s your chance to be a star! You and your trusty T-Mobile Sidekick, that is. Share your deepest thoughts or wildest whims online with a public journal you can update on the go!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;See?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/BlogWalking&quot;&gt;BlogWalking&lt;/a&gt; is a nascent meme!  Or something.  Yeah!&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2002 14:55:05 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/02/ooocoa/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/10/02/ooocoa/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>