<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels and self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/</link>
      <item>
          <title>VerisignOff from broken registrars</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nsi.com&quot;&gt;NetSol&lt;/a&gt;&amp;apos;s interface for me to change the DNS server responsible for decafbad.com has been coming up with an error page for me, &lt;i&gt;for 3 days now&lt;/i&gt;.  I just donated to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dyndns.org&quot;&gt;DynDns.org&lt;/a&gt; so I could get some dynamic DNS love going on with some decafbad.com subdomains, but no dice on switching the domain to point at their servers when my registrar&amp;apos;s &lt;b&gt;site is broken&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;apos;m going to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.verisignoff.org/&quot;&gt;VerisignOff&lt;/a&gt;.  I hopped over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.Pairnic.com/&quot;&gt;PairNIC&lt;/a&gt; and initiated a transfer.  Let&amp;apos;s see how much hassle &lt;i&gt;this&lt;/i&gt; brings me.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2002 23:10:09 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/ooobao/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/ooobao/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Digital photography the Lomography way?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Though I&amp;apos;m far, far from being an &amp;quot;artiste&amp;quot; of a photographer, I want to do &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/gallery&quot;&gt;neat things&lt;/a&gt; with my camera.  I want to capture some moments, some feelings, try some odd things.  It&amp;apos;s like hacking with light.  I see the kinds of things done with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lomography.com&quot;&gt;Lomo cameras&lt;/a&gt;, warm and in-the-moment images.  Sometimes they&amp;apos;re blurry, but that just lends them a rough handmade voice.  I read the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www1.lomography.com/0001/about/lomopop3.htm&quot;&gt;10 Golden Rules of Lomography&lt;/a&gt; and think, yeah, that&amp;apos;s what I want to do with this new gadget.    But I hope that the lens and the digital doesn&amp;apos;t kill too much of the warmth.  There&amp;apos;s a certain style that the Lomo gives to things that I doubt my gadget will get, but I want to capture the moments now that I have something small enough to be omnipresent with me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this doesn&amp;apos;t just degrade into &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/gallery/the-kitties&quot;&gt;101 pictures of my cats&lt;/a&gt;. :)  We&amp;apos;ll see.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2002 21:20:13 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/oooboi/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/oooboi/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>MT &amp; TrackBack, part the second</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Cool, looks like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.movabletype.org/trackback/&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt; is working and starting to catch on this morning.  I caught a &lt;a href=&quot;http://philringnalda.com/archives/002248.php&quot;&gt;nice compliment&lt;/a&gt; about my mutant &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000187.phtml#000187&quot;&gt;outline skin for &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/AmphetaDesk&quot;&gt;AmphetaDesk&lt;/a&gt;.  Must get back around to the next iteration of that thing, add some polish and some new features.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the MT upgrade from last night... looks like it nuked my post categories.  Grr.  That kind of blows chunks.  Might have to see what that&amp;apos;s all about, since I sagely backed everything up first.  Another thing is that I&amp;apos;d like to look more into this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TrackBack&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt; feature and the concept of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TrackBack&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt; URLs and pings.  Namely:  It&amp;apos;s a pain in the ass to cut &amp;amp; paste the TB URL, and the bookmarklet hasn&amp;apos;t worked for me yet.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I notice that there&amp;apos;s some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt; embedded in my posts now, describing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TrackBack&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt; link.  Unfortunately, I don&amp;apos;t see where the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt; explains that it is, in fact, about a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TrackBack&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt; link.  Though I haven&amp;apos;t dug into the workings yet, I assume that this is how &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TrackBack&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt;-enabled pages discover info about pages from which they&amp;apos;ve been pinged.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What would be nice is if the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt; also identifies itself as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TrackBack&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt; info.  This way, I could hack &lt;i&gt;my&lt;/i&gt; Movable Type to pluck URLs out of a post I&amp;apos;m publishing, go take a visit to each URL and try to harvest the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt;, and then automatically discover the ping URL and ping it.  All I&amp;apos;d need to do to activate the process is include a link to a page elsewhere that contains &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt; hints on how/where to ping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always looking to get more for less effort.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2002 18:13:20 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/oooboh/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/oooboh/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>TrackBack in MT 2.2</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Checking my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feeds, I see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.movabletype.org&quot;&gt;MovableType 2.2&lt;/a&gt; has been released, and it comes with support for a feature called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.movabletype.org/trackback/&quot;&gt;TrackBack&lt;/a&gt;.  Too sleepy to fully investigate and play right now, but it looks like another very cool push toward interconnectivity between blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2002 07:39:46 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/ooobog/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/ooobog/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Welcome to the wonderful world of digital photography.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So I broke down finally, and bought a digital camera.  The excuse ends up being that I&amp;apos;ll be needing it on my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.synthpopgoestheworld.com&quot;&gt;trip to Toronto this weekend&lt;/a&gt;.  I got a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.powershot.com/powershot2/s200/&quot;&gt;Canon &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/PowerShot?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;PowerShot&lt;/font&gt; S200, a 128MB CF card, the belt case, and two extra batteries.  That should be enough to cover a rampant nerd photography spree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this little thing, and I&amp;apos;ve been going insane with it.  After some twiddling and organizing in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.apple.com/iphoto/&quot;&gt;iPhoto&lt;/a&gt;, I uploaded a metric ton of photos and grabbed &lt;a href=&quot;http://gallery.sourceforge.net&quot;&gt;Gallery from &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/SourceForge?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/font&gt; to show them off in the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/gallery/&quot;&gt;0xDECAFBAD Gallery&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I stuck a lil &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/PHP&quot;&gt;PHP&lt;/a&gt; block that rotates random thumbnail images from the gallery into my busy and crowded right-side bar.  I can hear the woefully overburdened design of this site creaking and about to fall over.  So, next project in  a week or two is to tear this place apart and make it a bit easier on the eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, after I take a few hundred more pictures.  Been thinking of joining one of those online DP clubs to play around in a photo scavenger hunt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2002 07:11:12 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/ooobof/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/27/ooobof/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Busy but not too busy to warchalk</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Not much out of me yet, busy with many things.  But, you can look for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackbeltjones.com/warchalking/&quot;&gt;warchalk&lt;/a&gt; glyphs out in front of my apartment later today.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2002 23:12:22 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/25/oooboe/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/25/oooboe/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Ex-smoking bloggers of the world... breathe!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;From the recently-returned &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/backissues/2002/06/22#smoking&quot;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;I am now an ex-smoker. I want to say that in public. Of course I still really want to smoke.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Me too, since January 2002.  As Dave explains, I too had a very deep, integral place in my problem solving process for a cigarette.  I also had a spot for a cigarette in my avoiding-violence-against-coworkers process.  But, many panic attacks and insanity-verge moments later, I think I&amp;apos;m doing quite well.  I have started strangulating more co-workers, but my problem solving skills have become mroe productive.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2002 17:53:33 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/24/ooobod/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/24/ooobod/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>LiveJournal for K-Logs?!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;apos;s a crazy idea I&amp;apos;m considering:  Deploy the &lt;a href=&quot;http://cvs.livejournal.org&quot;&gt;LiveJournal source&lt;/a&gt; as our company-wide k-logging service.  Definitely make some cosmetic tweaks, possibly make some backend tweaks, but it might just be crazy enough to work.  This just struck me today, remembering back when &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000148.phtml&quot;&gt;I&amp;apos;d last thought about this&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LiveJournal can support a for each employee.  It has communities, which I can use for projects or special topics, or other forms of narrative pooling.  It has the concept of friends and friends pages, or in other words: subscriptions and aggregators.  There are friends groups, which we could use as aggregator feed groups.  And the laziness threshold is demonstratedly low, seeing the ease and frequency with which 14-year-old spew trash around their journals.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I&amp;apos;m thinking that any things missing from the LJ source I might want will be easier to add in than to build the whole thing up from scratch.  And it&amp;apos;s completely Open Source and free, though I might be able to convince some donated funds out of this place if the experiment is successful.  Hell, if not, I&amp;apos;d consider grabbing a permanent account the next time they offer them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm.  I still, someday, would like to see a decentrallized, server-less desktop answer to LJ, but this might work for now.  Radio + Frontier might get there someday, but the idea of K-Logs has such tenuous support in my organization that any cost whatsoever would kill it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Must play with this idea.  Must insinuate it like I did with the wiki.  It was accepted and made policy almost before anyone knew what hit them.  That was fun. :)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2002 00:11:08 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/22/oooboc/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/22/oooboc/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Game delayed due to illness</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In case anyone&amp;apos;s been wondering where I&amp;apos;ve been, here&amp;apos;s the story: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.livejournal.com/talkpost.bml?journal=deus_x&amp;amp;itemid=173919&quot;&gt;Clawing my way back to the land of the living&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briefly: Been bedridden with something nasty.  Too wiped out to do much besides read &amp;amp; stare.  Working on getting healthy and productive again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be back soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2002 23:16:11 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/20/ooobob/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/20/ooobob/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Recent RSS readers in RSS</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I have this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/rss_readers_rss.php&quot;&gt;recent &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; readers list in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/rss_readers_rss_php.txt&quot;&gt;src&lt;/a&gt;), I can start to see who&amp;apos;s just pulled me into their neighborhood.  (It even catches the userWeblog parameter from Radio subscribers!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I think I see that I&amp;apos;ve just had &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xs4all.nl/~punkey/Userland/&quot;&gt;Punkey&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.seanporter.com/&quot;&gt;Sean Porter&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nickn.net/radio/&quot;&gt;Nick Nichols&lt;/a&gt; join the audience.  Oh, and I see you&amp;apos;ve moved a bit, &lt;a href=&quot;http://intertwingly.net.sc.sabren.com/&quot;&gt;Mr. Ruby&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2002 01:24:23 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/15/oooboa/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/15/oooboa/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>AmphetaDesk v0.93 rolls out of bed</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/mt-images/ampheta-on-x-sm.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/mt-images/ampheta-on-x-sm.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Guess what?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disobey.com/amphetadesk&quot;&gt;AmphetaDesk v0.93&lt;/a&gt; is unleashed upon the world - so &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fnm.com/faq/#23&quot;&gt;sing and rejoice, fortune is smiling upon you&lt;/a&gt;.  I&amp;apos;m proud to say that I built the OS X faceplate for it, and hopefully the toxic chemicals I used in its production don&amp;apos;t cause any lasting effects on you, your children, or your pets.  So, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.disobey.com/amphetadesk&quot;&gt;go get it&lt;/a&gt; you infovore freaks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2002 23:11:53 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/14/oooboo/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/14/oooboo/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Aggregators taking over the desktop</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;More on aggregators and extending the concept further into the desktop, Ziv writes about &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0106548/2002/06/13.html#a27&quot;&gt;aggregation as a tool for the exterprise&lt;/a&gt;.  This is starting to cross over into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://searchebusiness.techtarget.com/sDefinition/0,,sid19_gci804078,00.html&quot;&gt;digital dashboard&lt;/a&gt; buzzword area, but I&amp;apos;m thinking that what we&amp;apos;re all &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.syndic8.com/~wkearney/blogs/syndic8/archives/000023.html#000023&quot;&gt;converging &lt;/a&gt; on will be the real deal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had to giggle though, because the &lt;a href=&quot;http://research.microsoft.com/scripts/pubs/view.asp?TR_ID=MSR-TR-2001-83&quot;&gt;Sideshow&lt;/a&gt;  project from Microsoft Research looks like my OS X dock on steroids.  Even down to the vertical arrangement, mail indicator, weather reports, IM buddy display (no faces, though), and a few other information readouts.  Of course, my dock doesn&amp;apos;t have the neato pop-out in-context mini-browser windows that connect to the icons, but that could be a keen OS X project.  Have to think about that.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2002 19:45:48 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/13/oooaii/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/13/oooaii/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>How to know when not to worry before grokking?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://bitworking.org/2002/06/12.html#a196&quot;&gt;Joe Gregorio&lt;/a&gt;: &amp;quot;&lt;i&gt;...I didn&amp;apos;t really see a need for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt; when I first learned HTML, but as I maintained some web sites over time and bumped my head enough times on having mark-up embedded in my content which made it difficult, if not impossible, to deploy a new look and feel to site without having to edit every page, I suddenly had a real need for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/CSS&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;/a&gt;. I still have a lot to learn, still more head bumping to do, and I want to have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt;, SVG, SMIL, and all the rest in my pocket when those days come.&lt;/i&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, along with his reference to Joel&amp;apos;s piece, &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joelonsoftware.com/news/20020402.html&quot;&gt;Can&amp;apos;t Understand It?  Don&amp;apos;t Worry&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, strikes a familiar chord with me.  So does &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/stories/storyReader$1657&quot;&gt;what Dave wrote&lt;/a&gt; on XML and practicians vs theoreticians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attitude I try to lead with when playing with all these new toys is that of a beginner mind.  Or, at least, that&amp;apos;s my attempted tact lately.  On the one hand, some things might look hopelessly convoluted and needlessly complicated to me.  On the other hand, there are people who are both more expert than me and who have worked longer than me on those things.  More than once I&amp;apos;ve decided I could do something better than someone else, only to discover that I was just following in that someone&amp;apos;s footsteps down the line and rediscovering all the pitfalls.  But sometimes, I do demonstrate that I&amp;apos;m smart too, and figure out something new.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I try to reserve judgement until I&amp;apos;ve grokked the thing.  Until I&amp;apos;ve soaked in it, played with it, scanned through the squabbles surrounding it, caught up with the Story So Far.  Sometimes I learn what&amp;apos;s what.  Sometimes I don&amp;apos;t.  And sometimes, I come to the conclusion that the thing I&amp;apos;m looking at really is a mess, and I stay away from it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My particular angle at the moment involves XSLT and SVG.  We want to put together a reporting and metrics package in-house at work, and I&amp;apos;m thinking that XML/XSLT/SVG may be a good combination for charting.  I understand SVG - or, rather, I get it to the extent that learning it appears obviously useful.  On the other hand, XSLT still has me scratching my head a bit.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An evangelist for XSLT at work here was trying to convince me that we could have all the HTML guys switch over from our &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.template-toolkit.org/&quot;&gt;current template technology&lt;/a&gt;, which is basically text or HTML with a small procedural scripting language for presentation work.  At present, the HTML guys are used to their process.  They&amp;apos;ve been doing it for years.  And as far as I know, they hardly ever touch the functional elements of the templates like the table foreach loops and such.  I have a sense that learning both XSLT and LISP will feel wholesome to me, but I can&amp;apos;t see the HTML guys doing it.  I mean...  recursion?!  What?  I just want to make a table and have the rows fill in with data!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So maybe the problem with this is that this is not precisely the perfect application of XSLT, though it seems to be.  With our current template toolkit, the logic of the app passes a perl data structure (a hash) to the engine, which then processes a template which refers to the keys of that structure.  I could easily represent that data structure in XML, with structure and lists and branches and all.  And I could see conceptually where an XSLT stylesheet could replace our templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But forget about our HTML guys for the minute.  What about me?  Like I said, I think it will be good for me to learn XSLT.  But I keep catching myself thinking: Why not just use a full scripting language?  Why not just use the template kit I know?  I&amp;apos;m thinking I don&amp;apos;t grok XSL well enough yet, though a part of me is grumbling skeptically at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I vaguely see some magic in it, though.  Like, XSLT contains instructions for transforming XML, yet it itself is XML.  XSLT uses XPath, which is vaguely starting to take shape in my head as something very powerful to replace many loops and frustrations in my scripting language XML processing.  And I keep seeing suggestions that XSLT can be seen as the SQL of XML, and I can imagine those uses.  But then, I see an article on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.topxml.com/xsl/articles/recurse/&quot;&gt;Two-stage recursive algorithms in XSLT&lt;/a&gt;, and I think, &amp;quot;All this, just to write a loop to calculate a sum?!&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;apos;m thinking part of this, too, is me sorting out &amp;quot;Daily Intended Use&amp;quot; versus &amp;quot;Freakish Abuse of All that is Good and Holy&amp;quot;.  Maybe when it comes down to sums, I&amp;apos;ll just do that in Perl.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hmm.  Back to drawing barcharts...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2002 19:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/13/oooaih/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/13/oooaih/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Even Mozilla supports RSS autodetection.  Sorta.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, and after downloading &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mozilla.org/releases/&quot;&gt;Mozilla 1.1a&lt;/a&gt; last night, I was pleased to see that the navigation toolbar was back.  And then, just now, I was even more pleased to see that it picked up the LINK to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feed on my front page:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/mt-images/rss-in-moz-navbar.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2002 17:24:42 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/13/oooaig/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/13/oooaig/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>News aggregators to converge toward Lifestreams/Scopeware interface?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Ziv Caspi of &lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0106548/&quot;&gt;Y. B. Normal&lt;/a&gt; thinks that &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://radio.weblogs.com/0106548/2002/06/13.html#a25&quot;&gt;Aggregators should bring more, not less, information&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;, and I&amp;apos;m inclined to agree.  Also, Adam &lt;a href=&quot;http://ipwebdev.com/radio/2002/06/11.php#a193&quot;&gt;wants to take the aggregator&lt;/a&gt; even further: &amp;quot;...I think the entire computer interface should be overhauled to be more aggregator like, events streaming by.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along these lines, has anyone played with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scopeware.com/products/prod_overview.html&quot;&gt;Scopeware&lt;/a&gt;, built from the research of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edge.org/3rd_cluture/bios/gelernter.html&quot;&gt;David Gelernter&lt;/a&gt;?    I think it used to be called &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acm.org/sigchi/chi96/proceedings/videos/Fertig/etf.htm&quot;&gt;Lifestreams&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; before it was made into a product.  I first heard of this work back when I read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/046504316X/0xdecafbad-20&quot;&gt;Machine Beauty : Elegance and the Heart of Technology&lt;/a&gt;, and was very interested but haven&amp;apos;t seen anything other than screenshots and mock-ups.  From what I can tell, this interface is literally &amp;quot;events [and documents] streaming by&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The little I&amp;apos;ve picked up from Gelernter&amp;apos;s work, along with a few other influences (ie. David Brin&amp;apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/055329024X/0xdecafbad-20&quot;&gt;Earth&lt;/a&gt;), has really stuck the picture in my head of how I want my future info-sieve to work.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with all of this, something else I was vaguely considering adding to my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000187.phtml#000187&quot;&gt;AmphetaDesk outliner skin&lt;/a&gt; was an IFRAME attached to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; items under a collapsed node.  When the node gets expanded, the IFRAME is loaded up with the item&amp;apos;s link.  The notion is that you do all your browsing from your &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feeds in a single window and within the same context.  Neat idea, I think, giving a hook to pull more information into the aggregator upon request.  But of course if I do it, it&amp;apos;ll likely be messy as hell for a zillion obvious reasons and catch my iBook on fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably have more to ramble on about this later, but it&amp;apos;s time for the first meeting of the day...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2002 17:02:20 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/13/oooaif/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/06/13/oooaif/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>