<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: msft - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/msft/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Liberating save games from Xbox Cloud Gaming</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ah, the problems of a masochistic nerd trying to game. For about a year now, my gaming PC has run &lt;a href=&quot;https://bazzite.gg/&quot;&gt;Bazzite Linux&lt;/a&gt; because I got tired of Windows. I&#39;ve also got a Game Pass subscription, prepaid for a long while from before I switched to Linux. This was not a well thought out plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While other game stores work pretty great, the only way to use my Game Pass subscription on Linux is via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-us/play&quot;&gt;Xbox Cloud Gaming&lt;/a&gt;. The Xbox app doesn&#39;t on Linux and won&#39;t install Game Pass stuff locally on Linux. Still, streaming works pretty well for games I want to try and ditch when I get bored. But, it&#39;s so ephemeral that I wouldn&#39;t really want to commit to buying a game through that outright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I started playing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/store/clair-obscur-expedition-33/9PPT8K6GQHRZ/0010&quot;&gt;Clair Obscur: Expedition 33&lt;/a&gt; via Cloud Gaming. After about 13 hours in, I realized I wanted to buy the game. As it turns out, Steam likes Linux and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.protondb.com/app/1903340&quot;&gt;the game runs well there&lt;/a&gt;. It was on sale in a bundle, so I went ahead and bought it &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.steampowered.com/app/1903340/Clair_Obscur_Expedition_33/&quot;&gt;from Steam&lt;/a&gt;  instead of from Xbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, my 13-hour-old save game was trapped in the cloud. I guessed I&#39;d just have to abandon it and start over. That is, until I pieced a few things together:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xbox.com/en-US/games/xbox-play-anywhere&quot;&gt;Xbox Play Anywhere&lt;/a&gt;, the saves in Cloud Gaming sync down to PC game installations. I had one old Windows laptop left in the house that would install Game Pass games - it just played them horribly. Once I installed the game locally from Game Pass and booted it up once, my cloud save descended onto my laptop hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I installed the game again from Steam - i.e. the copy I purchased. From there, I could follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://steamcommunity.com/app/1903340/discussions/0/592895445665061488/&quot;&gt;this guide to transplant my save file from Game Pass to Steam&lt;/a&gt;. Once properly transplanted, the save game found its way onto Steam&#39;s cloud sync servers and then back onto my real gaming PC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
For posterity, in case that thread goes away, I copied from the newest modified directory here: ```C:\Users\me\AppData\Local\Packages\KeplerInteractive.Expedition33_ymj30pw7xe604\SystemAppData\wgs\00090000044E48CB_000000000000000000000000697F9EC3```

And I copied to here: ```C:\Users\me\AppData\Local\Sandfall\Saved\SaveGames\76561198015267336```

Oh, and it needed renaming to `EXPEDITION_0.sav` - easy peasy. 
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realize this sounds like the plot to a dork heist. But, it worked!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 18:40:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/liberating-xbox-cloud-saves/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/20/liberating-xbox-cloud-saves/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>