<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: magic - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/magic/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Trifecta #59: Intention</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Thought I might try my hand at this Trifecta thing I just found, by way of Fred. The challenge is to write fiction, between 33 and 333 words, using the word of the week and its associated definition. I think I ended up with more of an introduction to something than a complete story, but here goes my attempt…&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/01/09/trifecta-59-intention/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/01/09/trifecta-59-intention/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Reviving my C64 history with a uIEC/SD</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;I&#39;ve lived a very focused life. From very early on, I&#39;ve been learning to make computers do things.
And being as introspective as I am, I like spending time considering how I got here.  I suppose this is nostalgia, but I like to think of it as recentering and recapitulation. Contemplating the story so far, as a means to consider the story yet to come.
One huge benefit of this habit is that I&#39;ve become ever more appreciative of today.  It&#39;s easy to forget, but we&#39;re living in the future these days—at least, with respect to who I was in 1983.
No flying cars yet, but for US$55 I was able to buy a tiny gadget called a uIED/SD that gives a Commodore 64 access to modern SD cards for storage.  And, of course, I have Jason Scott&#39;s review of the more general-use FC5025 5.25? Floppy to USB Adapter to blame in getting me started on this current mini-obsession.
You want to talk about a magical device? Screw the iPad—this is magic.  
This is what it looks like:&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 08 Apr 2010 00:08:44 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2010/04/07/reviving-my-c64-with-a-uiecsd/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2010/04/07/reviving-my-c64-with-a-uiecsd/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>