<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Parsec Patrol Diaries: Entity Component Systems</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;The Entity, Component, &amp;amp; System design pattern is old hat for many game developers. But, keep in mind that I’m a web developer, and mostly on the server side of things for the past decade or so. One of my last big revelations was discovering the Model, View, &amp;amp; Controller way of doing things. Apropos of that, this ECS thing seems to be a Big Deal of similar proportions.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/11/27/entity-component-system/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/11/27/entity-component-system/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Parsec Patrol Diaries: Hello World</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;So, I’ve been working on a retro space game for the web. I planned it as a fun project to “sharpen the saw” and get myself more current on some newer technologies. I also planned to use it as blog fodder, writing little diary entries about what I’ve been doing &amp;amp; discovering along the way. But, 147 commits and almost 4 months later, I’ve had fun doing the coding and have totally neglected the writing.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/11/19/parsec-patrol-diaries-hello-world/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/11/19/parsec-patrol-diaries-hello-world/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Parsec Patrol Diaries: Why a Game?</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;I decided to start writing a retro space game for the web, because I thought it might be a good way to exercise a lot of interesting technologies and have fun to boot. You know, like how sending rockets into space yields astronaut ice cream &amp;amp; anti-shock trousers back down on Earth. But, I’ve also wanted to make games all the way back to my Atari 2600, Commodore 64, and Apple ][ days – because Warren Robinett is my hero.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/11/19/parsec-patrol-diaries-why-a-game/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2013/11/19/parsec-patrol-diaries-why-a-game/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>