<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com</link>
      <item>
          <title>Baking, funky caching, and tarballs for weblog cryo storage</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So, while I was catching up on T Bryce Yehl&#39;s blog since missing &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ntwizards.net/blog/2002/11/04/so_long_radio.html&quot;&gt;his transition&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MovableType&quot;&gt;MovableType&lt;/a&gt;, I caught an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ntwizards.net/blog/2002/11/18/dynamic_vs_static.html&quot;&gt;interesting blurb he wrote&lt;/a&gt; with regards to &lt;a href=&quot;http://philringnalda.com/archives/002388.php&quot;&gt;Phil Ringnalda&#39;s ponderings&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/FriedPages&quot;&gt;FriedPages&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/BakedPages&quot;&gt;BakedPages&lt;/a&gt; in weblogs:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;&quot;Funky caching&quot; could be useful for a static publishing system as well. Weblog archives can consume a great deal of space, yet those pages are infrequently requested. Why not GZip entries from previous months and use a 404 handler to extract pages as-needed?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;The funky caching to which he refers involves implementing a 404 (page not found) handler that, instead of just supplying condolences for a missing page, actually digs the page up out of cold storage if it can.  I think I need to look into this for my site - throw all the old blog entries away into gzipped files, or maybe a tarball per month, and have a funky 404 handler dig them out when needed.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There are issues with this - such as what happens if I want to edit old content, or I change templates, or what not - but I think there could be decent solutions for those.  Hell, maybe this is an easier way to blog locally and publish globally - don&#39;t rsync directories of files, just publish locally and upload a new tarball.  Then, on the remote site, delete the index, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; files, and other affected files and watch happy updates ensue.  If a massive site change is made, rebuild locally, re-tarball every thing, upload the new tarballs, and delete all remote content to trigger revivification.  Scary but possibly nifty.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2002 08:54:32 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/28/ooocch/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/28/ooocch/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>.NET on OS X?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So... I want to learn and tinker with C# and .NET, but I don&#39;t have and don&#39;t want to build any Windows machines.  I have some headless Linux machines, but my main daily environment is Mac OS X.  So now I see that &lt;a href=&quot;http://msdn.microsoft.com/downloads/default.asp?url=/downloads/sample.asp?url=/msdn-files/027/002/097/msdncompositedoc.xml&quot;&gt;The Shared Source CLI 1.0 Release&lt;/a&gt; compiles for OS 10.2, and I see that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gnu.org/projects/dotgnu/&quot;&gt;DotGNU project&lt;/a&gt; has some news of a 100% free software release of Portable.Net.  What about Mono?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?q=mono%20os%20x&amp;amp;sourceid=mozilla-search&amp;amp;start=0&amp;amp;start=0&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&quot;&gt;Any OS X news&lt;/a&gt;?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Or are things still basically in the &quot;You can compile &amp;amp; run Hello World, barely, but don&#39;t expect access to any of the standard framework classes or GUI building&quot; stage?  Or are they in an even less developed stage that would make my non-compiler-building branes melt out my ears?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2002 06:52:59 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/28/oooccg/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/28/oooccg/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>RSS vs HTML - NO FIGHT!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintomark.org/archives/2002/11/26.html#syndication_is_not_publication&quot;&gt;Syndication is not Publication&lt;/a&gt;, Mark Pilgrim elucidates in eloquence what I&#39;d &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000331.phtml&quot;&gt;vaguely poked at in silliness&lt;/a&gt;.  No, I agree with mark - syndication cannot replace publication, and publication cannot replace syndication.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Though, I think it&#39;s interesting to watch the thought experiments and the &quot;what ifs&quot; as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000331.phtml#comments&quot;&gt;Anil commented&lt;/a&gt; - and while I sense some eloquence in both approaches, neither answers all the demands placed on each.  Hopefully, what dabbling in overloading one could provide is a little insight into enhancinging the other. In the end, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000331.phtml#comments&quot;&gt;Dave commented&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintomark.org/archives/2002/11/26.html#the_rebellion_will_be_syndicated&quot;&gt;Mark demonstrated&lt;/a&gt;, there will be no fight - tinkerers will route around the solution they don&#39;t like.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2002 06:24:57 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/28/oooccf/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/28/oooccf/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>XML-RPC case study redux, Part II: REST and I</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So, from my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000333.phtml&quot;&gt;last installment&lt;/a&gt;, I left off with this:  My daily situation with regards to integrating the web-based services of various parties boils down to what I can explain in 30 minutes to a developer of unknown competence to whom I&#39;m barely a priority.  So far, I&#39;ve been able to apply &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; as a solution to this problem with a great degree of success.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
About this, endulging me although I&#39;m sure issues like mine have been hashed out a million times already on various mailing lists, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogstream.com/pauls/1038403139&quot;&gt;Paul Prescod writes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;There&#39;s nothing wrong with the way you&#39;ve used XML-RPC and I&#39;ve used it that way myself. I only write to ensure that you (and anyone reading) understands the costs and benefits of this approach. You&#39;ve given up on many of the feature of the underlying XML and HTTP technologies. If you don&#39;t need the features, then amen, let her rip. But people building more substantial apps do need them.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yes.  So, I know that my chosen solution has its blemishes and land mines awaiting my step.  But, none of them have bitten me yet, nor do I expect them to for some time.  On the contrary, for every practical application of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; we&#39;ve deployed, we&#39;ve had happy clients.  While working in this industry, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?q=80/20%20rule&quot;&gt;80/20 rule&lt;/a&gt; has been beaten into me - so if a solution that&#39;s 20% complete solves 80% of our problems, it&#39;s time to move onto the next problem.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This, however, is a dangerous thing to become complacent about - there&#39;re still 20% worth of problems out there for which this solution falls down.  And each one will become a work-till-3-am nightmare when they hit.  And besides, I&#39;m a perfectionist and a purist at heart, so the dirtiness of this solution will never fail to irk me.  It may be simple, but simple is not necessarily elegant.  So what about the rest of Paul&#39;s points?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;The first axis of flexibility you&#39;ve given up is in character set. XML-RPC disallows Unicode character strings.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;On one hand, my impulse is to respond to this by invoking &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acronymfinder.com/af-query.asp?String=exact&amp;amp;Acronym=YAGNI&quot;&gt;YAGNI&lt;/a&gt; - since our use of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; involves messages between machines, I don&#39;t care about localizing those.  I&#39;ll just keep to language neutral data in there.  But, I&#39;m naive.  With a bit of pondering, I can identify at least one area where user-supplied input needs to be traded - shared registration and login for global promotions.  And if I can identify one, there&#39;s bound to be more.  I don&#39;t have as much experience with Unicode and handling languages other than English as I&#39;d like, so I can&#39;t trust my assumptions here.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;XML-RPC is brutally non-extensible. ... Dave Winer has been actively hostile to every effort to evolve XML-RPC.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;In this case, I&#39;d say this is a good thing, for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; in particular.  It does what it does, no more and no less, and this will never change.  I will never need to bring up versions of the spec in my 1/2 hour conversation with the junior engineer.  And though I don&#39;t want to second guess Dave Winer, I assume this is the goal in his insistence on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; being ever frozen.  The alternative at which he points, if memory serves, is SOAP.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;The third aspect: XML itself. What will happen when and if your industry, whatever it is, canonizes a schema for what you do, like the hundreds of existing ones. ... Maybe your industry isn&#39;t organized enough to define a schema for whatever it is you do.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Bingo.  Our industry is neither mature nor organized enough to conceive of any sort of schema.  Our products and the concepts involved in our work are in constant change, not to mention the conditions of the market and what will continue to work.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;Another way of attacking your interoperability problem would be to start from that point of view, defining the XML and then working back to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; system. That&#39;s a much more natural way to define a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt;-based web service and is arguably a better way to define web services in general. I would be curious whether you tried this.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Nope, haven&#39;t tried this.  This is where I start calling things &quot;ivory tower&quot;.  To me, it makes elegant sense.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;You say you tried &quot;REST-ish URL schemes&quot; but that isn&#39;t the same as trying &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt;. In particular, you don&#39;t say much about what your XML strategy was.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Calling our early interop schemes &quot;REST-ish&quot; may have been too strong an association with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt;.  No XML strategy.  More like: &quot;Make a GET to this URL with these query parameters, documented here.  You&#39;ll get a simple text response back, documented here.&quot;  This was always balked at, though I thought it was the simplest thing in the world.  I might have some thoughts on the failure of this, if I think about it some more.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;I don&#39;t know your suppliers, but in the vast majority of situations I have been exposed to, they &quot;get it&quot; if you tell them: &quot;here are some XML example documents. POST things like that to me when you want me to do something and GET them from me when you want to get information from me.&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Whenever XML is brought up, fear rises and eyes glaze.  We&#39;re the &quot;supplier&quot; in most situations, and it&#39;s rare that our clients are tech-centered companies.  They have a web site, and maybe a team maintaining it if we&#39;re lucky.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;You depicted the situation as SOAP on one side (grungy), &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; on the other (ivory tower) and XML-RPC in the middle. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; is basically the same old CGI-ish stuff we&#39;ve been doing for a decade so I don&#39;t see how it is very ivory towerish.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Well, I&#39;m mixing audiences here.  SOAP, to me and my lack of time with it, seems grungy and in flux.  To my clients, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; seems out there, especially if I ever try to explain to them what the letters stand for.  :)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&quot;What&#39;s a siggy?&quot;  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&quot;You mean a C-G-I?&quot;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In explaining &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt;, I usually say something long the lines of &quot;your people&#39;s boxes talk to my people&#39;s boxes,&quot; then point them at the website that says largely the same thing.  Of course, this begs the question of my effort and competence in explaining &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; to others, which I feel is lacking thus far.  Because, well, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; is also their boxes talking to my boxes.  And, I haven&#39;t found a website at which to point both techie and non-techie audiences to &quot;get it&quot;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;...perhaps &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t apply to you. Yet. ... You say that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; doesn&#39;t &quot;feel finished&quot; to you. Nor to me. Our industry is in the middle of a huge migration to extensible formats like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; which builds on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt; which builds on XML.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;I don&#39;t think &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; quite applies to us yet.  I&#39;d like it to.  Maybe once we, as a company, have formed much stronger partnerships I can get past the 30 minute barrier and get to some real discussions and establish things like XML schema.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;When people are comfortable with extensible, hyperlinked formats, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; will seem like a no-brainer.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;The more I read and think about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt;, the more I agree with this.  It&#39;s just that I find it very hard to sell the idea yet.  Again, this may be the nature of the beast for whom I work, and it may be my lack of ability to describe this simply.  
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But for now, it seems that the ability to throw a random unknown web developer an API and a URL with less than 30 minutes&#39; accompanying discussion, and get results, seems to work for us.
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2002 21:05:02 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/27/oooccd/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/27/oooccd/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>XML-RPC case study redux, Part I: Setting</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So, my little &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000332.phtml&quot;&gt;off the cuff case study&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; from yesterday got a ton of flow &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/backissues/2002/11/26#When:8:22:26AM&quot;&gt;from Dave&lt;/a&gt;.  Got some comments and some email, and a very good &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogstream.com/pauls/1038403139&quot;&gt;response / rebuttal from Paul Prescod.&lt;/a&gt;  Thanks to everyone for reading &amp;amp; responding!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I think a few things from that case study, the response to it, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blogstream.com/pauls/1038403139&quot;&gt;Paul&#39;s comments&lt;/a&gt; need some more consideration.  And, I think some more clarification of my situation would work as well.  So I&#39;ll start with that:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The first thing is that I think the quote Dave pulled from my case study nails my situation: &quot;I get it, my boss gets it, his boss gets it, the sales guys get it, and the marketing guy who&#39;s always our first contact at a client gets it.&quot;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I work at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eprize.net&quot;&gt;a promotions company&lt;/a&gt;.  Because we act as a sort of application service provider and host everything ourselves, we can do and have done some pretty nifty things within our walls.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
On our clients&#39; side, though, they&#39;re hiring us to do nifty things that don&#39;t require them to do much at all.  In fact, the vast majority of the time, our direct client contact is a marketing/PR person who has little, if any, access to technical resources.  It&#39;s a major undertaking for this person to get an image tag or a javascript pop-up window slipped into an HTML page somewhere on the company website - anything further than that leads down a trail of tears and a week&#39;s worth of conference calls with grumpy people.  We&#39;ve spent more than 4 years streamlining everything down to the acceptance of this fact.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So then, in walks the client who wants a lot more, like the aforementioned client for whom &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; worked swimmingly for integration between their site, their commerce vendor, and us.  Our direct contact is still a marketing person, but she has a &lt;em&gt;bit&lt;/em&gt; more technical support behind her.  She might be able to get up to 4 hours&#39; time from a junior engineer over there to whip up a CGI or JSP, assuming that the team in charge of the website approves permission to do so.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As part of that junior engineer&#39;s time, I have one half-hour conference call to explain our points of integration, how everything&#39;s going to work, and where to go for resources on how to do it.  I barrage the person with email, offer availability on at least 3 different instant messaging networks, but when it comes down to it this 1/2 hour phone call is all anyone remembers.  We&#39;ve been working on improving this situation, but the only traction comes from where we&#39;ve been able to gain the confidence of a client as a long term strategy partner.  Otherwise, we&#39;re just some random vendor who gets tossed away if we make too much noise.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
What this all boils down to is that I&#39;ve needed to develop a scheme of integration between web apps that can be explained mainly in 30 minutes to a developer of unknown competence to whom I&#39;m barely a priority.  This is my situation at present.  The situation has room for improvement - but the power to make those improvements are largely beyond my influence - so I&#39;ve applied &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; successfully &lt;strong&gt;so far&lt;/strong&gt; as a solution.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, I&#39;ll post this, and in the next installment (if you&#39;re still with me), I&#39;ll voice my concerns with the solution I&#39;ve chosen, and consider what Paul&#39;s written.  As always, I encourage you to tell me where I&#39;m full of it, and why.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2002 19:55:11 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/27/oooccc/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/27/oooccc/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>XML-RPC, a mini case study</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;About SOAP vs &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; vs XML-RPC, &lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/backissues/2002/11/23#When:3:49:18PM&quot;&gt;Dave writes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;By and large &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; interfaces don&#39;t tell you how to serialize and deserialize complex structures, so you kind of start from scratch every time. If they use a SOAP encoding, you get some of that. But there just is nothing simpler than saying &quot;Here&#39;s the XML-RPC interface, and some sample code in a few of the popular scripting languages.&quot; If you want developers to get going quickly, avoid the religious wars, just support XML-RPC. Now even this isn&#39;t bluster-free. Think of it as evangelism. Have a nice day.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Though I don&#39;t like his remarks on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt;, I gotta give Dave an &lt;i&gt;amen&lt;/i&gt; here and thank him for having &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; out there for me to stumble upon.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; seems shiny and neat to me but incomplete - I&#39;m pulling for it because it seems warm and fuzzy to my ivory tower branes.  SOAP seems to try to be nice &amp;amp; clean, but feels grungy and toxic to me and I&#39;ve always felt a vague sense of unease when walking past its house on the block.  In the middle, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; seems to be the right balance of dirt and acidity to grow things in.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
About &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt;, I can speak with some experience now.  I first started tinkering with it a few months shy of a year ago, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/news_archives/000020.phtml#000020&quot;&gt;when I first launched this blog&lt;/a&gt;.  I went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;http://www.xmlrpc.com&lt;/a&gt; and learned it in less than an afternoon.  Cobbled together a few &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/Projects&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; with it, and saw an opportunity to introduce &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; as a new tech at work.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(In case you don&#39;t know about my job, I&#39;m the guy who does most of the research &amp;amp; development, tool building, and overall platform architecture at a promotions company called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.eprize.net&quot;&gt;ePrize&lt;/a&gt;.  I grumble about the place from time to time, but on the whole they let me do an amazing amount of wandering around in finding new things.)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Anyway, we&#39;d been poking around with a few different means of integrating our promotions into clients&#39; websites.  You see, we host the web part of all promotions on our servers, and work toward making inclusion of those promotions not much harder than slipping in a banner.  But sometimes, there&#39;s just no avoiding more complex integration.  And sometimes, it&#39;s exactly what you want with things like shared sign-up &amp;amp; login, awarding tokens &amp;amp; coupons, and coordinating between vendors&#39; services.  So, we had a few different &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt;-esque URL-based schemes, some FTP-and-PGP-based things, and even managed to convince one client to use a one-off protocol between two perl net daemons.  Every time, it was something new, and we could seem to get no two clients happy with the same integration scheme.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Then one day I bring &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; into the office, and weave it into our app platform at the ground floor.  Overnight, just about every aspect of every promotion we do can be accessed via &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt;, given the proper switches thrown and the right access controls set.  Producing an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; API spec for potential clients took mostly a bit of cut &amp;amp; paste massaging of our internal API docs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
(Your mileage may vary greatly, but our homegrown platform seemed pre-designed to fit with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt;.  This point right here may be what makes this anecdote fall on its face for you and your experiences.  But, based on the success we have with it on the client end of things, I suspect that we&#39;re not that much an outlier.)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The next day, we had a meeting with a giant customer whose name I&#39;m not sure I can mention, but suffice it to say you&#39;ve heard of them and It&#39;s very, very likely that you&#39;ve used their gadgets.  We helped them put together a customer referral and rewards program, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt; as the glue between an online store vendor, the client&#39;s site, and us.  It was a great success, and since then we&#39;ve done another dozen or so cool promotions involving &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
What makes this tech so successful here is that it&#39;s so simple and decently understood.  I get it, my boss gets it, his boss gets it, the sales guys get it, and the marketing guy who&#39;s always our first contact at a client gets it.  And when we finally drill down to a tech guy on the client&#39;s side, we just tell him, &quot;Here&#39;s the API for your promotion, and visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xmlrpc.com&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;http://www.xmlrpc.com&lt;/a&gt; for details on how to call it.&quot;  And that&#39;s it - 75% of the time they get it and implement it.  The rest of the time, we have to spend some time proving the tech and answering doubts, but it&#39;s always a pleasant experience from our end having all the answers.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I&#39;ll adore &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/REST&quot;&gt;REST&lt;/a&gt; if/when it gets to this point in helping me get mine and my client counterparts&#39; jobs done.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Anyway, this is sounding like a bad infomercial and I need to get back to work.  But I had to toss out this bit of anecdotal dross in favor of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpc&quot;&gt;XmlRpc&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2002 18:46:07 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/26/oooccb/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/26/oooccb/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>RSS vs XHTML - FIGHT!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://backend.userland.com/formatsForBlogBrowsers&quot;&gt;Formats for Blog Browsers&lt;/a&gt;, Dave writes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;I wanted to add a facility that would automatically back up all your weblog posts... &quot;I bet &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; 2.0 could do this,&quot; I said out loud. And now that the code works, the answer is clear. It can. ...  Then another lightning bolt hit me. ... What if someone made a browser that worked with this format?  Let&#39;s call them Blog Browsers, apps specially designed for reading weblogs.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;About syndication formats, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dashes.com/anil/index.php?archives/004158.php&quot;&gt;Anil Dash writes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;I have a radical proposal for a ubiqitous content syndication format, applicable for almost any purpose, but extremely well suited for weblogs. ... My new syndication format is called XHTML.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;In one corner, we have the syndication format taking over the document format.  In the other corner, we have the document format taking over the syndication format!  &lt;strong&gt;FIGHT!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yeah, yeah, it&#39;s not quite &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; simple - but the opposed directions are interesting.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2002 18:04:31 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/26/ooocca/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/26/ooocca/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Hammer that round peg into that round hole</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;About the &quot;RDF tax&quot; in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.yahoo.com/group/rss-dev/message/4524&quot;&gt;Jon Hanna says&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ah, but you&#39;re missing the key point that a framework for making statements about web resources is of no use to a format that makes statements about web resources. It was obviously forced. :)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Heh, heh.  Full point, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt; team.  Now I go back to studying.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2002 19:07:52 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/25/ooocco/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/25/ooocco/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Bellyflop Into RDF</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Want to watch me taking baby steps in coming to terms with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt;?  Come take a look at, or point and stare at, my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RdfNotes&quot;&gt;RdfNotes&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2002 02:02:16 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/23/ooocbi/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/23/ooocbi/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Moblogging or BlogWalking, all the same to me</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Justin Hall of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefeature.com&quot;&gt;TheFeature&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thefeature.com/index.jsp?url=article.jsp?pageid=24815&quot;&gt;From Weblog to Moblog&lt;/a&gt;, writes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;Weblogs reflect our lives at our desks, on our computers, referencing mostly other flat pages, links between blocks of text. But mobile blogs should be far richer, fueled by multimedia, more intimate data and far-flung friends. As we chatter and text away, our phones could record and share the parts we choose: a walking, talking, texting, seeing record of our time around town, corrected and augmented by other mobloggers.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Touches on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/SmartMobs&quot;&gt;SmartMobs&lt;/a&gt; and collaborative journalism.  He calls it &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/MoBlogging?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;MoBlogging&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; (mobile-blogging), but I&#39;ll still call it &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/BlogWalking&quot;&gt;BlogWalking&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Haven&#39;t had a whole lot of success doing any blogging on the go with my Treo yet, but then I haven&#39;t tried very hard at all yet due to a lack of copious free time.  Have some ideas that should help.  Liking the Treo, but after settling into it, I&#39;m kind of wishing I could have gotten a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/HipTop&quot;&gt;HipTop&lt;/a&gt;.  I expected the Palm to be mature, but it&#39;s just kinda clunky and creaky and elderly.  I expect the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/HipTop&quot;&gt;HipTop&lt;/a&gt; to get slicker, and I&#39;d like the bigger keys better - not to mention the lil camera.  But, my Sprint contract is up in a little under a year, so around this time next year I&#39;ll retire the Treo and survey the landscape again.  Hopefully there&#39;ll be a dream device out by then.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2002 20:08:16 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/22/ooocbh/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/22/ooocbh/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Cool URIs don&#39;t change</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I&#39;m probably the only one who didn&#39;t know this, but I&#39;ve been wondering why it seems that every website owned by someone within a few degrees of separation from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TimBL&quot;&gt;TimBL&lt;/a&gt; tend to use URLs of the form:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;code&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.example.org/2002/11/nifty-thing&quot;&gt;http://www.example.org/2002/11/nifty-thing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Just one of those things I figured kinda made sense, but was never sure why for.  Then, today after a bit of wandering while researching things &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/SemanticWeb&quot;&gt;SemanticWeb&lt;/a&gt;, I found a link from &lt;a href=&quot;http://infomesh.net/sbp/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Sean B. Palmer&lt;/a&gt; pointing to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/Provider/Style/URI.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Hypertext Style: Cool URIs don&#39;t change&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TimBL&quot;&gt;TimBL&lt;/a&gt; himself.  Seems the example of this pattern is layed out there by the man himself.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Seems like it would work like a limited sort of concurrent versioning scheme, but it just looked wonky the first time I saw it.  I mean - date-based website layout?  I&#39;d been raised on the high falutin&#39; directory trees made by very well (overly?) paid Information Architect types.  &lt;code&gt;/2000/10/stuff&lt;/code&gt;?  What about &lt;code&gt;/about-us/corporate/ceo.html&lt;/code&gt;?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Of course, this is ignoring the fact that some webservers need not directly tie physical disk layout to URL layout.  Or that site architecture is best presented via links in the documents themselves.  It&#39;s just that plain vanilla Apache uses a 1:1 match between file path and URL path, and that&#39;s what most everyone uses.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Hmm..  Might play with it a bit around here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2002 07:18:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/22/ooocbg/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/22/ooocbg/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Let&#39;s play Marco Polo with RFID!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Remember that Slashdot story from the weekend - &lt;a href=&quot;http://slashdot.org/articles/02/11/17/0327244.shtml?tid=126&quot;&gt;Gillette Buys Half a Billion &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RFID&quot;&gt;RFID&lt;/a&gt; Tags?  Boring, yawn, inventory management, who cares?  Well, imagine if those things, along with their readers, got so ludicrously cheap and small that mothers would stick &#39;em to kids&#39; underwear as they went off to camp, and readers came standard in watches and cell phones.  Imagine that, somehow, the range was improved to at least 20 feet - your reader sends out a radio ping (MARCO!) and back comes a list of the contents of the room as every object responds (POLO!).  Assume as well that your reader can work out the location of each of these objects.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ignore the big brother fears for now - everyone will have this stuff, not just the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MiB&quot;&gt;MiBs&lt;/a&gt;.  Also, ignore my ignorance - many of these enhanced tricks are likely impossible or at least very hard for these little gadgets.  For now.  Until someone does something clever.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But, imagine!  Never lose your keys again!  Find the cat!  Owners manuals to everything you own - should you ever actually have the impulse to read one - are available with a tag ping and a lookup.  Imagine the games &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/SmartMobs&quot;&gt;SmartMobs&lt;/a&gt; will find for this stuff!  Handle the tag code on objects in the world with a URI scheme - the Semantic Web reaches out to help create the Semantic World!  It&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/CueCat&quot;&gt;CueCat&lt;/a&gt; on super steroids!  Facial recognition in your PDA to remember my name?  Bah - I&#39;ve got a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RFID&quot;&gt;RFID&lt;/a&gt; business card in my pocket.  Consider the combination of this with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WearableComputer&quot;&gt;WearableComputer&lt;/a&gt;, and the world becomes just a bit more active as previously inanimate objects can tell you their stories and stories told about them.  High tech &lt;a href=&quot;animism&quot;&gt;animism&lt;/a&gt;!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Okay, I&#39;m winding down on this.  I know I&#39;m going wonky with this idea, but this is along a theme I&#39;ve been playing with in my head: My favorite sci-fi stories and meditations on the future involve little clever bits of tech that get tweaked and leveraged in powerful ways few could have guessed at.  Maybe this tagging tech I&#39;m hyping won&#39;t be it, but it&#39;s one of the ideas that tweaked me in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/VernorVinge&quot;&gt;VernorVinge&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fictionwise.com/ebooks/eBook4380.htm&quot;&gt;Fast Times at Fairmont High&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Trying to stretch my brane more along these lines - squinting at the knee of the curve of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TheSingularity&quot;&gt;TheSingularity&lt;/a&gt;.  What else is on the verge of emergence, how much of it is crap and how much of it is the real thing?  Will things like this and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WearableComputer&quot;&gt;WearableComputer&lt;/a&gt; and ubiquitous internet actually cause major change, or will it just turn into more chuckles for my grandkids when they ask me what it was like in the 90&#39;s and double-naughts, when I was living it up at conventions on the company tab, sipping a stout while getting my whites washed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://cuisinenet.com/info/?v=237&amp;amp;/san_francisco/rest/5133.shtml&quot;&gt;a whacky laundry/bar in San Francisco&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2002 07:58:03 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/21/ooocbf/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/21/ooocbf/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Email as command line</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linuxjournal.com/article.php?sid=6453&quot;&gt;E-mail as a System Console. Part I&lt;/a&gt; over at Linux Journal.  It&#39;s something I&#39;ve been meaning to implement for awhile, using &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.cpan.org/search?mode=all&amp;amp;query=Mail::Audit&quot; title=&quot;CPAN search for Mail::Audit&quot;&gt;CPAN:Mail::Audit&lt;/a&gt; and other tools.  Got a bit of a start on things, with a sort of plugin system for adding commands available via email.  Maybe I should hit this again.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Personally, it&#39;s been a long, long while since I had a dialup-based system - so I don&#39;t have to solve their exact problem.  But, it would be nice to fire off an email to myself or some other mailbox I own, formulated just so and cryptographically signed by me that would cause some machine behind a firewall to open up an SSH tunnel to a predetermined location somewhere.  Among other things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2002 18:00:58 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/20/ooocbe/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/20/ooocbe/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Really, this time, I wanna come back</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Whew, it&#39;s been a long stretch of urgency and emergency lately without much time for reflection or writing, let alone any general hackery.  Don&#39;t want to go through a fully detailed recap - but my girlfriend moved in with me; mostly have survived a near &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/DeathMarch?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;DeathMarch&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; project; took care of said girlfriend after surgery; was taken care of by said girlfriend after surgery myself.  Managed to squeeze a birthday and dating anniversary celebratory break in there, but - not much time for blog, Doctor Jones.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I really want that to change now.  A lot has been going on since I&#39;ve had to take a step back from large parts of my life, but I think I can step back into things again now.  Need to restart the social life, and start poking my head out of the lurker pool on the net.  Time to finally regroup, exit the state of urgency and emergency, and get back to moving foward instead of moving in reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2002 09:00:03 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/19/ooocbd/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/19/ooocbd/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Broken project download links fixed</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just fixed the download links on these projects:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RssDisplay&quot;&gt;RssDisplay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/ShowReferers&quot;&gt;ShowReferers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/GoogleToRSS&quot;&gt;GoogleToRSS&lt;/a&gt;.  Just took me awhile to circle back around to it, ugh.  So if you were ever interested in those projects, please try grabbing them again for ridicule.  :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2002 08:49:27 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/19/ooocbc/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/11/19/ooocbc/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>