<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>GeniusEngineer Blog of the Day</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Wow.  It appears that this is the Blog of the day at
GeniusEngineer.com.  I&#39;ve never visited the
site before, but I&#39;m flattered by being chosen just the same.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2003 17:41:16 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/30/ge-blog-of-day/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/30/ge-blog-of-day/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Videos on tape (Travan, not VHS)</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Oh and while I&#39;m writing about watching video files on my TV, I&#39;ve
been thinking of getting myself a tape drive.  Sure, I&#39;ll use it to
actually, finally, back up all the important things I have littered
around my handful of machines.  Having established a backup routine
at work, I&#39;ve gotten to thinking.
How bad an idea would it be to use a tape drive to store TV shows?
I&#39;ve been capturing them with the VCD format, which gives me around
600MB per hour of show.  This fills up my drive pretty quickly,
obviously.  I know I really should take sometime to revisit things and
try another video codec, since originally I used VCD because I burned
everything to CD for my DVD player, but now I&#39;m streaming files to my
Powerbook over the network which gives me a lot more flexibility in
recording options.
However, not burning to CD leaves me with a hard drive full of video
that I&#39;m hesitant to delete yet have no good reason to need laying around on a
high speed hard drive.  But, burning all that to a spindle-worth
of blank CDs without a Lego Mindstorms based CD-changer robot leaves
me shuddering.  I recall reading about a DJ-bot
that did this for playing music, and I notice via Slashdot that someone with a
decent woodshop has provided plans
for such a beast for a CD writer.  But I can&#39;t afford the Legos at
the present moment, and I&#39;ll only end up hurting myself working with
power tools.
Then, I remember that high capacity tapes make backing up lots of data
easy at work.  I know that the tape trade off is capacity and price
for speed of access.  But, if all I need to do is skip from one file
to the next and only need relatively low bandwidth to stream the file
from the tape, this sounds like a great way to archive video.
Depending on the video compression, maybe I could fit a whole season
or two of a show onto a single tape.
Seems like a good idea, though pricey.  But maybe the price and cost
of media would offset the pain in the ass of any other method.  I probably
should look more into the price and pain of a DVD burner, but the idea
of more disc-like things laying around worries me.
What do you think?&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2003 14:58:52 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/30/video-on-tape/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/30/video-on-tape/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>My Powerbook&#39;s on TV</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;I don&#39;t gush about it very often, but I love my 12&quot; Powerbook.  Since
I got it this past March, it has been my primary machine for both work
and home.  And other than wishing that there was a 1GB memory module
out for it and grumbling that I&#39;ve lost one of the rubber footies on
the bottom, I&#39;ve been extremely happy with it.
And just last night, I was reminded of yet another feature that&#39;s made me
glad I got it: the included
Composite/SVHS video adapter.
I&#39;d had the AV cable
for my iBook before it, but the use of the adapter on the Powerbook
has a very important difference: dual display mode.
See, when I connected my iBook up to my home entertainment complex,
I got reduced resolution back on the LCD, and anything I did that went
full screen (ie. playing a DVD or a movie file) took over the machine.
But with the Powerbook, its connection to my television is just a second
desktop, not much different than the second monitor I use at work.
So, while I&#39;m at home on the futon with my girlfriend, I often stream
videos off a PC in the next room that&#39;s been recording TV shows for
me, and present them on this second desktop.  Most apps I use to view
movies, such as Quicktime Pro
and VideoLAN,
allow me to pick a monitor for fullscreen mode. Meanwhile, the LCD on the
Powerbook is still available for other work while we watch.
It&#39;s just a little thing, but it&#39;s a thing that lets me get much of the
benefit of a dedicated
Home Theater PC without
having to buy or build a box that looks nice alongside all our
video game consoles.
While I&#39;d still like to take on the project someday, my Powerbook does
just fine for the display and audio end of things, while an aging Windows PC
in the next room snags a few TV shows
for me.
Of course, if all you want is an HTPC, the Powerbook is expensive
overkill.  But, if you&#39;re shopping for a laptop and want some fringe
benefits, I think this is definitely one that doesn&#39;t get much attention.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2003 14:23:29 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/30/powerbook-on-tv/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/30/powerbook-on-tv/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Macromedia Central and Deja Vu?</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Macromedia Central provides a safe environment for developers to deploy occasionally-connected applications. Using Macromedia Central, developers can create an application and give it away for free. Or they can sell it to end users using the Try/Buy framework that is part of Central.                                            

Source: Macromedia - DevNet : Macromedia Central: How it Works



I’ve had a bit of enthusiasm for Flash lately.  So, this Macromedia Central thing that’s been on its way for a little while now looks very interesting.

&lt;p&gt;But…  What differentiates it from every other “widgets on your desktop” or “widgets in a little box” technology that’s come before?  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?q=dodots&quot;&gt;Remember&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://disobey.com/ghostsites/show_exhibit/dodots&quot;&gt;DoDots&lt;/a&gt; ?  &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;CNN&lt;/span&gt; called them &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cnn.com/2000/TECH/computing/04/07/dodots.idg/&quot;&gt;the web without a browser&lt;/a&gt; and there was general gushing here and there about it.  At one point, I was close to being drafted to write a few promotional games using their &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SDK&lt;/span&gt;, and it seemed nifty enough.  No clients bit, though.  And all that remains of the company on the web are ghost pages and ex-employee photo albums and reunions.  Oh, and I still have a mousepad and a clipboard from the dev kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://java.sun.com/products/javawebstart/&quot;&gt;Java Web Start&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.konfabulator.com/&quot;&gt;Konfabulator&lt;/a&gt; .  Have any of these sorts of things really taken off?  I mean, they all have their share of nifty things, but has this idea of a centrallized corral of mini-apps ever paid off?  Flash is yet another cool technology with which to develop these things, but will Central take off?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not trying to whiz on anyone’s Cheerios, since I honestly think these things are nifty, but then again I like widgets with fun buttons to push.&lt;/p&gt;

Update: Hmm...  Mike Chambers is inviting questions about Central.  Maybe I should wander over there and ask.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2003 12:26:05 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/30/mm-central-works/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/30/mm-central-works/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Google ads getting monotonous?</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Well, I forgot to mention it, but I emailed Google awhile back about their
rejecting my site for
Google ?AdSense.  They got back to me and let me in the club, which is
demonstrated by the skyscraper ad to the right.  So far, I seem to be on the
road to earning free hosting for the month, if my clickthroughs keep up,
which is more than I&#39;d hoped for.  I only hope that if everyone&#39;s seeing this
kind of performance, that Google makes some money at it and doesn&#39;t have to
cancel the program.
My only complain now is this:  Can I get some ad rotation?  I&#39;m not sure what
you&#39;re seeing, but I&#39;ve been looking at the same 4 ads for backup solutions
since I first plopped the code in.  At first I thought it was neat, since
I&#39;d been talking about backups at the time and the ads seemed an intelligent
complement.  But that story&#39;s long since scrolled off the page, and nothing
else interesing has come up since.  Maybe this is by design, but I expect
my clickthroughs to stop pretty soon.
Now, I have no ambitions to get rich quick via Google.  If they happen to
pay out enough to cover my hosting costs, I&#39;m abso-frickin-loutely
ecstatic.  So, I won&#39;t be spending
much time obsessing over search terms and &quot;borrowing&quot; public domain works to
boosting my ?AdSense revenue,
but it seems like the service could use a little freshening.
Am I missing something?
Update: Heh, funny thing.  No sooner do I post this and visit the site to
check out how things look, the Google ad appears to have rotated.
Is someone watching?  Heh, heh.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2003 14:33:36 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/29/google-ads-monotony/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/29/google-ads-monotony/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Desktops are better than laptops?</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;What I&#39;ve discovered, though, is that my desktop PC, for standard development tasks, is astoundingly faster than my work laptop for just about everything.

Source: rc3.org | Developing on my game box



Personally, though I really do want a new PowerMac G5 I can’t see myself investing much in desk-anchored computing anymore.  Not since I got my first laptop, and later my first wireless ethernet card.  What I can see myself doing, though, is maybe investing a little bit into a new PC for games, and maybe for a box with lots of storage and CPU power to stick in a closet somewhere and use via network.

&lt;p&gt;Sure, a dirt cheap box tied to the spot via a dozen cables should be able to smoke my lightweight personal computing device…  but what if I use that stationary box &lt;strong&gt;from remote&lt;/strong&gt; with that lightweight device?  It’s client/server all over again, but this time I own both the server and the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See… that’s where I &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; think it’s at. :)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2003 16:06:37 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/28/desktops-rock/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/28/desktops-rock/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Finding the RSS in Amazon searches</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Amazon.com Syndicated Content is delivered in RSS format. RSS is a standard format (in  XML) for delivering  content that changes on a regular basis. Content is delivered in small chunks, generally a synopsis, preview, or headline. Selected categories, subcategories and  search results in Amazon.com stores now have RSS feeds associated with them, delivering a headline-view of the top 10 bestsellers in that category or set of  search results.

Source: Amazon.com Syndicated Content  (via Silicon Valley - Dan Gillmor&#39;s eJournal - Amazon Does RSS, Officially)



This is very cool, though the feeds a little hard to find at first.  Don’t look for the orange XML or RSS buttons – use RSS autodiscovery to find the feed associated with a search.  (In other words, the URL will be in a link tag in the header of a search results page.)

&lt;p&gt;And though I don’t really want to stir up trouble, I find it strange that Amazon uses &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; v0.91, and that they link to &lt;i&gt;Netscape&lt;/i&gt; (an all but defunct entity) and not a spec hosted by UserLand or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecrimson.com/today/article348552.html&quot;&gt;Harvard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, at least they‘re providing feeds in &lt;strong&gt;some&lt;/strong&gt; format!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2003 18:59:13 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/26/amazon-rss/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/26/amazon-rss/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>HTTP/1.1 From header and FOAF use in RSS aggregators</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Privacy issues aside (for the moment), there is a request header called &quot;FROM&quot;, RFC 2616 s14.22 describes it. 




Now, it does say it should, if given, contain an Internet e-mail address for the human user who controls the requesting user agent.  SHOULD isn&#39;t MUST though, so what putting the user&#39;s homepage there?
It also says &quot;In particular, robot agents SHOULD include this header so that the person responsible for running the robot can be contacted if problems occur on the receiving end.&quot;
Source: eric scheid: Atom aggregator behavior (HTTP level) [dive into mark]



Ask a stupid question , get a smart answer .

&lt;p&gt;Last year, I thought it was a good idea to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/tech/old/oooahe.html&quot;&gt;abuse referers&lt;/a&gt; in order to leave footprints behind when I consume &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/span&gt; feeds.  Then, this past January, the abuse in the practice was revealed and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/tech/old/ooodoe.html&quot;&gt;using the User-Agent header&lt;/a&gt; was recommended for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, just for the hell of it, I &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintomark.org/archives/2003/07/21/atom_aggregator_behavior_http_level.html#c003136&quot;&gt;asked about the User-Agent header&lt;/a&gt; for use in the context over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diveintomark.org&quot;&gt;Mark’s place&lt;/a&gt; to see what responses I’d get.  The one that seemed most informative was from &lt;a href=&quot;http://IAwiki.net/EricScheid&quot;&gt;Eric Scheid&lt;/a&gt; as quoted above, referring me to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/Protocols/rfc2616/rfc2616-sec14.html#sec14.22&quot;&gt;the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;HTTP&lt;/span&gt;/1.1 spec, section 14.22&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per Eric’s comment and the spec, the value of a “From” header &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;SHOULD&lt;/span&gt; be an email address, but I would think that using a &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; wouldn’t be &lt;strong&gt;too&lt;/strong&gt; much an abuse of this header.  Seems like a good idea to stick either the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; to a blog here, or even better, stick the &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/span&gt; to your &lt;span class=&quot;caps&quot;&gt;FOAF&lt;/span&gt; file here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d really like to see this get built into aggregators as an option, though not turned on by defauilt for privacy’s sake.  I like the idea of leaving my name or a trail back to me at the doorstep of people whose feeds I’m reading, and I like the idea of standardizing the practice as cleanly as possible.  Using the “From” header seems to be the best option so far, versus header abuse and User-Agent overloading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man.  One of these days, I really have to get around to studying those specs in full, rather than just sporadically referencing them.  Thank goodness for smart guys like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diveintomark.org&quot;&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://IAwiki.net/EricScheid&quot;&gt;Eric&lt;/a&gt; (among others) who actually take the time to read these things and try to communicate the gist to the rest of us busy developers!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2003 21:00:37 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/23/from-foaf-rss/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/23/from-foaf-rss/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>This evening&#39;s sleep brought to me by science.</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;For a change, I feel awake today.
It&#39;s ironic that much of my writing in journals and much of my thought goes toward the topic of consciousness and thought itself.  I&#39;ve been studying and contemplating issues of cognition, awareness, and self for as long as I can remember.  I&#39;ve wolfed down self-help books and pop-psych in high school, went on to get a minor degree in psychology proper in college.  
I don&#39;t use drugs to tinker with my consciousness (other than caffeine, that is), but I&#39;ve tried various more controlled forms of meditation, visualization, and introspection.  I flirted with Dianetics &amp;amp; Scientology (but ran far, far away), employed psycho-cybernetics, got motivated by Anthony Robbins, twisted my inner eye around to see itself with the help of Douglas R. Hofstadter, studied concept-formation and knowledge ala Ayn Rand, considered the multiplicity of self with Marvin Minsky, and explored dreams and archetypes with C. G. Jung.  With the help of each influence, I&#39;ve been stitching together a rough manual to my mind.  Just like I&#39;ve hacked around with computing devices, I&#39;ve worked to understand and tweak my own mentality.  
Oh, but I probably need to explain the irony: For the past few months-- likely the past few years-- I&#39;ve been suffering from sleep apnea.  LIke my father, and his father before him, I&#39;ve developed a horrible snore and have started fighting a losing struggle with sleepiness.  My dad is known for falling asleep constantly: in the midst of conversation, while eating, while getting his haircut, while using a computer.  And lately, those have all been things that I&#39;ve begun to &quot;enjoy&quot;.  Especially bad has been my tendency to fall asleep at work, and especially dangerous has been me falling asleep whenever I have to drive for more than 10 minutes.
This condition seems to have come upon me so gradually that it&#39;s only been recently, with the scare of losing my new job, and missadroit&#39;s persistent persuasion, that I finally ackowledged the problem and sought treatment.  So, I managed to get an appointment at the University of Michigan Sleep Disorders Clinic, where one evening at the beginning of the month I was covered with wires and sent to bed.  About a week later, they called me back to inform me that I had very severe sleep apnea, and was barely getting any sleep at all in a night with about 2-3 breathless episodes per hour.
Within a few days of that news-- yesterday, in fact-- I was given a new toy: The REMstar Pro CPAP System.  After one night with the thing, my snoring is gone except for the occasional snort as I become accustomed to a breathing mask, and I feel quite a bit more rested than I have in recent memory.  I still feel a bit tired, but that&#39;s to be expected: I&#39;ve got many nights to catch up for.
I&#39;d gone from being able to track &quot;seven, plus or minus two&quot; things at once down to barely one thing at a time, and that was if I didn&#39;t doze off in the middle of the task and have to rebuild the thought process when I snapped back awake.  The irony of it all is similar to something I was reminded of last week: As it turns out, software needs hardware to run.  So, for all my introspective experimentation on myself, and all my attention to consciousness, I&#39;ve been feeling it slipping away from me lately.  As a &quot;software&quot; guy, I can&#39;t do much with my &quot;hardware&quot;.  
So, I&#39;m very happy that I finally-- after much denial and procrastination by me, and after much encouragement and tolerance by missadroit-- called and started the process that ended up with me sleeping through the night again.
And now maybe I can close my eyes and meditate without losing consciousness again.
Now maybe I can be myself again.
(P.S.:  Thank you, missadroit.  I love you and don&#39;t know what I&#39;d do without you.)&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2003 18:07:06 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/23/sleep-apnea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/23/sleep-apnea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Tap + Click = Two mouse buttons on a Mac trackpad?</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;I have my powerbook trackpad set to accept taps as mouse clicks, which makes the behavior identical to the button.
 
What I&#39;d like to do is set one of them to behave as a second mouse button. That sounds like it should be possible. All of the usual suspects have thus far failed me. I&#39;m surprised there isn&#39;t something on versiontracker -- it seems like it would be a popular hac
Source: osxhack: new powerbook - two button mouse from trackpad?



Sounds like a great idea to me.  Has it been done?  Or has someone realized that it’s actually a really bad idea for some reason I haven’t thought of?&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2003 11:57:15 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/22/two-track-buttons/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/22/two-track-buttons/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Textile + Wiki = ...?</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Yesterday, I downloaded Mark Pilgrim’s Python implementation of Textile and integrated it into the new hackish blog posting feature I added to my aggregator, and it works great.  Now, I want Textile in my wiki.  I google for it and don’t find much on wikis and Textile together.  I wonder how this could be most easily done?  In TWiki ? MoinMoin ? KWiki ?&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2003 00:56:41 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/18/textile-wiki/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/18/textile-wiki/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>&quot;It isn&#39;t working.&quot;</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;Words to strike terror into the heart of the home&#39;s designated computer geek...

Source: Caveat Lector: Iulii 13, 2003 – Iulii 19, 2003 Archives



This doesn’t happen to me at home, but it strikes terror into me whether I’m at work, visiting relatives, or mistaken for an employee at some computer store.  “It doesn’t work” always seems to be the introduction into a great, murky mystery which usually leads me into wishing I was either a mind reader or had a cluebat on me.  :)&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2003 16:53:46 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/18/not-working/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/18/not-working/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>As it turns out, software needs hardware to run.</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;RAM and motherboards are the least likely suspect in kernel panics, but if you just have a new system, and or just installed new memory and you get a kernel panic, that&#39;s the most likely place to start looking.  ... use the Hardware Test CD ...

Source: Mac OS X Kernel Panic FAQ





In my current job as jack-of-all-trades tech guy, I have to deal with everything.  Lately, it’s been a 15” PowerBook that’s been having random crashes and happily corrupting its hard drive.  Being a software guy, I run every program I can think of:  Disk First Aid, DiskWarrior, fsck.  Reinstalled Photoshop.  Then, tried wiping the machine and installing OS X, which was fine until the installer itself crashed. Kernel panic after kernel panic.  At one point, I considered consulting Eliza. 

&lt;p&gt;Turns out it was the memory.  We found this out by finally running the one bit of software that, as a software focused guy, I hadn’t even conceived of: The Hardware Diagnostics CD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2003 16:02:59 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/17/1058457401/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/17/1058457401/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Changes in my link blogging</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;You might notice a sudden rise in link-quote-comment entries around
here, depending on how well this works for my lazy self.  I just threw
together a quick bookmarklet and aggregator-integrated posting hack
for myself, hoping it will be as easy as BookmarkBlogger for noting
down URLs of interest throughout the day.  Nothing revolutionary,
just slightly new for me in daily use.
But, I was starting to wish that I could provide a little more info
around my posted links, such as why I was sharing the link and
from where I found it.  So, I&#39;ll be trying a slightly different
approach.  Let me know if it gets annoying.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2003 03:55:26 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/16/linkblog-changes/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/16/linkblog-changes/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>On tag uniqueness and versioning in Pie/Echo feeds</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&quot;feed&quot; is not a very unique name, and if another format were to come
along with the same top level element we would not be able to write a
format driver for it. Our architecture keys off the top-level
element. I suggest changing the top-level element to indicate the
format, and also add a version number so that aggregators can have an
idea of what spec the content provider is using. I imagine Radio is
not the only aggregator that would like to key off the name of the
top-level element.



Source:Radio UserLand: Radio gets some kind of Echo support







Nope, &quot;feed&quot; seems like a pretty poor choice as a name if the goal was
uniqueness in the tag name itself.  But, since we have XML namespaces
to ensure uniqueness between vocabularies, we can instead focus on a
clear and simple name that only needs to be unique within the
vocabulary.  And as for versioning, why not consider different
versions of a namespace to be entirely different vocabularies,
each with different namespaces?
I did some quick Googling and found the following:

... documents, containing multiple markup vocabularies, pose problems
of recognition and collision.  Software modules need to be able to
recognize the tags and attributes which they are designed to process,
even in the face of &quot;collisions&quot; occurring when markup intended for
some other software package uses the same element type or attribute
name.
These considerations require that document constructs should have
universal names, whose scope extends beyond their containing document.
This specification describes a mechanism, XML namespaces, which
accomplishes this.



Source:Namespaces in XML








One of the core features of XML is its ability to deal with changes in
the rules for data (hence the extensible in its name -- Extensible
Markup Language).  As changes are made to XML vocabularies, the
creation of multiple versions is inevitable.  This makes it necessary
to mark the versions clearly, for human and machine information.  The
clear marking of versions can be used for driving validation, or for
branch processing according to the requirements of each version.



You can mark the version of an XML vocabulary in many ways.  This
discussion focuses on the use of XML namespaces for marking versions.



Source:Tip: Namespaces and versioning







I haven&#39;t looked into RadioUserLand feed handling architecture,
but how difficult would it be to use the namespace and tag together
as key, rather than the tag alone?&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2003 17:36:50 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/12/echo-unique-namespaces/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/07/12/echo-unique-namespaces/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>