<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels and self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/</link>
      <item>
          <title>Next generation web apps using REST, XML, XSLT, and XmlHTTPRequest</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So, like I was saying:  I&amp;apos;ve been working on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/kwiki?FeedReactor&quot;&gt;FeedReactor&lt;/a&gt; and have been doing some things with it that I find rather interesting, independent of news aggregation.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the core goals I have for FeedReactor is to explore what it takes to build a web app that exploits &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xfront.com/REST-Web-Services.html&quot;&gt;principles of REST architecture&lt;/a&gt;.  Having already &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/tech/old/oooccb&quot;&gt;sung the praises&lt;/a&gt; of XML-RPC, I wanted to get immersed in REST and see what all the hubbub was about.  I&amp;apos;ve got some ways to go, but I think I understand the major concepts now, and it&amp;apos;s a pretty nifty frame within which to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, two other things I&amp;apos;ve added to my mix have really made things interesting for me:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;XSLT filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The XmlHTTPRequest object&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XSLT and REST make a really good pair, as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/2004/06/16/wishofthemonthclub1&quot;&gt;Amazon Web Services already demonstrate&lt;/a&gt;.  Inspired by that API (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/2003/09/02/xsl_scraper&quot;&gt;and earlier experiments&lt;/a&gt;), I use XML for all the input and output formats in my API and accept a query string parameter that contains the path to an XSLT file.  When this parameter is supplied, the XML output by the API is first processed using the given XSLT.  (Think of it like piping API output through &lt;code&gt;xsltproc&lt;/code&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with a properly constructed collection of XSLT, I can present a browser-viewable HTML user interface served up directly from REST API calls.  Links, frame sets, and iframes present in the HTML lead the user from that call to the next XSLT-wrapped REST API call. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, once the initial HTML-and-JavaScript payload reaches the browser, it gets better (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.infoworld.com/article/04/10/22/43OPstrategic_1.html&quot;&gt;ala Gmail&lt;/a&gt;):  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On older browsers (if I happen to care about them), I can make new HTTP requests back to the server &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/internet/webcontent/iframe.html&quot;&gt;from JavaScript using iframes&lt;/a&gt;.  In this case, XSLT filtering lets me retrofit the API&amp;apos;s responses to the HTML-and-JavaScript crud I need to serve up to make things happen back in the browser client.  Unfortunately, passing data &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; the API (which expects XML, not form submissions) is still a bit wonky and requires some hacks and exceptions involving hidden forms and such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on the newer browsers, it&amp;apos;s all about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.apple.com/internet/webcontent/xmlhttpreq.html&quot;&gt;XmlHTTPRequest object&lt;/a&gt;.  With this facility, I can make clean asynchronous requests back to the REST API, including XML data in the request body if I feel like it.  Responses are handled by JavaScript callbacks, which twiddle the browser DOM to update the user interface in response.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after the major initial contact with the API to supply the browser with HTML by way of XSLT, most future interactions take place in the form of direct calls to the REST API using XML.  Although for some things, it&amp;apos;s easier to just reload a page of HTML, it&amp;apos;s nicer for most interactions to be handled via DOM manipulations in-place.  I&amp;apos;ve been amazed at the Gmail-like responsiveness I get from FeedReactor when I&amp;apos;m skimming through news items, marking some as seen or flagged, and popping open the descriptions on others.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose I &lt;em&gt;shouldn&amp;apos;t&lt;/em&gt; be amazed at the responsiveness, since I&amp;apos;m using some of the same techniques as Gmail.  However, my daily-use installation of FeedReactor is presently running on an old 300Mhz Debian Linux PC at home, and it&amp;apos;s taking me through the daily produce of 600 subscribed feeds faster than any desktop aggregator has yet.  Of course, this is partly a product of my familiarity with the UI I&amp;apos;ve cobbled together, but... &lt;em&gt;the server&amp;apos;s running on a 300Mhz PC with 256MB of RAM!&lt;/em&gt;  And the client is my 867Mhz G4 PowerBook, running Firefox or Safari, depending on my mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I can&amp;apos;t see when I&amp;apos;ll have time for it, I really want to explore this approach further using desktop apps on OS X and accessing the API from Flash movies (maybe using &lt;a href=&quot;http://openlaszlo.org/&quot;&gt;Laszlo&lt;/a&gt;).  I&amp;apos;d also like to see how far I can go toward adapting the interface toward mobile devices like my Treo 600.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway, this has been where most of my private hacking sessions have been taking me over the past year or so:  combining HTML, CSS, DOM, JavaScript, XML, XSLT, and REST to build what I consider to be a next-generation web app.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, although I use FeedReactor on a daily basis to keep up with all my feeds, it&amp;apos;s nowhere near any state suitable for public consumption.  I add new subscriptions from a command-line script and still fiddle with the database directly for some operations.  I&amp;apos;d like to have a personal-server version of it ready for use by some alpha geeks before or not long into the new year, but I&amp;apos;d like to share some of the things I&amp;apos;ve been doing with it before then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that in mind, I think I&amp;apos;ll wrap up this entry and think about putting together a quick tutorial pico-project to demonstrate some of the concepts.  Maybe an address book, or something equally simple-yet-useful.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2004 21:53:35 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/11/30/nextgenwebapps/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/11/30/nextgenwebapps/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Pico-projects and Trepanation</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2004 18:41:06 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/11/30/pico-projects-and-trepanation/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/11/30/pico-projects-and-trepanation/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Early New Years&#39; Resolution</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;apos;s the last month of 2004 tomorrow, and it&amp;apos;s occurred to me that I haven&amp;apos;t spent much time around here.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing a quick check, it looks like I&amp;apos;ve written a little over 50 posts &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2004/&quot;&gt;this year&lt;/a&gt;, down from around 170 &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2003/&quot;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt;.  And the &lt;a href=&quot;/blog/2002/&quot;&gt;year before that&lt;/a&gt; was around 340.  Mainly, my activity around here has progressed toward much more link blogging using my own tools and, more recently, &lt;a href=&quot;http://del.icio.us&quot;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;.  When I actually have written something of my own lately, I&amp;apos;ve tended toward sweating over longer entries or nothing at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does all this mean I&amp;apos;m an ex-blogger?  Or was I ever?  On the other hand, who really cares?  Funny thing is, I&amp;apos;m sure I can find a few dozen entries I&amp;apos;ve written, self-flagellating about not writing more often.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I were to let you read from my handwritten journals, you&amp;apos;d find the same thing every few entries.  It seems I suffer from a strange complex of guilt and pedestal building: I feel guilty for not writing more, but then when I have something quick I could write, I feel guilty for not having something grander to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;apos;s also the fact that I had a really busy streak in my work-a-day life for awhile there, but for the past month or so I&amp;apos;ve mostly been lying fallow.  Now, I&amp;apos;m getting antsy to produce some &lt;strong&gt;Worthwhile Things&lt;/strong&gt; again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bah.  How about an early New Years&amp;apos; Resolution to follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/2004/09/22/bloggingyourbliss&quot;&gt;my own advice&lt;/a&gt; and let my brain dribble barely-worthy crap here on a more regular basis.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, how about I make this the last entry I write about not writing entries?  I&amp;apos;m sure I can come up with other topics about which to write when I can&amp;apos;t think of what to write.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2004 17:41:41 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/11/30/earlyresolution/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/11/30/earlyresolution/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>I ran out of costume ideas</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rasterweb.net/raster/200410.html#10272004091236&quot;&gt;Pete&lt;/a&gt;?  Where do I send the candy?  This one&amp;apos;s for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ipmradio.com/webcam/webcam_2004/103004_halloween/bobs/ipmradio0017.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/2004/11/02/ipod-halloween.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2004 20:18:48 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/11/02/ipodcostume/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2004/11/02/ipodcostume/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>