<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels and self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/</link>
      <item>
          <title>Partial stab at MoinMoin XML-RPC interface</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Uploaded a partial stab at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpcToWiki&quot;&gt;XmlRpcToWiki&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt;.  Have to figure out how to map enumerated versions to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt;&amp;apos;s style of diffs, have to update all the implementations with a few changes to the API spec in general.  But, I just wanted to get some things out there, even if they&amp;apos;re in progress.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2002 08:57:07 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/28/oooodb/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/28/oooodb/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Still playing with templates</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Tweaking around some fonts, layout, etc.  Silly me, I&amp;apos;ve been looking at all of this in Mozilla and haven&amp;apos;t touched IE in a week or two.  It wasn&amp;apos;t pretty when I checked it out there.  If anyone ran screaming from this site in funky horror after looking at it in IE, I offer my apologies.  Now if only I can get MT to stop doing funky things with apostrophes.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Working on the site design itself more, stripped away the frames (MT&amp;apos;s pings to weblogs.com didn&amp;apos;t like &amp;apos;em anyway), having more &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/SSI&quot;&gt;SSI&lt;/a&gt; fun, and generally trying to clean up the second level pages of the site (ie. individual story pages, etc.)  Next, I should be making pages to each individual category, if I can figure out what kind of seconday sidebar &amp;amp;etc I want on those pages.  Obviously something more understated than the major sidebar on the front page.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is fun, my first website to actually be up and doing something, even if no one&amp;apos;s paying attention yet :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2002 08:51:51 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/28/ooooda/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/28/ooooda/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>To Slashcode or not to SLashcode</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It seems like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.movabletype.org&quot;&gt;Movable Type&lt;/a&gt; does pretty much everything I want it to do for a weblog, and the upcoming &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.movabletype.org/2002_02_26.shtml#000224&quot;&gt;v2.0&lt;/a&gt; looks even better.  In one sense, I&amp;apos;m not satisfied with the fact that all it does it maintain a static set of pages rather than being a dynamic app...  but then I think, &lt;i&gt;do I really need anything more than that?&lt;/i&gt;  I mean, the one dynamic thing I have on the front page is the recent wiki changes, and that&amp;apos;s a server-side include (that almost seems retro to me).  Seems to work fine.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The main reason I have a tiny doubt is just having checked out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slashcode.com&quot;&gt;Slashcode&lt;/a&gt; again and remembering all the neato stuff it does, including its own &lt;a href=&quot;http://slashcode.com/article.pl?sid=02/02/27/1723205&amp;amp;mode=thread&amp;amp;tid=24&quot;&gt;wiki plugin&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://software.tangent.org/&quot;&gt;software.tangent.org&lt;/a&gt; uses Slashcode, but then they&amp;apos;re Slashcode contributors over there if I recall.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I could see MT choking if I had tons of content.  Say I update my site&amp;apos;s templates again and it has to rebuild &lt;i&gt;everything&lt;/i&gt;.  Eh, that&amp;apos;s a degenerate and least frequent case.  And I&amp;apos;ve got the source, so I could pry my content out of it if I had to.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As things are, the template system is dead simple, and I&amp;apos;ve started creating categories.  Everything &lt;i&gt;Just Works&lt;/i&gt;.  Maybe I&amp;apos;ll go drop a donation in their hat next week...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2002 01:59:33 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/27/oooodo/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/27/oooodo/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>More sites like this...</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hmm, looks like there&amp;apos;s a site over here at &lt;a href=&quot;http://software.tangent.org/&quot;&gt;TangentOrg&lt;/a&gt; that&amp;apos;s doing a lot of what I keep thinking I want to do with 0xDECAFBAD.  Looking for rolemodels.  If you&amp;apos;re out there (&lt;strong&gt;knocks on your screen&lt;/strong&gt;), can you point me to any other weblog-ish sites that are kinda about software, kinda about some dude (or dudette), and kinda about the &lt;i&gt;stuff&lt;/i&gt; that goes on out there?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;apos;m sure there&amp;apos;re plenty, but I&amp;apos;m looking for not just weblogs, but weblogs that spin off &lt;i&gt;things&lt;/i&gt; and make &lt;i&gt;stuff&lt;/i&gt; and other &lt;i&gt;crap&lt;/i&gt; that sticks around and gets improved, and all that.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Does this make any sense?  It&amp;apos;s time to go home.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2002 01:11:21 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/27/ooooci/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/27/ooooci/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>How to TiVOize your PC?  Been there, done that.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Hmm, does something like this fit into the &amp;quot;format&amp;quot; of 0xDECAFBAD?  Sure, but I&amp;apos;ll probably want to consider setting up some categories.  Like general tech rant/commentary, 0xDECAFBAD project updates, site updates, etc.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk&quot;&gt;The Register&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/content/54/24222.html&quot;&gt;How to &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/TiVO?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;TiVO&lt;/font&gt;-ize your PC&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;TiVO-like time shifting capabilities have come to the PC. At the Intel Developer Forum, Rakesh Agrawal, CEO of thirteen-man &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/SnapStream?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;SnapStream&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, took his PVS software through its paces for The Register&amp;apos;s pleasure.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;Is it just me, or are these people are slow?  Maybe it&amp;apos;s just because of the new release of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.snapstream.com&quot;&gt;SnapStream&lt;/a&gt; software (which I tried a few months ago, and hated, might be worth a try again), but people all over the blog world have been mentioning this as if it&amp;apos;s something new.  &amp;quot;TiVO killer on your PC!  Check this out!&amp;quot;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The only reason for it I could see is if the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.snapstream.com&quot;&gt;SnapStream&lt;/a&gt; software has improved incredibly since the last time I played with it, and it&amp;apos;s become so dead simple that my Mom can use it by making vague flappy gesticulations at the screen.  The only semi-exciting thing I see in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.snapstream.com&quot;&gt;SnapStream&lt;/a&gt; buzz is that they&amp;apos;re planning on doing something with .NET web services, but no one&amp;apos;s really talking about that facet of it.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Maybe they&amp;apos;ve all missed the availability of these products, but I&amp;apos;ve been using my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ati.com/na/pages/products/pc/aiw_radeon/index.html&quot;&gt;ALL-IN-WONDER? RADEON&lt;/a&gt; for the past year and a half, before which I used a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.riva3d.com/3500/&quot;&gt;Voodoo 3 3500TV&lt;/a&gt; (which sucked ass), and before &lt;i&gt;that&lt;/i&gt; I used a plain old &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ati.com/na/pages/products/pc/aiw/index.html&quot;&gt;ATI All-In-Wonder&lt;/a&gt; card.  That&amp;apos;s been since I got my first real PC in 1997.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;apos;ve been using these cards to record the few shows I care about, in limited fashion, until I got the Radeon card and things took off.  With the AIW Radeon, I record straight to VCD format.  I burn the VCD movies onto CDRW and watch them in my DVD player, just like I used to use my VCR.  If I happen to like the show, I burn it to a real CD and file it away.  It&amp;apos;s not the greatest quality, but is pretty comparable to VHS, which is fine.  If I want better quality, there&amp;apos;s Super VCD which uses MPEG-2 to fit 30 minutes of DVD-quality video on a CD.  Or...  &lt;strong&gt;gasp&lt;/strong&gt; I could get a DVD burner.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And then, there&amp;apos;s the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dlink.com/products/usb/dsbr100/&quot;&gt;D-Link DSB-R100 PC FM USB Radio&lt;/a&gt; I&amp;apos;ve been using to record and archive FM radio shows, most notably Big Sonic Heaven.  Oh yeah, and the Voodoo 3500TV was good for that, too.  (But mostly, it sucked.)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My digital lifestyle&amp;apos;s been kicking it for some time now.  Hell, not even Apple&amp;apos;s caught up to me yet, since I can&amp;apos;t find Mac-OS-X-supported replacements for my cable and FM radio archival rig.  If I had the money, I&amp;apos;d switch to 100% Apple in an eyeblink if they could seamlessly replace all the above.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Anyway.  I&amp;apos;m done now.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2002 19:50:21 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/27/ooooch/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/27/ooooch/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Where oh where did my little httpd go?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Brief server outage, swift support response from my friendly local host:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;i&gt;It is always something with that wretched httpd. Afew days ago it was a php exploit, preventing the restart of apache, and now this. All the pids which run under httpd must be killed, in order for a restart to take effect. This does not happen automatically, so I must kill them all, manually and with extreme vengence.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2002 20:23:17 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/26/oooocg/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/26/oooocg/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Almost done with another implementation of the Wiki XML-RPC API</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Hacked around tonight looking into the innards of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt;  and discovered that things are not all that bad in there.  I&amp;apos;ve got most of a  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt; rendition of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpcToWiki&quot;&gt;XmlRpcToWiki&lt;/a&gt; done.  I just have to figure out how to map the concept of numerical versions into editlog manipulations.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Whee, after this, that&amp;apos;ll be 3 wikis I&amp;apos;ve thrown this thing at.  No sweat.  Next, I have to &lt;i&gt;do something&lt;/i&gt; with it and prove that it hasn&amp;apos;t just been &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TechQuaTech&quot;&gt;TechQuaTech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2002 09:42:14 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/26/oooocf/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/26/oooocf/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>0xDECAFBAD is trying to find itself.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I doubt that I have much of an audience yet, still, so I suppose this will be just thinking out loud... but hey, that&amp;apos;s pretty much the express purpose of this site.  The historical context is useful, nonetheless.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Speaking of the purpose of this site: what about the purpose of this weblog?  Should this just be for general site news and calls-to-attention, or should I start all out nerdy musing about tech and what&amp;apos;s going on out there?  I&amp;apos;m thinking the latter, since any glance at the wiki&amp;apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RecentChanges&quot;&gt;RecentChanges&lt;/a&gt; will get you that.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I have a half-thought notion that I might enfold more people into 0xDECAFBAD eventually, so I&amp;apos;d like to keep the place from being &lt;i&gt;too&lt;/i&gt; centered on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/LesOrchard&quot;&gt;l.m.orchard&lt;/a&gt;, but seeing as I&amp;apos;m the only denizen here for now, it will be. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, maybe I should elucidate a bit within the site purpose up there in the corner.  This is a place for exposed thought processes about developing technologies.  Developing being used in a double meaning here-- both as an adjective and as verb.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The purpose of 0xDECAFBAD lies in both discussing the state of and participating in the process of technology building.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
How&amp;apos;s that?  Great.  (Suggest refinements, if you like.)  Now...  &amp;quot;technology&amp;quot; is a fairly broad topic.  &lt;i&gt;What&lt;/i&gt; technology, exactly?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Seeing as I am the sole dictator of the site&amp;apos;s direction so far, I will define this to be technologies that suit my fancy.  This, however is no definition-- it&amp;apos;s more of a redirection.  A see also.  So, what technologies, in particular?  Here&amp;apos;s a list off the cuff:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/Collaboration&quot;&gt;Collaboration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WritingOnTheWeb&quot;&gt;WritingOnTheWeb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/InformationManagement&quot;&gt;InformationManagement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;&amp;lt;a href=&quot; http: www.decafbad.com twiki bin view main knowledgemanagement&quot;&gt;KnowledgeManagement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;This probably needs some fleshing out.  In general, the focus is on web and internet tech with a lean toward that which enables human beings to work with information and each other.  Mainly, I&amp;apos;m interested in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/PowerToThePeople&quot;&gt;PowerToThePeople&lt;/a&gt; rather than &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/TechQuaTech&quot;&gt;TechQuaTech&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
How&amp;apos;s that for a start?
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2002 23:15:02 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/25/ooooce/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/25/ooooce/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Tweaking the Wiki, building APIs and bridges</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Even more twiddling.  Seriously thinking of moving &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WebHome&quot;&gt;the Wiki&lt;/a&gt; over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt; now that I&amp;apos;ve had a better look.  It seems to support almost all of the features I use with TWiki, but looks to have a much cleaner design.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Did some poking tonight, and it looks like I could have yet another implementation of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpcToWiki&quot;&gt;XmlRpcToWiki&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt;.  That would bring me up to a total of 3 supported wikis.  After that, I just need to keep them all in synch with the API as it shapes up over on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ecyrd.com/JSPWiki/Wiki.jsp?page=WikiRPCInterface&quot;&gt;JspWiki&lt;/a&gt; site.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After I get the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpcToWiki&quot;&gt;XmlRpcToWiki&lt;/a&gt; implemented for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt;, I can work on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WikiWikiBridge&quot;&gt;WikiWikiBridge&lt;/a&gt; between TWiki and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt; to execute the conversion of content for migration.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The side effect of moving to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt; in this way is that I&amp;apos;ll end up with 3 wiki engines speaking XML-RPC, and one bridge between engines.  Sounds like fun to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2002 09:48:29 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/25/oooocd/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/25/oooocd/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Trying out a new site layout</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Thinking that simple is better here, so I tossed out the big vertical sidebar navigation for a much simpler nav bar at the bottom.  Also playing around with putting wiki changes in the sidebar.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Any thoughts?  I think I&amp;apos;ll stop twiddling with that for now and play around with getting a few more things released.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Okay, maybe one more tweak.  This is not exactly like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/OutOfBox&quot;&gt;out-of-box&lt;/a&gt; Movable Type, but hopefully not annoying.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2002 02:20:04 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/oooocb/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/oooocb/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Testing out BlogChat:</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing out &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/BlogChat?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;BlogChat&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  Any suggestions on where I might put this?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; src=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blogchat/anybodyhome.php&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2002 00:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/ooooca/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/ooooca/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Second verse, same as the</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Second verse, same as the first.  Everybody sing!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2002 10:16:10 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/ooooco/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/ooooco/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Testing my new MT template.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing my new MT template.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2002 10:15:04 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/oooobi/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/oooobi/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>It&amp;apos;s quiet. Too quiet. Actually,</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Actually, I have been doing quite a bit.  here&amp;apos;s a quick update:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I had a go at doing something cool with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/CommentsInRadioUserland&quot;&gt;CommentsInRadioUserland&lt;/a&gt;, but I don&amp;apos;t think very many people noticed my hacky iframe tricks before a more elegant solution was baked into Radio.  Well, &lt;i&gt;I&lt;/i&gt; thought it was cool. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I released the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/XmlRpcToWiki&quot;&gt;XmlRpcToWiki&lt;/a&gt; for two Wikis, TWiki and &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/UseModWiki?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;UseModWiki&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  I&amp;apos;m aiming for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt; next, and I might even be nutty and convert from TWiki to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MoinMoin&quot;&gt;MoinMoin&lt;/a&gt; for usage here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started doing the dogfood thing and have been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/MailToRSS&quot;&gt;MailToRSS&lt;/a&gt; (based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/Caffinate&quot;&gt;Caffinate&lt;/a&gt;) on a daily basis in my Radio &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/UserLand&quot;&gt;UserLand&lt;/a&gt; feed.  Seems pretty useful.  Going to clean a few things up, upload some files, and bump those two projects up into the &amp;quot;Available&amp;quot; category and make a release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I ripped the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WebHome&quot;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt;&amp;apos;s style-sheet off and went back to plain old, unadulterated default style.  I might try again with a few tweaks, but best to let wikis be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking I&amp;apos;m going to set aim on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/WeblogMulticaster&quot;&gt;WeblogMulticaster&lt;/a&gt; next.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
I&amp;apos;ll have more to write soon.
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2002 09:24:13 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/oooobh/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/24/oooobh/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>And another thing: on UNIX-y development</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;apos;s worth noting that I&amp;apos;m trying a change in approach now to get my hacking morale up.  I&amp;apos;m adopting a more UNIX-y approach and planning to write and release a number of smaller, interoperating utilities at first.  They should be really easy to pipe together, like cat | grep | more.  They should, at first, run just fine on my laptop Apache installation or out on the 0xDECAFBAD servers.  Eventually I might write the overarching &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/DesktopWebAppServer&quot;&gt;DesktopWebAppServer&lt;/a&gt; that provides another shell within which they can reside, but I have to get away from my year-long hermitage arcs of development where I make really cool things and get 75% of the way done and then abandon them.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Okay.  Nevermind work, it&amp;apos;s time to go home.  Wheee!
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;(Grr, and &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/TextRouter?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;TextRouter&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt; keeps &amp;quot;helpfully&amp;quot; escaping all my HTML tags with entities.  Have to do more digging to work out how to stop that.)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2002 01:16:39 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/18/oooobb/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2002/02/18/oooobb/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>