<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: writing - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/writing/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Quoting Ashley Willis</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ashley Willis, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ashley.dev/posts/fear-of-being-seen/&quot;&gt;Working Through the Fear of Being Seen&lt;/a&gt;&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I don’t need to be prolific. Maybe I don’t need to impress anyone. Maybe I just need to show up. Write what’s on my mind. Share the small things. Even if they’re messy. Even if they’re quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I know I’m not the only one who feels like this. I know I’m not the only one trying to find their way back to something they used to love. I know I’m not the only one wondering where their confidence went.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m not exactly where she is, but I think I&#39;m in the neighborhood. I&#39;m posting a bunch of little random stuff right now, hoping to keep the channel open in case something good tumbles through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 03:46:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/quoting-ashley-willis/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/quoting-ashley-willis/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Generating documentation for my Easy-Blog Oven with Claude</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;I asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/claude/sonnet&quot;&gt;Claude 3.7 Sonnet&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://aider.chat/&quot;&gt;Aider&lt;/a&gt; to take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/tree/main/lib&quot;&gt;the core libraries&lt;/a&gt; for my Easy-Blog Oven and to try drafting a quick user manual for it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/MANUAL.md&quot;&gt;I think the result is actually not bad at all&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aider tells me it cost about US$0.17 in API credits. It caught all the major quirky features I&#39;ve hacked into the system over the years. I only made one or two minor edits before checking it into the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been meaning to write something like this for myself for years, if only to remind myself how it all works after long periods of neglect. It&#39;s a boring task and one of those things I&#39;d most likely never get around to—especially not for one of my own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also one of those kinds of things &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/13/thinking-about-llms/&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve been reticent to write about&lt;/a&gt;, anticipating negative feedback. But, it really is kind of neat and I found it personally useful. I can totally see the value in this kind of thing, when packaged up in friendlier UX for other folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 21:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/generating-documentation-for-my-easyblog-oven-with/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/generating-documentation-for-my-easyblog-oven-with/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-09</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Been watching &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lCuoUSDBVa&quot;&gt;Resurrecting Sinistar: A Cyber-Archaeology Documentary&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, which has been great. Played Sinistar last at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.retrogamingexpo.com/&quot;&gt;Portland Retro Gaming Expo&lt;/a&gt; in October and was digging the heck out of it. They squeezed so much out of that 8-bit processor - I guess it had a multitasking system that could handle like over 100 game entities? In 1983?! The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/synamaxmusic/sinistar&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; has actually surfaced, so you can see how they did it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was starting to do &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/tag/weeknotes/&quot;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, this month. But, this week, I decided what I really wanted to do was just blog more. So, that got me started hacking on my blog software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m just going to deploy these changes to the blog. Some things might be broken, but I&#39;ll fix them as I go. I want to start actually using the thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking I&#39;ll start each day off with a miscellanea entry like this one and fill it full of little bullets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe I&#39;ll start spawning little entries for bookmarks and quotes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the main things I&#39;m thinking about with all this hackery and ASCII art is whether I&#39;ll be able to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; with all these files in 10 - 20 years&#39; time. Granted, I&#39;ll be pushing 70, so maybe I won&#39;t care by then?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But, the writing is the important part to me. I could write a whole new blog publisher from scratch and still read all the file formats. I&#39;ve done that a couple times now and I can still handle stuff I wrote back in 2002. I think that&#39;s pretty cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And here I am, attempting to blog from Obsidian on my phone? Is this the future?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next thing I need to work out is how to upload and display images via Obsidian on my phone. I think it&#39;s very doable, just a few more bits of Rube Goldberg crud to slot into place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve been asked to write up how this whole mess works - that might be a thing I&#39;ll do this weekend in greater detail. It really is an accumulation of random little parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dang, now that I have this easy channel from my brain into my blog, I&#39;m feeling like a motormouth. I&#39;ll probably settle down, soon enough. I&#39;m always giddy with a new toy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Blogging elsewhere than into the void</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;The thing about blogging -  and why I want to do more of it and more often - is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.henrikkarlsson.xyz/p/search-query&quot;&gt;a blog post is a very long and complex search query to find fascinating people and make them route interesting stuff to your inbox&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s why I used to blog so much, back before Twitter ate my brain. It actually brought me good fortune and favorable outcomes - friends, acquaintances, writing opportunities, job interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&#39;m posting just the occasional too-long-didn&#39;t-read entry, I&#39;m not getting many hits returning from my search queries these days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That could just be because no one reads blogs at all, these days. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2024/03/11/dance-for-the-bots/&quot;&gt;Except bots, maybe.&lt;/a&gt; Still, I don&#39;t think my few shots at posting have been interesting enough to justify the time to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might get more hits if I can better balance frequency, length, and interestingness. And I think I can write more often if I write shorter things. As for the interestingness part - well, I think I just need more &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shot_on_goal_(ice_hockey)&quot;&gt;shots on goal&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to see what lands, rather than put forth a bunch of effort on one thing that lands to the sound of crickets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of sounds like I&#39;m ruminating on some &quot;engagement hacks&quot; - kind of icky and I guess a product of my marketing-tech-poisoned brain. But also, I would actually like to connect with folks and not just shout into the void. I also really like writing and would like to find ways to work with my ADHD brain to make it happen more often in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 20:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/blogging-elsewhere-than-into-the-void/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/blogging-elsewhere-than-into-the-void/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>New blog, a lot like the old blog, but more of it</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years now, I&#39;ve wanted to turn this blog into a place to write Big Serious Entries with fancy layouts and lots of words &amp;amp; images. I thought that would get me somewhere interesting. But, it turns out, that&#39;s a pretty heavy squelch filter on getting things out of my brain and onto the web. I just don&#39;t have the energy or follow-through to come up with Big Serious Entries all that often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I do have is a lot of little things that I could let tumble out of my ADHD brain. I used to do more of that here - but since the advent of Twitter, way back in 2006, I allowed most of that to be shunted over there. And when I finally abandoned Twitter in 2022, that brain spew more fully moved to &lt;a href=&quot;https://masto.hackers.town/@lmorchard&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except, not entirely. Twitter and Mastodon are mostly good for tiny things. Not medium or long things. Or things that start small and grow with further thought throughout a day or a week. My blog could be good at that, though. So, I&#39;m reworking the layout and how I can write entries to better accomodate that and dovetail into my habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the way &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison&lt;/a&gt; run their blogs. They riff throughout the day with notions of various length and format - sometimes as short as a toot and sometimes expanding out into full essays. They&#39;ve both done this for years and years, and they&#39;ve done well at it. So, I&#39;m going to shamelessly steal some of their ideas and plonk them down here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I&#39;m also going to try a few of my own ideas. Like, Simon runs his blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/simonw/simonwillisonblog&quot;&gt;as a Django app&lt;/a&gt; and Dave &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=about&quot;&gt;writes in OPML&lt;/a&gt;. Personally, I like my &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2020/05/24/easy-blog-oven/index.html&quot;&gt;Easy-Blog Oven&lt;/a&gt; and I like writing in Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I don&#39;t like is tediously opening a new Markdown file every time I might have a wild idea, though. That&#39;s a thing that Dave&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.opml.org/&quot;&gt;OPML Editor&lt;/a&gt; had going for it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20061003021452/http://blogs.opml.org/decafbad/&quot;&gt;back when I blogged with it&lt;/a&gt;: You opened one outline for the whole day and just let ideas tumble into it over the hours. (Hmm, I want a screenshot here. I need to figure out how to paste one in.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, my stand-in for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.opml.org/&quot;&gt;OPML Editor&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. In some ways, it&#39;s more cumbersome for outlining than OPML, but it does other things I like. So, I&#39;ve come up with this goofy file format to open just one file per day and compose multiple entries in that file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s markdown, but if I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/content/posts/2025/2025-05-09.md?plain=1#L15&quot;&gt;start a line with ASCII-art scissors (i.e. &lt;code&gt;8&amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/a&gt; then my Easy-Blog Oven &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/lib/posts.js#L140-L156&quot;&gt;will chop that file up&lt;/a&gt; into separate entries. I can also include a bit of JSON in there for post metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No entry in the file is final, things may expand and contract and bud off into new entries over time. I&#39;ll probably let them alone after midnight, though. That might cause some churn in my RSS feeds, so I may eventually set them to a 24-hour delay. I don&#39;t know, I&#39;m still thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I get really ambitious, I&#39;ll rig up some machinery to automatically publish as I write in an Obsidian tab. But, that&#39;s some hackery for the days ahead. For now, I just want to get these changes pushed out into the world before I wander off after something else shiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Edit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/script/publish-posts-from-obsidian.sh&quot;&gt;I wrote a script that runs in a cronjob that pushes my edits from Obsidian to GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. That&#39;s all it really took, just one more sproingy bit atop the Rube Goldberg machine.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 19:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/new-blog-a-lot-like-the-old/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/new-blog-a-lot-like-the-old/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Been doing a lot of (hand)writing outside my blog</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just realized today that I&#39;ve written my 359th three-page week-daily handwritten journal entry on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.boox.com/collections/all/products/tabultrac&quot;&gt;BOOX Tab Ultra C e-ink tablet&lt;/a&gt;. I&#39;ve also got paper volumes going back to 2017 with similar cadence. That&#39;s a lot of writing that no one but me will probably ever read. But, I do read it, occasionally, to sort myself out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve got a back-burnered side project to train a handwriting recognition model to actually convert my journal entries to text. I should get back to that. No off-the-shelf model has yet been able to successfully decipher my script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve also got a notion, once I&#39;ve converted my journals, to try feeding them to an LLM - either as a fine-tuned model or searching via RAG. Then, I could maybe pull themes and trends out of my past writing and ask annoying questions of my insufferable past self.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/been-doing-a-lot-of-handwriting-outside/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/been-doing-a-lot-of-handwriting-outside/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Dance like the bots aren&#39;t watching?</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: Why bother sharing anything on the open web if it&#39;s just going to be fodder for extractive, non-reciprocal bots?&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2024/03/11/dance-for-the-bots/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2024/03/11/dance-for-the-bots/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>There are no ushers on Mastodon</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: There are no ushers on Mastodon. There&#39;s no one paid to show you to your seat, no one whose job it is to ease you into comfort and remove friction.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/11/07/no-ushers/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/11/07/no-ushers/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Twitter, or social cowardice as a service</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: Yeah, yeah, I&#39;m navel gazing about Twitter over here.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/28/twitter/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/28/twitter/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>5:00am is the enemy</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/07/5am-is-the-enemy/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/07/5am-is-the-enemy/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>My summer spent avoiding a writing habit</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/01/my-summer-avoiding-a-writing-habit/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/01/my-summer-avoiding-a-writing-habit/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Writing Habit Recap No. 3</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR:  I&#39;d meant to do these recap posts every week. But, oops: it&#39;s been a month since the last one. Now that I sit down to write this, though, I think I&#39;ve done more than I thought.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/06/12/writing-habit-recap-no-3/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/06/12/writing-habit-recap-no-3/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Writing Habit Recap No. 2</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR:  I&#39;ve gotten through over a month of writing posted here. I thought it might be worth reflecting and recapping again.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/05/15/writing-habit-recap-no-2/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/05/15/writing-habit-recap-no-2/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Writing Habit Recap No. 1</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: I&#39;ve gotten through twenty days of writing posted here. I thought it might be worth recapping the last few things I managed to post.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/05/01/writing-recap-no-1/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/05/01/writing-recap-no-1/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Building a New Creative Writing Habit</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: I&#39;m trying to build a new creative writing habit. The immediate form that this has taken is a goal of writing 300 words of fiction per day that I post to my blog. I&#39;ve been using 3-card spreads from a Tarot deck to supply writing prompts. I&#39;m hoping I keep it up.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/04/20/building-a-new-creative-writing-habit/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/04/20/building-a-new-creative-writing-habit/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>