<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: Header - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />      
      <item>
          <title>Trying out a new site layout</title>
          <description>Thinking that simple is better here, so I tossed out the big vertical sidebar navigation for a much simpler nav bar at the bottom.  Also playing around with putting wiki changes in the sidebar.

Any thoughts?  I think I&#39;ll stop twiddling with that for now and play around with getting a few more things released.

Okay, maybe one more tweak.  This is not exactly like out-of-box Movable Type, but hopefully not annoying.</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2002 02:20:04 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/25/oooocb/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/25/oooocb/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Testing out BlogChat:</title>
          <description>Testing out ?BlogChat.  Any suggestions on where I might put this?</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2002 00:25:52 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/25/ooooca/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/25/ooooca/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Second verse, same as the</title>
          <description>Second verse, same as the first.  Everybody sing!</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2002 10:16:10 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/24/ooooco/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/24/ooooco/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>It&amp;apos;s quiet. Too quiet. Actually,</title>
          <description>Actually, I have been doing quite a bit.  here&#39;s a quick update:

I had a go at doing something cool with CommentsInRadioUserland, but I don&#39;t think very many people noticed my hacky iframe tricks before a more elegant solution was baked into Radio.  Well, I thought it was cool. :)
I released the XmlRpcToWiki for two Wikis, TWiki and ?UseModWiki.  I&#39;m aiming for MoinMoin next, and I might even be nutty and convert from TWiki to MoinMoin for usage here.
Started doing the dogfood thing and have been using MailToRSS (based on Caffinate) on a daily basis in my Radio UserLand feed.  Seems pretty useful.  Going to clean a few things up, upload some files, and bump those two projects up into the &quot;Available&quot; category and make a release.
I ripped the Wiki&#39;s style-sheet off and went back to plain old, unadulterated default style.  I might try again with a few tweaks, but best to let wikis be.
Thinking I&#39;m going to set aim on the WeblogMulticaster next.
I&#39;ll have more to write soon.</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2002 09:24:13 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/24/oooobh/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/24/oooobh/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>And another thing: on UNIX-y development</title>
          <description>It&#39;s worth noting that I&#39;m trying a change in approach now to get my hacking morale up.  I&#39;m adopting a more UNIX-y approach and planning to write and release a number of smaller, interoperating utilities at first.  They should be really easy to pipe together, like cat | grep | more.  They should, at first, run just fine on my laptop Apache installation or out on the 0xDECAFBAD servers.  Eventually I might write the overarching DesktopWebAppServer that provides another shell within which they can reside, but I have to get away from my year-long hermitage arcs of development where I make really cool things and get 75% of the way done and then abandon them.

Okay.  Nevermind work, it&#39;s time to go home.  Wheee!

(Grr, and ?TextRouter keeps &quot;helpfully&quot; escaping all my HTML tags with entities.  Have to do more digging to work out how to stop that.)</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2002 01:16:39 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/19/oooobb/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/19/oooobb/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Wanted: A non-ugly stylesheet</title>
          <description>Oh yeah, and though I&#39;m pretty sure I&#39;m blogging into the void right now, would anyone out there happen to have some tips on how to make my site less ass ugly? :)  I&#39;ve just co-opted the Movable Type out-of-box style, but I think I&#39;ll need to move on from that eventually...</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2002 01:10:15 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/19/ooooba/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/19/ooooba/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Blew the dust off the BBS</title>
          <description>It&#39;s been up for 49 days and has served about 8 people.  It&#39;s running on a crappy lil 70Mhz HP Vectra PC I found in the dumpster. 

It&#39;s 0xDECAFBAD BBS, my telnet BBS running Synchronet BBS!

Call on in, either via Java applet on the web (http://bbs.decafbad.com) or via direct telnet (telnet://bbs.decafbad.com:2323)  But, it would sure be lots of useless old-school fun to get people playing on here :)

I haven&#39;t done a whole lot of work on it yet, other than putz around with an ANSI logo, and a few hours&#39; nostalgic gathering and installing of BBS Door games (Legend of the Red Dragon, anyone?)

Let&#39;s see how long I can go before Comcast finds it and shuts me down, whee!</description>
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2002 18:35:09 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/15/ooooai/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2002/02/15/ooooai/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>