<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: ux - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/ux/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Beyond Text-only AI</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fatih Kadir Akın, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.fka.dev/blog/2025-05-16-beyond-text-only-ai-on-demand-ui-generation-for-better-conversational-experiences/&quot;&gt;Beyond Text-Only AI: On-Demand UI Generation for Better Conversational Experience&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if AI systems could generate precisely the right interface components when needed, without requiring developers to build every possible UI variation in advance? This post explores my work on a new prototype that enables LLMs to create dynamic, interactive UI components on demand, transforming how users interact with AI systems and MCP servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where LLMs are very interesting to me, where applications with them are most able to escape hype into practical building. A thing they&#39;re good at is taking some of the vague stuff we hand-wave at like &quot;you know, that thing with the days in squares on it&quot; and jumping to &quot;you mean a calendar?&quot; But then, skip straight from that to presenting a calendar for input as part of the workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;m finding LLMs most handy when they work in smaller universes. Give it a relatively small inventory of UI components, properly described with context, and they can be great at picking which one to use and when. Hard to hallucinate when there&#39;s not a wide range for wandering, easy to mitigate what hallucinations might occur when you can automatically kick it back into bounds. Meanwhile, the workflow can feel more smooth and demand less fiddly navigation from a user. That seems like a really promising glimmer to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 22:28:39 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/beyond-text-only-ai/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/beyond-text-only-ai/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Quoting Katie Parrott</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Katie Parrott, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://every.to/working-overtime/it-s-me-hi-i-m-the-vibe-coder&quot;&gt;It’s Me, Hi. I’m the Vibe Coder.&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then there are people like me, who aren’t chasing entry into the engineer club or a seven-figure seed round. We&#39;re writers, designers, business owners, and domain experts motivated by specific problems we deeply understand, &lt;a href=&quot;https://every.to/chain-of-thought/you-re-a-developer-now&quot;&gt;empowered by AI tools&lt;/a&gt; that finally &lt;a href=&quot;https://every.to/podcast/how-to-win-with-prompt-engineering&quot;&gt;speak our language&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vibe coding hints at a future where software emerges from the inside out—from the people closest to the problems. As AI lowers the technical barrier, we may see more tools built by marketers, editors, researchers—anyone with deep context and a persistent itch to fix things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of thing is very exciting to me. While &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/13/thinking-about-llms/&quot;&gt;I think&lt;/a&gt; vibe coding is currently flawed &amp;amp; fraught for folks who don&#39;t entirely understand the code, I agree with Simon Willison that &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/2025/Mar/19/vibe-coding/#let-s-not-lose-track-of-what-makes-vibe-coding-special&quot;&gt;everyone deserves the ability to automate tedious tasks in ther lives with computers&lt;/a&gt;&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a lot of hype and cynicism in tension out there. But, I&#39;ve personally cycled through a bunch of AI tools in the past few years. I&#39;ve seen their actual utility and glimmers of where they can go next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to stay sober here, but I&#39;d love to see more tools meet users where they are and lower the technical bar overall. I think it&#39;s both possible and worth it to work toward improving the capability &amp;amp; reliability of these tools for folks outside of the programming &quot;priesthood&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 20:18:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/quoting-katie-parrott/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/quoting-katie-parrott/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>