<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com</link>
      <item>
          <title>Getting a Strange &quot;Component Manager&quot; Message Under OS X?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Posting this just in case anyone needs it.  I&#39;ve been getting the
following strange message lately in logs and consoles under OS X:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;pre&gt;## Component Manager: attempting to find symbols in a component alias of type (regR/carP/x!bt)&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As it turns out, I had just installed Toast.  A quick Google search
leads me to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mail-archive.com/cocoa-dev@lists.apple.com/msg09330.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;blame Toast and remove a QuickTime component supporting Video CD&lt;/a&gt;.
That&#39;s pretty obscure.  Hmph.  So much for never again worrying about strange drivers and
cryptic error messages under OS X.  :)
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2003 18:22:57 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/30/strange-component-error/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/30/strange-component-error/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>iTunes Does Indeed Do DRM</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;How unobservant am I?  It took 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theregister.co.uk/content/6/30458.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;an article from The Register&lt;/a&gt;
to make me realize that this new Apple music store does indeed
use DRM to lock up purchased music.  The files aren&#39;t mine.  (Though, whoopie, I&#39;m 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.info.apple.com/article.html?artnum=93014&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;allowed to use them on up to 3 computers&lt;/a&gt;.)
Crap.  No thanks.  I guess
that 10% of the catalog doesn&#39;t look quite so attractive at a buck-a-song now.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I mean, I&#39;ve already destroyed one computer 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/misc/thirsty_ibook.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;with a tumbler of water&lt;/a&gt;, why would
I want to lose all my music with the next one I douse?  And what happens in 10
years or so, when I want to listen to all those hypothetical Talking Heads
tunes I bought?  Of course, I&#39;m still listening to CDs and tapes I acquired back
in junior high, and I don&#39;t need to query anyone&#39;s permission to do so.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I hereby bestow this award to the Apple Music Store:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scotlandsoftware.com/blog/?post=/personal/bah.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.scotlandsoftware.com/images/bah.png&quot; border=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2003 23:10:37 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/29/itunes-does-drm/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/29/itunes-does-drm/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>What is my iSync doing?</title>
          <description>&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/downloads/isync-bookmarks.gif&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; vspace=&quot;8&quot; hspace=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
Umm...  what is iSync doing?  I didn&#39;t know that it had anything to do
with my bookmarks.  Lately I&#39;ve been using bookmarks more since I started
using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/BookmarkBlogger&quot;&gt;BookmarkBlogger&lt;/a&gt;.  Nearly every time I try dragging a bookmark into a
toolbar folder, though, I&#39;m rebuffed by this dialog.  What gives?  The bookmarks
don&#39;t show up on my PDA, or my calendar.  With what are they being synched?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I see that &lt;a href=&quot;http://birdhouse.org/blog/archives/000810.php&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Scot Hacker&lt;/a&gt; has
discovered the same thing happening to him.  Lots of comments, but still no
answer as to what&#39;s up with this.  Hmm.
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2003 20:24:56 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/29/isync-bookmarks-huh/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/29/isync-bookmarks-huh/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Indie Music Service (ala Apple)?</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Okay, so in between all the other hecticity currently ongoing in my life,
I managed to check out Apple&#39;s new music service.  Although I&#39;m not interested
in approximately 90% of the music offered so far, that still leaves me with
2000 songs whose &quot;buy&quot; buttons call my name.  The process is simple, the files
are mine and not locked up with DRM, and although I hope and expect the price
structure to change (ie. maybe price based on popularity?), a dollar a song
isn&#39;t horrendous considering that I get what I want on demand and without 
hopping in the car and going anywhere.  So far, so good.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So...  This got me to thinking in the last 10 minutes:  What about an indie
clone of the Apple Music Service?  One using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RDF&quot;&gt;RDF&lt;/a&gt; or some other XML format to
offer up the catalogues of record labels?  Include all artists, albums, songs,
and any various and sundry bits of trivia about all the above.  Establish a
modular mechanism for specifying payment process (ie. paypal, credit card,
free, upload a song), and make the whole interface as slick and easy as
iTunes&#39;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The real trick I see in this, though, is to make the file format for music
vendors fairly easy yet flexible.  It should be as easy or easier than an
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; feed for a blog.  Let a hundred of these mushrooms bloom, aggregate, 
search, and buy.  Make it distributed and not dependant on any particular
music company or technology company.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Not a terribly original idea, but that&#39;s what I just thought of.  Sounds
like a good semantic web app that could have some umph going for it in
the immediate future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2003 12:28:02 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/29/rdf-tunes/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/29/rdf-tunes/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>rsync: It&#39;s a damn brilliant thing.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I take rsync for granted.  It&#39;s just the best way to keep stuff &lt;i&gt;out there&lt;/i&gt;
up to date with stuff &lt;i&gt;over here&lt;/i&gt;, and vice versa.  And lately, I&#39;ve been
using it to supplant my usage of &lt;code&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt;.  And it works.  Brilliantly.  And until
recently, I hadn&#39;t stopped to realize:  Hey, you know, this thing somehow works
out differences between files &lt;i&gt;out there&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;over here&lt;/i&gt; long &lt;i&gt;before&lt;/i&gt;
what&#39;s &lt;i&gt;here&lt;/i&gt; gets &lt;i&gt;there&lt;/i&gt;.  I know, duh, but I just hadn&#39;t considered it.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Well,
&lt;a href=&quot;http://weblog.bluepenguin.us/archives/2003/04/22/rsync_one_of_the_wonders_of_the_cs_world.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Paul Holbrook reminded me&lt;/a&gt;
of this tonight, with links to &lt;a href=&quot;http://samba.anu.edu.au/~tridge/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Andrew Tridgell&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
paper on the algorithm, among other things.  Damn, things like this remind me
that I&#39;m supposed to be getting my butt back into school...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2003 03:00:25 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/23/wonders-of-rsync/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/23/wonders-of-rsync/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Learning How to Do Magic with Flash and XML</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Was thinking about learning new tech, and well, I haven&#39;t gotten much
farther into .NET
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/tech/dot_net_newbie.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;as I&#39;d wanted to&lt;/a&gt;,
given moving and a sudden appearance of work.  Instead, I&#39;ve had
a project hurled at me that combines Flash MX and XML, something I&#39;ve
just barely touched before.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Wow, is this stuff fun.  And I write that without a trace of sarcasm--
this app I&#39;ve inherited for maintenance and extension, though it&#39;s a
bit grungy and shows some signs of late-night expediency, does some
neat things with actions and buttons dynamically wired up in response
to XML config files loaded via URL, which are in turn generated from a
database managed by a simple end-user admin interface.  Not sure how
much more I should write about it, but I&#39;m dying to post a link.  Of
course, this isn&#39;t revolutionary stuff in general.  It&#39;s just a revelation
to me.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The last time I had an opportunity to really, really dig around in
Flash was just about when Flash 5 came out.  I was immersed daily in
Flash in the years between the initial acquisition by Macromedia, up
through version 4, and just started drifting away, sadly, when things
started getting really interesting with v5.  That was when my daily
job swung entirely into the backend, and client-side concerns were
no longer my task.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But now I&#39;m back in this old neighborhood, and I can see why some
people would love nothing better but to build entire websites in
Flash.  Yeah, that&#39;s evil, but it&#39;s sexy.  Despite some clunkiness,
there are some very nice possibilities I see now.  I love Java, and
loved cobbling together funky applets 5 years or so ago, but Flash
makes me want to toy with rich client-side apps again.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And then, there&#39;s this
&lt;a href=&quot;http://sonyelectronics.sonystyle.com/micros/clie/models/tg50.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Sony Clie PEG-TG50&lt;/a&gt;
handheld I&#39;ve recently started pining for, and it appears to run a
Flash 5 player.  It&#39;s probably underwhelming, but who knows?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Anyway, back to work, but just had to spill some enthusiasm for
Flash.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2003 16:22:50 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/22/flash-xml-magic/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/22/flash-xml-magic/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Do NOT Taunt the Happy Fun Dave</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Mark Pilgrim asks: &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintomark.org/archives/2003/04/21/whats_your_winer_number.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;What&#39;s your Winer number?&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I duck &amp;amp; cover under our new futon.  The one that I broke already, but it&#39;s better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2003 05:28:17 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/22/shitstorms-abound-2/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/22/shitstorms-abound-2/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Do Not Taunt Happy Fun Bloggers</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow.  Missed &lt;a href=&quot;http://diveintomark.org/archives/2003/04/18/enough_already.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;this from Mark&lt;/a&gt; over
the weekend, and then further missed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intertwingly.net/blog/1345.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Sam&#39;s link to it&lt;/a&gt;
and the subsequent whirling mass of shitstorm that rolled past in its wake.  Well, at least everyone 
just ends up being an asshole in the end, and no nazis or ethnicities 
or monsters were invoked in the process.  And no one co-opted any acronyms, though I think
someone got ketchup on their tie.  Hope it wasn&#39;t silk.  And does anyone know if all us assholes
are actually alive or dead in Schroedinger&#39;s Trunk?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2003 05:09:01 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/22/shitstorms-abound/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/22/shitstorms-abound/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Further Bitchun Reading...</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally got around to reading Cory Doctorow&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.craphound.com/down/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Down &amp;amp; Out in the Magic Kingdom&lt;/a&gt;,
and though I loved it, I wish it were longer.  Or, at least,
I&#39;d love to see more stories from the same setting or playing with the
same themes of the Bitchun Society.  I have seen some of these things
in stories before, though.  So, hey, I haven&#39;t posted anything here in
a few days - have some babble and book links (feel free to comment and
leave some more links):
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Of course I love the notion of ubiquitous computing and personal
HUD&#39;s.  I&#39;ve babbled about that at length for sure.  If you want more
of that, go check out Vernor Vinge&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0312875843/0xdecafbad-20&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Fast Times at Fairmont High&lt;/a&gt;.
Mediated reality with P2P computing woven into clothing and projected
across contact lens displays.  A little less obtrusive than
seisure-inducing in-brain electronics, but just as post-human.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And then there&#39;s backup-and-restore and the cure for death.  Although
in David Brin&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0765342618/0xdecafbad-20&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Kiln People&lt;/a&gt;,
things start with disposable
doppelgangers, survival of personality after bodily death is promised
in the ending.  What could change human nature more than transcending
mortality?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As for deadheading, check out Vinge&#39;s
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0671720988/0xdecafbad-20&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Across Realtime&lt;/a&gt;
series.  In
particular, read up on bobbling in Marooned in Realtime.  There&#39;s also
Orson Scott Card&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0812533313/0xdecafbad-20&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;The Worthing Saga&lt;/a&gt;.
A one-way trip into the far future
through geological periods of time seems particularly external to
known human experience, especially when combined with immortality.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
One thing I&#39;ve yet to see much in stories or speculations is how
society could function in a post-mortality and post-scarcity
conditions.  I&#39;ve never been satisfied with the way Star Trek dodges
the day-to-day realities of a post-capitalistic Federation of plenty.
Walter Jon Williams&#39; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/tg/detail/-/0312851723/0xdecafbad-20&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Aristoi&lt;/a&gt;
explores an interesting track with a
meritocratic society whose top members have godlike powers matched to
godlike creativity and self-possession (not to mention possession by
multiple selves).
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But so far, Whuffie and its currency in reputation is the best game
I&#39;ve seen yet.  Since, even if the problems of mortality and material
scarcity are solved, human attention and cooperation will never be
gratis.  So, how else do you herd the cats when you can neither
threaten nor reward them via any physical means?  Seems like the
blogosphere, gift culture, and open source noosphere brought to
reality.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Kinda makes me want to get back to fiction writing meself and finally
get out the dozen or so stories I&#39;ve had bouncing around in my head
these past years.  Doesn&#39;t necessarily mean I&#39;d churn out anything
good, but who knows?  Maybe after some work and some stumbling I could
produce something passable.  All those creative writing classes in
college and short stories in spiral-bound notebooks from high school
have to count for something.  I&#39;d even love to squat in the Bitchun
Society for a few stories, but that might be a bit presumptuous, even though
Mr. Doctorow himself &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.craphound.com/down/archives/2003_01.php#000054&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;has let on&lt;/a&gt;
that he&#39;s not likely to write more
tales from the same Bitchun universe.
Better to get some practice in before jamming in someone else&#39;s club.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2003 18:30:20 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/21/down-and-out/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/21/down-and-out/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>OPML vs OML - Fork but don&#39;t fight!</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In my intermittent online presence, I&#39;ve been happily watching &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scripting.com&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt;&#39;s
ramp-up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/OPML&quot;&gt;OPML&lt;/a&gt; toward OSCON with things like 
&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opml.org/howToImplementOpmlDirectoryBrowser&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;How to implement an &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/OPML&quot;&gt;OPML&lt;/a&gt; directory browser&quot;.
I love outliners, and though it&#39;s been a little while since I played with Radio, I loved Instant Outlining
and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/tech/old/ooocoe.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;transclusion&lt;/a&gt; of outside outlines into the
one at hand via URL.  And when Dave first introduced the idea of an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/OPML&quot;&gt;OPML&lt;/a&gt;-based distributed web directory,
I figured it was the start of another nifty twist in the web fabric.  (You know, the kind that makes wrinkles?
The kind of wrinkles that make brains smarter?)
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Anyway, even given all this, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/OPML&quot;&gt;OPML&lt;/a&gt; has always bugged me, and I&#39;m not alone.  In fact, today I found a
link to &lt;a href=&quot;http://oml.sourceforge.net/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;OML&lt;/a&gt;, the Outline Markup Language project on &lt;span style=&quot;background : #FFFFCE;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/edit/Main/SourceForge?topicparent=Main.FilterData&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;font color=&quot;#0000FF&quot;&gt;SourceForge&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/span&gt;,
which seems to seek to address many of the same things that have bugged me.  That is, things like
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/UserLand&quot;&gt;UserLand&lt;/a&gt; application-specific tags, and extension via arbitrary attributes.  Though I&#39;m no master
of deep XML magic, these things struck me as grungy.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But you know, we&#39;re &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/tech/old/oooced.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;designing for recombinant growth with the lazyweb&lt;/a&gt; here
(or at least, Dave Winer was and is), and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/OPML&quot;&gt;OPML&lt;/a&gt; looks like one of those dirty things that got
thrown together quickly in order to enable a laundry list of further projects.  It works, isn&#39;t
all that hard to grasp, and has gotten adopted quickly.  There&#39;s momentum there.  As 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://scriptingnews.userland.com/2003/04/15#noWaitForTools&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Dave says&lt;/a&gt;, there is no wait for
tools.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So, now there&#39;s also &lt;a href=&quot;http://oml.sourceforge.net/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;OML&lt;/a&gt; starting.  Hopefully this won&#39;t become another rehash of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/RSS&quot;&gt;RSS&lt;/a&gt; fight.&lt;br&gt;Because, I sense many similar issues between the two.  Maybe it would have been better still if OML had been named something
completely avoiding the letters O, P, M, or L.  I already see mailing list charters being called out in order to quiet unwanted
discussion of fundamentals, but, hopefully we can avoid anyone claiming that they have the One True Format, all fighting for the
same name and slapping each other around with version numbers.  Gah.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Anyway.  I like OML but see some grunge in it as well.  At the moment, I&#39;m using an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/twiki/bin/view/Main/OPML&quot;&gt;OPML&lt;/a&gt;-supporting tool. I can&#39;t imagine that
conversion would be more than an XSLT file away.  Well, maybe more than that.  Beyond that, let&#39;s agree to disagree and viva le
fork.  Let the best, most demonstratably capable format win.  Meanwhile, I&#39;m still considering that Tinderbox license to see if I
might like multi-dimensional outlining...&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2003 20:40:41 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/16/opml-vs-oml/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/16/opml-vs-oml/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Safari has tabs now, but I&#39;ve changed my mind.</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;So yeah, I wanted tabs in Safari.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.decafbad.com/blog/tech/old/oooche.html&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;Or something like tabs.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
But since discovering that the &quot;Window&quot; menu in OS X is not painful to
use, and that CMD-Backquote rotates between open windows, I&#39;ve not missed
tabs an incredible amount.  I think my tab usage was a response to my experience
with Windows and Linux window managers, though even those have changed since
I started using tabs in my browser.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
However, I still love using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.students.tut.fi/~tuomov/pwm/&quot; target=&quot;_top&quot;&gt;pwm&lt;/a&gt; as
my window manager under X11, with its tab collections and windowshading.  Go
figure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2003 14:36:31 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/15/safari-tabs/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/15/safari-tabs/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Still Alive Out Here</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Been out of touch with my usual online haunts as of late, and have barely had time to think straight,
let alone write. 
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
My girlfriend and I have moved just from one end of town to the other, and we have an overlapping
month of leases between the new place and old.  In theory, this is plenty of time to accomplish moving
and cleaning and decorating.  But, some things are hard to move gradually, especially when both she
and I have compact cars and trucks rent by the hour.  And then there&#39;s the fact that our new residence
is found on the third floor, providing much exercise to the both of us.  So, it&#39;s been a hectic couple
of weeks so far, though well worth it for us to start settling down in new and improved digs.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And then, right in the middle of things, I was offered an opportunity for a few months&#39; work as a
contractor for a startup located almost (but not quite) within walking distance of the new apartment. 
So, I decided to snatch that up, and since then things have been doubly busy.  Whew.  This&#39;ll give me
some breathing room to figure out what&#39;s next, hopefully.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
So anyway, here&#39;s hoping things settle down a bit and stop feeling like I&#39;ve jumped the tracks.  After
getting life in general into some semblance of happy chaos, I hope to get a chance to catch up on
happenings and maybe even take a stab at some of my projects around here again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2003 14:36:17 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/15/still-breathing/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2003/04/15/still-breathing/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>