<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: folksonomy - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels and self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/</link>
      <item>
          <title>Tags do work (for me, at least)</title>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For the &amp;quot;&lt;a href=&quot;delicious.com/tag/tl;dr&quot;&gt;too long&lt;/a&gt;; &lt;a href=&quot;http://delicious.com/tag/tldr&quot;&gt;didn&amp;apos;t read&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot; crowd:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;apos;ve &lt;a href=&quot;http://del.icio.us/deusx&quot;&gt;been using a lot of tags on Delicious&lt;/a&gt; over a relatively long time, so they seem very useful to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delicious encourages the use of tags through UI convention and tool usage patterns, whereas Flickr presents no particular bias toward collecting tags from users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since title and description attract more contribution effort from users on Flickr than on Delicious, it&amp;apos;s natural that search over those fields will be more productive than for tags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search on Delicious doesn&amp;apos;t have access to the complete text of the bookmarked resource, and often tags will contain information missing from the supplied title or description.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All told, tags on Delicious are more essential than tags on Flickr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In conclusion, I think &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tekka.net/10/tags.html&quot;&gt;Do Tags Work?&lt;/a&gt; misses the value of tags, as I know them, by focusing on Flickr.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, I don&amp;apos;t really care what this means for folksonomy and the rest of Web 2.0&amp;#x2014;tags work for me on Delicious.  So, I suspect this means I&amp;apos;m not &lt;em&gt;entirely&lt;/em&gt; opposed to the sentiment in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tekka.net/10/tags.html&quot;&gt;Do Tags Work?&lt;/a&gt;, because I don&amp;apos;t think tags work everywhere their use is attempted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of this entry elaborates on the above.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
          
          <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2009 06:29:34 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2009/01/18/tags-do-work-for-me-at-least/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com//2009/01/18/tags-do-work-for-me-at-least/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>