<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
  <rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
      <title>Tag: metablogging - blog.lmorchard.com</title>
      <description>It&#39;s all spinning wheels &amp; self-doubt until the first pot of coffee.</description>
      <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/tag/metablogging/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/index.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
      <item>
          <title>Foggy Blogging</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Baldur Bjarnason, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.baldurbjarnason.com/notes/2025/foggy-feeds/&quot;&gt;Foggy feeds: the decline in my feed reader subscriptions&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...I follow a lot of feeds in my feed reader, most of them only updating at most once a month, maybe weekly, and only a tiny handful update daily. About seven hundred (700) of the feeds I follow are active and I’ve been following some of them since the early 2000s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s a decent sample size both across fields – tech, media, and academia – and time – I’ve been following most of these since before COVID – and the decline in people’s thinking across many of these feeds has been noticeable because it’s incredibly fucking annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My feeds suck, right now. My main excuse is I&#39;m way out of the habit of blogging like I did 20 years ago. And I think part of that habit is thinking out loud, getting things out into words in front of me to clarify the thinking. Tweets and toots aren&#39;t really long enough to let a fully formed notion flop out of my head and thrash around on the desk for awhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do know a lot of folks who got COVID, though. Gratefully, I seem to have avoided it so far. Is this like the notion that &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/science/2021/07/did-lead-poisoning-cause-downfall-of-roman-empire-the-jury-is-still-out/&quot;&gt;the Roman Empire collapsed due to lead poisoning&lt;/a&gt;? I do feel like there&#39;s a lot of stupidity out there right now, like more than I&#39;d expect. I don&#39;t know if that&#39;s a conspiracy theory or just cynicism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 19:58:20 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/foggy-blogging/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/19/foggy-blogging/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Message in a bottle</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matt Webb, &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://interconnected.org/home/2025/05/16/bottle&quot;&gt;When was peak message in a bottle?&lt;/a&gt;&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grew up with the idea that you could put a paper note in a bottle and throw it into the ocean, and somebody might find it a thousand miles away.
...
So maybe this is my message in a bottle, right here? If it’s 2035 for you pls do drop me a note.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A little early, but answering with a bottled message of my own here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 19:57:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/message-in-a-bottle/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/16/message-in-a-bottle/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Generating documentation for my Easy-Blog Oven with Claude</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;I asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anthropic.com/claude/sonnet&quot;&gt;Claude 3.7 Sonnet&lt;/a&gt; via &lt;a href=&quot;https://aider.chat/&quot;&gt;Aider&lt;/a&gt; to take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/tree/main/lib&quot;&gt;the core libraries&lt;/a&gt; for my Easy-Blog Oven and to try drafting a quick user manual for it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/MANUAL.md&quot;&gt;I think the result is actually not bad at all&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aider tells me it cost about US$0.17 in API credits. It caught all the major quirky features I&#39;ve hacked into the system over the years. I only made one or two minor edits before checking it into the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve been meaning to write something like this for myself for years, if only to remind myself how it all works after long periods of neglect. It&#39;s a boring task and one of those things I&#39;d most likely never get around to—especially not for one of my own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also one of those kinds of things &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/13/thinking-about-llms/&quot;&gt;I&#39;ve been reticent to write about&lt;/a&gt;, anticipating negative feedback. But, it really is kind of neat and I found it personally useful. I can totally see the value in this kind of thing, when packaged up in friendlier UX for other folks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 21:05:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/generating-documentation-for-my-easyblog-oven-with/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/14/generating-documentation-for-my-easyblog-oven-with/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-12</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m probably going to keep &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/metablogging&quot;&gt;#metablogging&lt;/a&gt; here for awhile, as I work out the kinks with the revised system. I do have other projects &amp;amp; pursuits that I want to start rambling about here. Also kind of hoping that having an easy channel for show &amp;amp; tell will encourage me a bit to actually spend time on them and document a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://codepen.io/tofjadesign/pen/LEExbqr&quot;&gt;Carousel + Lightbox + Glow demo on CodePen&lt;/a&gt; is too fancy for my blog, but it&#39;s really nifty. Maybe I need to just code my own up from scratch and I&#39;m overthinking this lightGallery thing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://flipboard.video/w/p7cECAUgThGrfQo9Cqvb8r&quot;&gt;Molly White argues&lt;/a&gt; it’s time to reclaim the web: move your work to spaces you control, support open tools, and help build a web that serves people, not profit.&quot; She&#39;s been banging this drum for a long while, and she&#39;s right.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Considering integrating responses from Bluesky and Mastodon here and posting entries from here to there. Those aren&#39;t exactly space I control, but they&#39;re relatively open tools, and I can archive things here. Also, I think it&#39;d be meeting folks more where they are. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I thought maybe requiring a Bluesky or Mastodon account to respond here would be a pain in the butt. But, I gave my Disqus widget a fresh try over the weekend and it&#39;s not exactly pleasant these days. I guess I can see why a lot of blogs just punt and link out to Hacker News threads for their comments - but I am not at all a fan of the orange site, myself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I post the occasional toot &lt;a href=&quot;https://masto.hackers.town/@lmorchard&quot;&gt;on Mastodon&lt;/a&gt; and I post links to my half-baked &lt;a href=&quot;https://pebbl.ing/u/lmorchard?&quot;&gt;Pebbling Club profile&lt;/a&gt;. Tempted to do the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indieweb.org/PESOS&quot;&gt;PESOS&lt;/a&gt; thing and copy those into daily entries over here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pushed out some RSS feed fixes:&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;images should be properly linked with absolute URLs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posts with timestamps in the future should be omitted (i.e. like my daily miscellanea that&#39;s not &quot;final&quot; until just before midnight)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;links to feeds from tag pages should work now, both as visible in-page links and in the head of the page for auto-discovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/12/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/12/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-11</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hello world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A thing I have realized: filling all the vents of my Crocs with &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/3dprinting&quot;&gt;#3dprinting&lt;/a&gt; nonsense makes them a bit too warm to wear. 🥵&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Man, this image gallery component I lashed together just isn&#39;t behaving right. Image sizes are all over the place. I&#39;ve seen this particular &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lightgalleryjs.com/&quot;&gt;lightGallery&lt;/a&gt; widget work well on other sites, so I&#39;m pretty sure it&#39;s something I&#39;m doing that&#39;s disagreeable. Not sure how to fix it, tempted to switch to something else entirely - on the hypothesis that picking it up and shaking it like an Etch-a-Sketch may result in a better outcome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&#39;t often get feedback &amp;amp; comments via the Disqus comments widget I&#39;ve embedded at the end of every post. That could be because a) folks aren&#39;t reading my blog or b) Disqus is too annoying to use these days. Probably both. I can work on the former by posting better stuff more often and sharing it around. As for the latter, I dunno. I don&#39;t want to open a spam honeypot, but I think I need to offer some simpler way to at least give a lil thumbs up as a response.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m tempted to hook this stuff up to accounts on the Fediverse and Bluesky, try to get feedback from those channels. That could be worth hacking on for a bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just like my RSS feeds, though, I don&#39;t want to generate churn on those networks as I iterate on posts over the course of a day. I&#39;m still thinking through how to balance editing flexibility with publishing stable things when word goes out to the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe these miscellanea posts get a 24-hour delay, because they&#39;re where I expect to futz around the most throughout a day. If you happen to read them, you&#39;re an early alpha reader I guess. Other posts that bud off from this daily scratchpad will likely be stable enough to send out immediately. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I guess that means I need to implement a defer-until feature in my Easy-Blog Oven 🤔 Maybe I can set the post date into the future and implement logic such that no post shows up in a feed or gets sent out to another service until after that time? Too clever?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hmm, I sent out &quot;Word to your mother&quot; on &lt;a href=&quot;/tag/meshtastic&quot;&gt;#meshtastic&lt;/a&gt; and someone replied. Maybe my messages &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; getting out?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m starting to look into getting a doorbell camera that works with Home Assistant. I&#39;ve seen a few recommendations for PoE widgets. Like this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/REOLINK-Doorbell-Security-Diagonal-Detection/dp/B0B7S1HMPC&quot;&gt;REOLINK Video Doorbell PoE Camera&lt;/a&gt;. That seems troublesome, unless I&#39;m careful to stick it on its own VLAN / DMZ / whatever? Like I&#39;m imagining someone could walk up at 4am, unhook it, plug in a laptop, and have fun on my network?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/11/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/11/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Playing with image uploads</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.makeitsnappys.com/&quot;&gt;Snappy&#39;s&lt;/a&gt; was playing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt0119116/&quot;&gt;The Fifth Element&lt;/a&gt; when I went there for lunch today. I wonder if I can get image uploads to work? Actually, probably not: I think I need to write the code to copy the images to the site build 🤔&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(...time passes...)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/commit/0712506fa593928d8ae4a9b05871aa13b132d37f&quot;&gt;I think I managed to do it&lt;/a&gt;? Added code to copy over attachments from Obsidian. Had to rework the URLs for display in post lists, too. And it looks like I fixed my image gallery component by not lazy-loading the images. Not entirely happy with that outcome, so I may bang on it some more. But it seems to be working better now overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, the nice thing is that I can easily add images as attachments to a file in Obsidian. That makes it a comfy user interface for me - even from my phone - and the site generator takes care of the rest!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next part might be to apply a little image optimization along with the copying, since these images are straight from my phone and probably too huge?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;image-gallery&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/10/playing-with-image-uploads/attachments/IMG_8514.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/10/playing-with-image-uploads/attachments/IMG_8513.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/10/playing-with-image-uploads/attachments/IMG_8512.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/10/playing-with-image-uploads/attachments/IMG_8515.jpeg&quot; width=&quot;&quot; height=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;/image-gallery&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:41:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/10/playing-with-image-uploads/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/10/playing-with-image-uploads/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Miscellanea for 2025-05-09</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Been watching &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lCuoUSDBVa&quot;&gt;Resurrecting Sinistar: A Cyber-Archaeology Documentary&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, which has been great. Played Sinistar last at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.retrogamingexpo.com/&quot;&gt;Portland Retro Gaming Expo&lt;/a&gt; in October and was digging the heck out of it. They squeezed so much out of that 8-bit processor - I guess it had a multitasking system that could handle like over 100 game entities? In 1983?! The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/synamaxmusic/sinistar&quot;&gt;source code&lt;/a&gt; has actually surfaced, so you can see how they did it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was starting to do &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/tag/weeknotes/&quot;&gt;weeknotes&lt;/a&gt;&quot;, this month. But, this week, I decided what I really wanted to do was just blog more. So, that got me started hacking on my blog software.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;m just going to deploy these changes to the blog. Some things might be broken, but I&#39;ll fix them as I go. I want to start actually using the thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking I&#39;ll start each day off with a miscellanea entry like this one and fill it full of little bullets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maybe I&#39;ll start spawning little entries for bookmarks and quotes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One of the main things I&#39;m thinking about with all this hackery and ASCII art is whether I&#39;ll be able to do &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; with all these files in 10 - 20 years&#39; time. Granted, I&#39;ll be pushing 70, so maybe I won&#39;t care by then?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But, the writing is the important part to me. I could write a whole new blog publisher from scratch and still read all the file formats. I&#39;ve done that a couple times now and I can still handle stuff I wrote back in 2002. I think that&#39;s pretty cool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And here I am, attempting to blog from Obsidian on my phone? Is this the future?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next thing I need to work out is how to upload and display images via Obsidian on my phone. I think it&#39;s very doable, just a few more bits of Rube Goldberg crud to slot into place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&#39;ve been asked to write up how this whole mess works - that might be a thing I&#39;ll do this weekend in greater detail. It really is an accumulation of random little parts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dang, now that I have this easy channel from my brain into my blog, I&#39;m feeling like a motormouth. I&#39;ll probably settle down, soon enough. I&#39;m always giddy with a new toy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2025 06:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/miscellanea/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/miscellanea/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Blogging elsewhere than into the void</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;The thing about blogging -  and why I want to do more of it and more often - is that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.henrikkarlsson.xyz/p/search-query&quot;&gt;a blog post is a very long and complex search query to find fascinating people and make them route interesting stuff to your inbox&lt;/a&gt;. It&#39;s why I used to blog so much, back before Twitter ate my brain. It actually brought me good fortune and favorable outcomes - friends, acquaintances, writing opportunities, job interviews.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I&#39;m posting just the occasional too-long-didn&#39;t-read entry, I&#39;m not getting many hits returning from my search queries these days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That could just be because no one reads blogs at all, these days. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2024/03/11/dance-for-the-bots/&quot;&gt;Except bots, maybe.&lt;/a&gt; Still, I don&#39;t think my few shots at posting have been interesting enough to justify the time to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might get more hits if I can better balance frequency, length, and interestingness. And I think I can write more often if I write shorter things. As for the interestingness part - well, I think I just need more &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shot_on_goal_(ice_hockey)&quot;&gt;shots on goal&lt;/a&gt;&quot; to see what lands, rather than put forth a bunch of effort on one thing that lands to the sound of crickets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of sounds like I&#39;m ruminating on some &quot;engagement hacks&quot; - kind of icky and I guess a product of my marketing-tech-poisoned brain. But also, I would actually like to connect with folks and not just shout into the void. I also really like writing and would like to find ways to work with my ADHD brain to make it happen more often in public.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 20:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/blogging-elsewhere-than-into-the-void/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/blogging-elsewhere-than-into-the-void/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>New blog, a lot like the old blog, but more of it</title>
          
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years now, I&#39;ve wanted to turn this blog into a place to write Big Serious Entries with fancy layouts and lots of words &amp;amp; images. I thought that would get me somewhere interesting. But, it turns out, that&#39;s a pretty heavy squelch filter on getting things out of my brain and onto the web. I just don&#39;t have the energy or follow-through to come up with Big Serious Entries all that often.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I do have is a lot of little things that I could let tumble out of my ADHD brain. I used to do more of that here - but since the advent of Twitter, way back in 2006, I allowed most of that to be shunted over there. And when I finally abandoned Twitter in 2022, that brain spew more fully moved to &lt;a href=&quot;https://masto.hackers.town/@lmorchard&quot;&gt;Mastodon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except, not entirely. Twitter and Mastodon are mostly good for tiny things. Not medium or long things. Or things that start small and grow with further thought throughout a day or a week. My blog could be good at that, though. So, I&#39;m reworking the layout and how I can write entries to better accomodate that and dovetail into my habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like the way &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/&quot;&gt;Dave Winer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://simonwillison.net/&quot;&gt;Simon Willison&lt;/a&gt; run their blogs. They riff throughout the day with notions of various length and format - sometimes as short as a toot and sometimes expanding out into full essays. They&#39;ve both done this for years and years, and they&#39;ve done well at it. So, I&#39;m going to shamelessly steal some of their ideas and plonk them down here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I&#39;m also going to try a few of my own ideas. Like, Simon runs his blog &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/simonw/simonwillisonblog&quot;&gt;as a Django app&lt;/a&gt; and Dave &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripting.com/?tab=about&quot;&gt;writes in OPML&lt;/a&gt;. Personally, I like my &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.lmorchard.com/2020/05/24/easy-blog-oven/index.html&quot;&gt;Easy-Blog Oven&lt;/a&gt; and I like writing in Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I don&#39;t like is tediously opening a new Markdown file every time I might have a wild idea, though. That&#39;s a thing that Dave&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.opml.org/&quot;&gt;OPML Editor&lt;/a&gt; had going for it, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20061003021452/http://blogs.opml.org/decafbad/&quot;&gt;back when I blogged with it&lt;/a&gt;: You opened one outline for the whole day and just let ideas tumble into it over the hours. (Hmm, I want a screenshot here. I need to figure out how to paste one in.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, my stand-in for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://home.opml.org/&quot;&gt;OPML Editor&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;https://obsidian.md/&quot;&gt;Obsidian&lt;/a&gt;. In some ways, it&#39;s more cumbersome for outlining than OPML, but it does other things I like. So, I&#39;ve come up with this goofy file format to open just one file per day and compose multiple entries in that file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, it&#39;s markdown, but if I &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/content/posts/2025/2025-05-09.md?plain=1#L15&quot;&gt;start a line with ASCII-art scissors (i.e. &lt;code&gt;8&amp;lt;&lt;/code&gt;)&lt;/a&gt; then my Easy-Blog Oven &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/lib/posts.js#L140-L156&quot;&gt;will chop that file up&lt;/a&gt; into separate entries. I can also include a bit of JSON in there for post metadata.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No entry in the file is final, things may expand and contract and bud off into new entries over time. I&#39;ll probably let them alone after midnight, though. That might cause some churn in my RSS feeds, so I may eventually set them to a 24-hour delay. I don&#39;t know, I&#39;m still thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I get really ambitious, I&#39;ll rig up some machinery to automatically publish as I write in an Obsidian tab. But, that&#39;s some hackery for the days ahead. For now, I just want to get these changes pushed out into the world before I wander off after something else shiny.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Edit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/lmorchard/blog.lmorchard.com/blob/main/script/publish-posts-from-obsidian.sh&quot;&gt;I wrote a script that runs in a cronjob that pushes my edits from Obsidian to GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. That&#39;s all it really took, just one more sproingy bit atop the Rube Goldberg machine.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 19:13:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/new-blog-a-lot-like-the-old/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/09/new-blog-a-lot-like-the-old/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>2025 Week 18</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: This week, I messed around with Meshtastic firmware on Bazzite, printed some goofy charms for my new Crocs, and ruminated about backfilling my blog. Also, some thoughts on GitHub Pages, moats in AI IDEs, and frustration with platform lock-in—especially from Apple.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/02/w18/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/05/02/w18/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>2025 Week 16</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: Kicked off a new habit: jotting down bits and bobs throughout the week, then turning it into a blog post. Played with Meshtastic, roasted some coffee, fixed (and broke) Fossilizer, and started messing with garden irrigation. Just trying to get stuff out of my head and onto the web again.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/04/18/w16/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2025/04/18/w16/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Dance like the bots aren&#39;t watching?</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: Why bother sharing anything on the open web if it&#39;s just going to be fodder for extractive, non-reciprocal bots?&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2024/03/11/dance-for-the-bots/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2024/03/11/dance-for-the-bots/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>There are no ushers on Mastodon</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: There are no ushers on Mastodon. There&#39;s no one paid to show you to your seat, no one whose job it is to ease you into comfort and remove friction.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/11/07/no-ushers/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/11/07/no-ushers/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>Twitter, or social cowardice as a service</title>
          <description
                >&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;TL;DR: Yeah, yeah, I&#39;m navel gazing about Twitter over here.&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description
              >
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/28/twitter/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/28/twitter/</guid>
        </item><item>
          <title>5:00am is the enemy</title>
          
          
          <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
          <link>https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/07/5am-is-the-enemy/</link>
          <guid isPermaLink="true">https://lmorchard.github.io/blog.lmorchard.com/2022/10/07/5am-is-the-enemy/</guid>
        </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>